<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1659">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04811885</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Institute Technology Carlow</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04811885</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effects of Covid-19 Pandemic on the Cardiovascular Heath of Children With Autism Spectrum Disorder</brief_title>
  <acronym>ASD</acronym>
  <official_title>The Effects of Covid-19 Pandemic on the Cardiovascular Heath of Children With Autism</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Institute of Technology, Carlow</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Institute of Technology, Carlow</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of the questionnaire and semi structured interview was to understand how the Covid 19&#xD;
      pandemic has impacted the cardiovascular health, physical activity levels, sedentary&#xD;
      behavior, sleep, anxiety levels and eating habits of children with ASD in comparison to&#xD;
      before the pandemic.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      A questionnaire was designed and was available for completion on the colleges survey monkey&#xD;
      account. The link for the questionnaire and an explanation of the purpose of the&#xD;
      questionnaire was e-mailed to relevant Autism charities or groups within Ireland, the UK and&#xD;
      the USA and the administrators of these group were requested to send the link for the&#xD;
      questionnaire onto their members. The administrators of relevant social media sites such as&#xD;
      Facebook Autism groups were contacted and asked for permission to share the link for the&#xD;
      questionnaire to be circulated on their Facebook page.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The questionnaire was completed by parents of children with ASD and consisted of questions&#xD;
      relating to them and their child. Within the questionnaire they were asked about their&#xD;
      socio-economic background and about their ASD child's cardiovascular health, physical&#xD;
      activity levels, sedentary behavior, eating habits and anxiety levels during the Covid 19&#xD;
      pandemic compared to normal life before the outbreak of the pandemic. The aim of the&#xD;
      questionnaire was to understand how the Covid 19 pandemic has impacted the cardiovascular&#xD;
      health, physical activity levels, sedentary behavior, sleep, anxiety levels and eating habits&#xD;
      in comparison to before the pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The questionnaires was completed online through IT Carlow's survey monkey. Individual results&#xD;
      were anonymous and results of the questionnaire were stored on a password protected computer.&#xD;
      Participants completed a consent form that explained that participation in the survey was&#xD;
      completely voluntary and they could withdraw at any stage if they wished to do so. If they&#xD;
      did not wish to answer a question, was a prefer not to say option available and they could&#xD;
      continue with the survey. Parents had an option at the end of the survey to enter their email&#xD;
      address which allowed them to partake in any follow up questionnaire studies. The&#xD;
      questionnaire was initially piloted and was amended as necessary based on the results of the&#xD;
      pilot study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The second aspect will of the study used qualitative design (semi-structured interviews,&#xD;
      n=10) to gain deeper insights into the challenges and barriers to engaging children with&#xD;
      autism in healthy lifestyle behaviours and the effects COVID 19 had on these challenges and&#xD;
      barriers. Each interview was approximately 60 minutes in length. A semi-structured,&#xD;
      qualitative interview schedule, which is attached below guided the interview process and was&#xD;
      continually revised based on reflection and evolving conceptualisation. Written consent was&#xD;
      sought from all participants. The consent form explained that participation in the interview&#xD;
      was completely voluntary and they could withdraw at any stage if they wished to do so. If&#xD;
      they did not wish to answer a question, they could decline and move on to the next question.&#xD;
      The interview was initially piloted and was amended as necessary based on the results of the&#xD;
      pilot study.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">October 14, 2019</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 14, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 14, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The Effects of Covid-9 Pandemic on the Cardiovascular Heath of Children With Autism Spectrum Disorder</measure>
    <time_frame>24 months</time_frame>
    <description>Questionnaire, interview</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">120</enrollment>
  <condition>Autism Spectrum Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Cardiovascular Health</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>child with ASD of school going age</arm_group_label>
    <description>Questionnaire complete by parent with children with ASD semi structure interview complete by parent with children</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>The Effects of Covid 19 Pandemic on the Cardiovascular Heath of Children With Autism Spectrum Disorder</intervention_name>
    <description>The Effects of Covid 19 Pandemic on the Cardiovascular Heath of Children With Autism Spectrum Disorder</description>
    <arm_group_label>child with ASD of school going age</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Questionnaire study</other_name>
    <other_name>Interview study</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        child with ASD of school going age living in Ireland, UK and USA.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  children with ASD&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>18 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Katie White</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Institute of Technology, Carlow</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Institute of Technology Carlow</name>
      <address>
        <city>Carlow</city>
        <state>Lenister</state>
        <country>Ireland</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Ireland</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Institute of Technology, Carlow</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Katie White</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Post graduate research student</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Autism Spectrum Disorder</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Autism Spectrum Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Child Development Disorders, Pervasive</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

