<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="789">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04795583</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>00001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04795583</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Corticosteroids for COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>CORE-COVID</acronym>
  <official_title>A Randomized Clinical Trial Comparing 7 Days Treatment With Corticosteroids Versus Placebo for Early COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alberta</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alberta</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>Yes</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This trial is an interventional, randomized, placebo-controlled, adaptive clinical trial in&#xD;
      outpatients with symptomatic microbiologically-confirmed SARS-CoV-2, in stable clinical&#xD;
      condition, and increased levels of serum C-reactive protein. The hypothesis of this study is&#xD;
      that early administration of prednisone for 7 days in patients with evidence of increased&#xD;
      C-reactive protein will decrease the progression of COVID-19, prevent clinical deterioration,&#xD;
      and hospital admission. Objectives: Primary Objective: To evaluate if early administration of&#xD;
      corticosteroids in non-hospitalized participants with proven SARS-CoV-2 infection with&#xD;
      compatible clinical symptoms and increased C-reactive protein can prevent hospital admission&#xD;
      or early death&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The proposed trial is an interventional, randomized, placebo-controlled, adaptive clinical&#xD;
      trial in outpatients with symptomatic microbiologically-confirmed SARS-CoV-2, in stable&#xD;
      clinical condition, and increased levels of serum C-reactive protein.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Potential participants will be identified via Public Health after a diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      infection is made either by positive nucleic acid testing or by antigen detection, from a&#xD;
      nasal or pharyngeal swab. These study candidates will be asked for permission to be&#xD;
      contacted. If this person agrees, a research collaborator will contact the potential&#xD;
      participant by phone call. During this phone call, verbal informed consent to be included in&#xD;
      the study will be requested.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After inclusion in the study, participants will be divided into two groups with the below&#xD;
      follow-up outline:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Group 1 non-RCT: Asymptomatic participants (no symptoms of early COVID-19). These&#xD;
           participants will be followed by phone call every 48 hours for 14 days. If asymptomatic&#xD;
           participants develop clinical symptoms of early COVID-19 during follow-up&#xD;
           (pre-symptomatic COVID-19), they will be transferred to Group 2. Otherwise, study for&#xD;
           this group will end at the 14 days timepoint with the exception 20 participants who&#xD;
           consent to partake in the pulmonary evaluation at 12 weeks (tertiary/exploratory&#xD;
           objective, see sections 3.1 and 7.1).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Group 2 non-RCT: Participants with symptoms of early COVID-19 will undergo full&#xD;
           follow-up every 48 hours for 4 visits (8 days) which will consist of:&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Review of clinical symptoms by phone call.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  Oxygen saturation.&#xD;
&#xD;
             -  C-reactive protein in blood.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The strategy for the follow-up visits is described below. Participants in this group who&#xD;
      present with the inclusion criteria and without exclusion criteria (section 1.5) will be&#xD;
      asked to join the randomized control trial. Otherwise, study for this group will end at the 8&#xD;
      days time point with the exception of 20 participants who consent to partake in the pulmonary&#xD;
      evaluation at 12 weeks (tertiary/exploratory objective, see sections 3.1 and 7.1).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study visits:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Monitoring of C-reactive protein and oxygen saturation will be evaluated at the participant's&#xD;
      home following a COVID-19 safe procedure. C-reactive protein will be determined by a&#xD;
      point-of-care diagnostic device (Afinion[TM] 2 Analyzer, Abbott Laboratories, USA; Health&#xD;
      Canada Regitration number 99614) using C-reactive protein cartridges and controls by the same&#xD;
      manufacturer (Afinion CRP and Afinion CRP control Health Canada Registration number 98995).&#xD;
      More information of the point-of-care device can be found at:&#xD;
      https://www.globalpointofcare.abbott/en/product-details/afinion2-analyzer.html). A kit with&#xD;
      all the necessary materials (gloves, lancet, alcohol scrubs, pulse oximeter (ToronTek-E400,&#xD;
      Health Canada Registration number: 90629) and AfinionTM C-reactive protein cartridges) will&#xD;
      be placed at the front door of the participant's home. In the case of long-term care&#xD;
      facilities, nursing homes or other facilities with healthcare workers, the kit will be&#xD;
      provided to the participant's main caregiver. The research associate (research coordinator,&#xD;
      research assistant or medical student) will never be in contact with the participant or&#xD;
      relatives and will always wear a mask and gloves to manipulate the material.&#xD;
&#xD;
      An educational video will be offered to participants to self-perform blood drop collection to&#xD;
      the integrated capillary system. Those patients unable to perform self-collection of blood&#xD;
      drop will be offered to remain in the study to know the evolution of clinical symptoms and&#xD;
      outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In each visit, a kit will be delivered to the participant's home by a research coordinator or&#xD;
      research assistant. The content of the kit for each visit will contain the following items.&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Pulse oximeter.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Surgical mask.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Alcohol pads (x2).&#xD;
&#xD;
        4. Single-use lancet (Unistik 3, Owen Mumford Ltd, Health Canada Licence No.: 9790) (x2).&#xD;
&#xD;
        5. Afinion 2 CRP cartridge.&#xD;
&#xD;
        6. Paper sheet.&#xD;
&#xD;
        7. Pen.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In the first visit, the kit will contain a 50 mL bottle of hand sanitizer and a 1-liter sharp&#xD;
      container that the participant will retain for the following visits. Briefly, the patient&#xD;
      will be instructed to wash her/his hands before collecting the kit. Before touching any other&#xD;
      item, the participant will put on the surgical mask. The next step will be to register the&#xD;
      oxygen saturation using the pulse oximeter and will register the value on the paper sheet.&#xD;
      After cleaning the tip of a finger with an alcohol pad, the participant will obtain a blood&#xD;
      drop and load the capillary of the C-reactive cartridge. After completing this task, the&#xD;
      visit will be completed and the participant will return the kit containing the pen, paper&#xD;
      sheet, Afinion 2 CRP cartridge and pulse oximeter. The participant will be instructed to&#xD;
      deposit the used lancet in the sharp container.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Intervention: Eligible participants who sign informed consent for the RCT will be randomized&#xD;
      at a ratio of 1:1 to:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Oral prednisone in 25mg capsules with a dosage determined according to weight range for&#xD;
           7 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Oral placebo capsules with the same appearance daily for 7 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Follow-up of RCT participants post-randomization and end of study (Figure 1, Table 2):&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. During intervention (Day 0 to 7 post-randomization):&#xD;
&#xD;
           i. A baseline questionnaire (EQ-5D-5L) for state of patient health will be collected at&#xD;
           day 0.&#xD;
&#xD;
           ii. Clinical monitoring by phone call at day 3 and end of treatment (day 7). iii.&#xD;
           C-reactive protein levels and oxygen saturation at the end of treatment (day 7)&#xD;
           collected as described above.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. After intervention (Week 1 to 12 post-randomization):&#xD;
&#xD;
           i. Once treatment is completed, follow up will be performed by phone calls on a weekly&#xD;
           basis until week 12 post-randomization (end of study).&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. End of study (Week 12 post-randomization). Visit at the post-COVID clinic. i.&#xD;
           Participants will be asked to complete the EQ-5D-5L questionnaire and the Post-COVID&#xD;
           Functional Status (PCFS) scale.&#xD;
&#xD;
      ii. Spirometry: FEV1, FVC, FEV1/FVC. iii. 6-minute walking test.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">August 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator)</masking>
    <masking_description>Placebo-controlled</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital admission or death in the first 2 weeks after randomization</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Need to be admitted to hospital or death during the first 2 weeks after randomization</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospitalization at 30 days</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Need of hospital admission in the first 30 days after randomization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mortality at 30 days</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Death in the first 30 days after randomization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serious adverse events at 30 days</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>Occurrence of SAEs in the first 30 days after randomization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Death at week 12</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>Death in the first 12 weeks after randomization</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Duration of symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Week 12</time_frame>
    <description>COVID-19 symptoms duration in days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Long COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>12 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Persistent symptoms of COVID-19 at week 12 of randomization</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1526</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Prednisone</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Treatment adjusted by weight. Prednisone 25 mg capsules:&#xD;
≤ 50kg = 2 capsules QD x 7 days (maximum dose = 50mg/day)&#xD;
50 - 80kg = 3 capsules QD x 7 days (maximum dose = 75mg/day)&#xD;
&gt; 80kg = 4 capsules QD x 7 days (maximum dose = 100mg/day)</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Capsules with the same appearance as Prednisone</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Prednisone</intervention_name>
    <description>Prednisone 25 mg capsules</description>
    <arm_group_label>Prednisone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Device</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Point of Care testing device for C-reactive protein</intervention_name>
    <description>Determination of C-reactive protein blood levels by point of care testing device</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Prednisone</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age ≥ 18 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Microbiologically-confirmed SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Clinical symptoms compatible with COVID-19 for 14 days or less before randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Oxygen saturation ≥ 95%.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Protein C-reactive in blood performed by point-of-care testing ≥ 20 mg/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Signed informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Oxygen requirement at home due to chronic lung disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Patients with immunosuppression or immunosuppressive therapies defined as:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cancer on active chemotherapy.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Stem cell transplant in the previous 6 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Neutrophil count &lt; 1000 cells/mm3.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chronic treatment with immunosuppressive therapy, except for low-dose (≤10 mg&#xD;
                  daily) prednisone or equivalent dose of other corticosteroids.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  HIV-infected patients with CD4 &lt; 200 x 106/L.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Diagnosis with primary immunodeficiencies.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Chronic liver damage Child-Pugh C.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Chronic underlying process with suspected life expectancy less than 12 weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Uncontrolled diabetes mellitus at screening, defined as no blood glucose testing or&#xD;
             any blood glucose level higher than 14 mmol/L (or 250 mg/dL) in the last 14 days.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Diagnosis of any form of psychosis without receiving appropriate treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Pregnancy at time of randomization.&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Patients who received approved or trial vaccination for SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Carlos Cervera, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>780-492-5346</phone>
    <email>cerveraa@ualberta.ca</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Clinica de la Mujer</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bogotá</city>
        <country>Colombia</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Ximena Castaneda Luquerna, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ximena Castaneda Luquerna, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>ABC Medical Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mexico City</city>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Irma Hoyo Ulloa, MD</last_name>
    </contact>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Irma Hoyo Ulloa, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Colombia</country>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 16, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 16, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 18, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alberta</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Carlos Cervera Alvarez</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Associate Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Prednisone</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

