<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="400">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04810117</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>15032021-1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04810117</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Monitoring the IgG/IgM Antibodies in COVID-19 Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>Monitoring the Patterns of IgG/IgM Antibodies in Asymptomatic/Symptomatic COVID-19 Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Sargodha</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dr Fariha Kanwal, Med-X Research Institute, School of biomedical engineering, Shanghai</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Sargodha</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>Yes</is_fda_regulated_device>
    <is_us_export>No</is_us_export>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The COVID-19 was declared a global pandemic by WHO more than a year ago, and the world is&#xD;
      still experiencing a state of global emergency. This disease is caused by a novel RNA&#xD;
      coronavirus suspected to originate in animals like bats and pangolin. Coronaviruses found in&#xD;
      humans can be divided into seven classes, and out of them, three, i.e., MERS-CoV, SARS-CoV,&#xD;
      and SARS-CoV-2, lead to global outbreaks. SARS-CoV-2 has claimed more than 120 million&#xD;
      confirmed global cases of the COVID-19, where more than 26 million fatalities have also been&#xD;
      recorded by the mid of March 2021. Many drugs have been repurposed and employed, but no&#xD;
      specific antiviral medicine has been approved by the FDA to treat this disease. Although&#xD;
      three vaccines have been approved by the FDA, mutations in the SARS-CoV-2 may cause problems&#xD;
      in antibody neutralization against the virus. COVID-19 patients have been found either&#xD;
      symptomatic or asymptomatic. In most people, the disease was found with mild symptoms with no&#xD;
      need for hospitalization, or sometimes patients don't show any symptom. Elderly people and&#xD;
      people with compromised health are mainly affected by the disease. Serologic assays involving&#xD;
      IgM and IgG antibodies to detect antibodies against SARS-CoV-2 are of great interest as these&#xD;
      antibodies can be detected from the second week of the start of COVID-19 symptom's where IgM&#xD;
      can be detected after the fourth day of infection and IgG has been found after the eighth day&#xD;
      of disease onset. Serologic assays provide quick diagnostic by avoiding PCR false&#xD;
      positive/false negative result as well as these provide antibody pattern for estimation of&#xD;
      strength and duration of humoral immunity. Here, serologic assays will be used to estimate&#xD;
      IgM and IgG antibodies in symptomatic or asymptomatic COVID subjects recovered from the&#xD;
      disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      SARS-CoV-2 (Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2) pandemic has affected millions&#xD;
      of people around the globe. Despite many efforts to find some effective medicines against&#xD;
      SARS CoV-2, still no established therapeutics available. A year ago, SARS-CoV-2 emerged as a&#xD;
      novel virus with no available treatment option and caused a serious disaster across the&#xD;
      world. The disease caused by this virus, &quot;COVID-19&quot;, announced a global pandemic on March 11,&#xD;
      2020. Without any proper treatment and vaccine for COVID-19, people around the world are&#xD;
      currently experiencing a worldwide emergency affecting all societies, and it has sent&#xD;
      billions of people into lockdown. Around the world, desperate efforts are underway to curtail&#xD;
      this pandemic while it has resulted in the collapsing of health systems and has triggered&#xD;
      lasting geopolitical and economic changes. To date, no approved medical treatment is&#xD;
      available, which makes social distancing the only best possible solution to stop the spread&#xD;
      of the virus. It is thought that future outbreaks of CoVs are unavoidable because of changes&#xD;
      in the climate and ecology and increased interaction of humans with animals. Therefore, there&#xD;
      is a need to develop effective therapeutics and vaccines against CoVs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Poor diagnosis of COVID-19 has also contributed to disease severity due to stress (in case of&#xD;
      false positive) and disease spread (in case of a false negative). A lack of RT-PCR test&#xD;
      sampling of lower tract respiratory specimens was the main reason for the misclassification&#xD;
      of symptomatic patients as either having COVID-19 or not. A prompt diagnosis with serological&#xD;
      testing shows SARS-CoV-2 IgG/IgM patterns in a better and understandable way of&#xD;
      seroconversion.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The IgG/IgM assays to detect the length and origin of humoral responses against SARS-CoV-2 is&#xD;
      very important, and these antibodies can be detected from a few days after the onset of&#xD;
      diseases and may remain in the body even after years of infection. In the case of COVID-19,&#xD;
      IgM and IgG response can be observed from the second week of the disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In Coronaviruses, IgM and IgG levels are found to disappear over time in humans. IgG&#xD;
      antibodies against SARS-CoV-1 were found to wane approximately two years after infection, and&#xD;
      the person may become vulnerable to reinfection after the complete reduction of the immune&#xD;
      response. In MERS- CoV, IgG levels were found gradually reduced after a year of infection&#xD;
      onset. The length of the protective immunity is very important to avoid reinfection and also&#xD;
      helps in the prediction of vaccine response in the body. The humoral immune response varies&#xD;
      among young and elderly people, men and women, healthy and health compromised people. Studies&#xD;
      on dynamics and the mechanisms of the humoral immune response may help in COVID-19 vaccine&#xD;
      development and laws implementation, and other public health responses. This study is&#xD;
      particularly designed to access the IgM and IgG antibodies in various COVID-19 subjects in&#xD;
      Sargodha, Punjab, Pakistan, where no specific study of this kind has been performed. This&#xD;
      will help predict the reinfection probabilities among the local population and predict the&#xD;
      length and efficacy of the vaccine and the requirement of vaccine boosters.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>IgG positive</measure>
    <time_frame>from date of consent to date of test completion, up to 40 days</time_frame>
    <description>COVID patients</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19 Infections</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 PCR positive patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients test positive with PCR and recovered from COVID-19</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 patients with obvious symptoms</arm_group_label>
    <description>COVID-19 patients with obvious symptoms but PCR test was not conducted for them</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 suspected patients with no symptoms</arm_group_label>
    <description>COVID-19 suspected patients with no symptoms but cam in obvious contact with infected environmental/biological samples</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Serodiagnosis of IgG and IgM</intervention_name>
    <description>IgG and IgM antibodies will be detected in COVID-19 patients</description>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 PCR positive patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>COVID-19 patients with obvious symptoms</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood Samples&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Local people living in the Sargodha District&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Suspected/PCR positive COVID-19 patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients aged &gt;18 years and &lt; 60 year&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to fill/understand/answer the questionnaire and provide consent to use of&#xD;
             personal health information.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Impaired/disable patients who can not understand or provide questionnaire answers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients aged &lt;18 years and &gt; 60 year&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rehman MFU, Fariha C, Anwar A, Shahzad N, Ahmad M, Mukhtar S, Farhan Ul Haque M. Novel coronavirus disease (COVID-19) pandemic: A recent mini review. Comput Struct Biotechnol J. 2021;19:612-623. doi: 10.1016/j.csbj.2020.12.033. Epub 2020 Dec 31. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>33398233</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lee YL, Liao CH, Liu PY, Cheng CY, Chung MY, Liu CE, Chang SY, Hsueh PR. Dynamics of anti-SARS-Cov-2 IgM and IgG antibodies among COVID-19 patients. J Infect. 2020 Aug;81(2):e55-e58. doi: 10.1016/j.jinf.2020.04.019. Epub 2020 Apr 23.</citation>
    <PMID>32335168</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 19, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 19, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 22, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Sargodha</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Muhammad Fayyaz ur Rehman</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Lecturer</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>Humoral response</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

