<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4739">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04813692</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IT-VA:85/2021</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04813692</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mechanical Complications of Acute Myocardial Infarction During COVID-19 Pandemics</brief_title>
  <acronym>CautionCov19</acronym>
  <official_title>Mechanical Complications of Acute Myocardial Infarction: an International Multicenter Cohort Study During COVID-19 Pandemics (CautionCov19)</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Maastricht University Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Maastricht University Medical Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The ongoing COVID-19 pandemics has put an overwhelming pressure on the healthcare systems of&#xD;
      many European countries. Such a situation has potentially led to delayed and impaired access&#xD;
      to appropriate treatment for patients affected by other severe, non-COVID-19-related&#xD;
      conditions, including cardiovascular diseases. This resulted in a reported lower admission,&#xD;
      but higher mortality rate for AMI patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Such a situation might be explained by many factors, including unavailability of early&#xD;
      reperfusion therapy and late hospital presentation of AMI patients due to a general anxiety&#xD;
      related to the COVID-19 contagious risk of the hospital environment. As a matter of fact,&#xD;
      during this year of pandemics, several case reports suggested a new, significant surge of&#xD;
      post-AMI mechanical complications, sometimes describing patients admitted in too severe&#xD;
      conditions to consider surgical repair a viable option, and therefore inevitably undergone an&#xD;
      unfavorable outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, we decided to involve the large network of European centers already participating&#xD;
      to the &quot;Caution Study 1&quot;, in order to study the impact of COVID-19 pandemics on the outcomes,&#xD;
      incidence and treatments of post-AMI mechanical complications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Mechanical complications must be carefully searched for in any patient with an acute coronary&#xD;
      syndrome and signs of cardiogenic shock, as prompt diagnosis and immediate surgery often&#xD;
      represent the only effective treatment for such ominous conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The management of patients with postinfarction mechanical complications requires the&#xD;
      consideration of several factors: (i) the extremely poor prognosis without surgical&#xD;
      treatment; (ii) the higher mortality risk associated with emergency surgery; (iii) the&#xD;
      potential rapid deterioration of initially stable patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data from the Society of Thoracic Surgeons National Database demonstrated an average 43%&#xD;
      in-hospital/30-day mortality for surgical treatment of ventricular septal rupture. Data from&#xD;
      the same registry on papillary muscle rupture showed a 30-day mortality of 20%. Matteucci et&#xD;
      al. recently reported a 36.4% mortality rate for free wall rupture from the large CAUTION&#xD;
      multicenter study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given the low incidence of these post-AMI mechanical complications, evidence-based&#xD;
      therapeutic strategies remain controversial, and little is known on the early clinical&#xD;
      results and late follow-up, with most information derived from small single-center&#xD;
      experiences or national registries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, we started the &quot;Mechanical complications of acute myocardial infarction: an&#xD;
      international multicenter cohort study&quot; - (Caution Study 1), a retrospective, international&#xD;
      multicenter clinical trial aimed at evaluating the survival, postoperative outcome and&#xD;
      quality of life of patients undergone cardiac surgery for post-infarction mechanical&#xD;
      complications starting from 2001.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The ongoing COVID-19 pandemics, however, has put an overwhelming pressure on the healthcare&#xD;
      systems of many European countries. Such a situation has potentially led to delayed and&#xD;
      impaired access to appropriate treatment for patients affected by other severe,&#xD;
      non-COVID-19-related conditions, including cardiovascular diseases. This resulted in a&#xD;
      reported lower admission, but higher mortality rate for AMI patients.This situation might be&#xD;
      explained by many factors, including unavailability of early reperfusion therapy and late&#xD;
      hospital presentation of AMI patients due to a general anxiety related to the COVID-19&#xD;
      contagious risk of the hospital environment. As a matter of fact, during this year of&#xD;
      pandemics, several case reports suggested a new, significant surge of post-AMI mechanical&#xD;
      complications, sometimes describing patients admitted in too severe conditions to consider&#xD;
      surgical repair a viable option, and therefore inevitably undergone an unfavorable outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore, we decided to involve the large network of European centers already participating&#xD;
      to the &quot;Caution Study 1&quot;, in order to study the impact of COVID-19 pandemics on the outcomes,&#xD;
      incidence and treatments of post-AMI mechanical complications.&#xD;
&#xD;
      &quot;Mechanical complications of acute myocardial infarction: an international multicenter cohort&#xD;
      study during COVID-19 pandemics&quot; is a retrospective, international multicenter clinical trial&#xD;
      aimed at evaluating the trend of incidence, types of treatment and survival of patients&#xD;
      admitted to hospital with a diagnosis of post-infarction mechanical complications.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>In-hospital survival</measure>
    <time_frame>interval from intervention (surgical or percutaneous) to hospital discharge (expected: up to 4 weeks)</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the in-hospital survival rate of patients admitted with a diagnosis of post-AMI mechanical complications and underwent surgical or percutaneous treatment</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">150</enrollment>
  <condition>Ventricular Septal Rupture</condition>
  <condition>Papillary Muscle Rupture</condition>
  <condition>Free Wall Rupture, Heart</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Surgical repair</intervention_name>
    <description>Surgical repair of post-infarction LVFWR or VSR</description>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Percutaneous treatment</intervention_name>
    <description>Percutaneous closure of post-infarction VSR (or treatment for LVFWR)</description>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mitral valve surgery</intervention_name>
    <description>Mitral valve repair or replacement for post-infarction PMR</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All adult patients who were diagnosed with mechanical complications of acute myocardial&#xD;
        infarction, between March 2018 to February 2021, independent of the treatment offered.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients ≥ 18 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  recent diagnosis of acute myocardial infarction;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  presence of ventricular free-wall rupture and/or ventricular septal rupture and/or&#xD;
             papillary muscle rupture.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  patients &lt; 18 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  ventricular free-wall rupture or ventricular septal rupture or papillary muscle&#xD;
             rupture not related with acute myocardial infarction.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Daniele Ronco, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+39.3479464501</phone>
    <email>daniele.ronco@live.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Matteucci Matteo</name>
      <address>
        <city>Maastricht</city>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Matteo Matteucci, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+393493556001</phone>
      <email>matteomatteucci87@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Daniele Ronco, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+393479464501</phone>
      <email>daniele.ronco@live.it</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Matteo Matteucci, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Roberto Lorusso, MD, PhD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Daniele Ronco, MD</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myocardial Infarction</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Ventricular Septal Rupture</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Heart Rupture</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Infarction</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Rupture</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

