<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="5501">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04818008</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>&quot;11-2021&quot;</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04818008</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of the Arabic Otago Exercise Program on Falls in People With Multiple Sclerosis</brief_title>
  <official_title>Measuring the Effect of Using the Arabic Otago Exercise Program on Falls and Falls-related Factors in People With Multiple Sclerosis</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Jordan</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Jordan</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      People with multiple sclerosis (MS) need exercise training programs throughout their life in&#xD;
      order to prevent secondary complications of the disease. Coronavirus disease of 2019&#xD;
      (COVID-19) forced people with chronic disorders to stay at home in order to prevent the&#xD;
      transmission of the virus. Therefore, people with MS now are facing a new challenge in going&#xD;
      outside their home to perform their rehabilitation sessions. One of the solutions to keep&#xD;
      them exercising is a home-based exercise program and one of the home exercise programs that&#xD;
      are well validated in older adults is the Otago exercise program (OEP). Investigators suggest&#xD;
      that the balance would improve and fall incidences would reduce using the OEP in people with&#xD;
      MS compared to health awareness videos only.&#xD;
&#xD;
      50 participants with confirmed diagnosis of MS will be recruited in both groups. Using a&#xD;
      randomized controlled trial this study aims to examine the effectiveness of the OEP compared&#xD;
      to a control group that gets health awareness videos only on falls and falls-related factors&#xD;
      in people with MS.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Ethical consideration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study got the ethics approval from the deanship of scientific research ethical committee&#xD;
      at University of Jordan. A consent form that contains the study procedures will be prepared&#xD;
      and signed from all patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This will be a single blinded randomized controlled trial study with 2 groups. The treatment&#xD;
      group will receive the OEP for 8 weeks plus health awareness videos about topics related to&#xD;
      MS. The control group will receive only the same health awareness videos. The health&#xD;
      awareness videos will be video-recorded by a health-care provider then sent to all&#xD;
      participants on weekly basis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
      People with a confirmed diagnosis of MS will be approached via their society and social&#xD;
      media.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Procedures:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This trial will be registered on &quot;clinicaltrials.gov&quot; registry prior to the conduction of the&#xD;
      study. Patients will be screened for eligibility and interested individuals will be informed&#xD;
      about the study details and sign the informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
      All participants will be invited to University of Jordan for the baseline and end of program&#xD;
      assessment. Demographics (age, gender, marital status, educational level) and health-related&#xD;
      information (weight in kilograms and height in meters to be combined to report BMI in kg/m^2)&#xD;
      and (caffeine consumption, smoking, present medical history, and Expanded Disability Status&#xD;
      Scale score) will be gathered before going through the study measurements as baseline&#xD;
      assessment by a licensed physical therapist (PT). The study measurements include fall&#xD;
      history, chair balance test, four test balance scale, the Modified Fatigue Impact Scale&#xD;
      (MFIS), Hand Held Dynamometer (HHD) for quadriceps muscle, Timed-Up and go (TUG), the Falls&#xD;
      Efficacy Scale-International (FES-I), the Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI), the Hospital&#xD;
      Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS), the Medical Outcomes Study Short Form 12 (SF-12), and&#xD;
      the Montreal Cognitive Assessment (MoCA).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Afterward, participants will be randomly allocated to the treatment or control groups using a&#xD;
      computer-generated software. After 8 weeks, each participant in both groups will be&#xD;
      reassessed using the same measurements used at the baseline assessment. Follow up questions&#xD;
      about falls will be asked in 6 and 12 months post-treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in the treatment group will be visited at their homes each 2 weeks. In the first&#xD;
      visit, the following steps will be conducted: (1) establish a good working relationship with&#xD;
      the participant, (2) explain the rationale for the program, (3) prescribe a set of exercises&#xD;
      from the OEP booklet and encourage the person to become familiar with the instructions for&#xD;
      each exercise, and (4) if possible, introduce a safe walking plan. Participants in the&#xD;
      treatment group will progress their exercises each 2 weeks to complete the 4 levels of OEP&#xD;
      during the 8 weeks according to the instructions of the OEP. The PT will call participants&#xD;
      weekly to make sure they are doing their exercises and to record any adverse events like&#xD;
      relapse or falling.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants in the control group will be provided with health awareness videos about topics&#xD;
      related to MS and inform them to avoid engagement in any exercise programs during the period&#xD;
      of the study. Participants will be called weekly to make sure they adhere to the&#xD;
      instructions.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">June 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2023</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of falls</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the intervention on the incidence of falls.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of falls</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months post intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the intervention on the incidence of falls.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of falls</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months post intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the intervention on the incidence of falls.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Fear of Falling (using the Falls Efficacy Scale-International )</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the intervention on fear of falling. The total score ranges between 16 and 64 with a higher score indicates greater fear of falling (worse).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Balance (using Chair balance test and Four test balance scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the intervention on balance. The time taken to conduct these balance tasks are timed using a stopwatch. The longer the time taken by the patient to perform the tasks, the worse the balance. There is no minimum or maximum scores for these tests.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Mobility (using Timed-Up and go)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the intervention on mobility. This assessments of mobility is timed out using a stopwatch.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quadriceps strength (using a dynamometer)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the intervention on quadriceps strength. The strength of quadriceps will be assessed using a dynamometer in kilograms.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The severity of fatigue (using Modified Fatigue Impact Scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the intervention on the severity of fatigue. The total score ranges from 0 to 84 with a higher score indicates greater severity of fatigue symptoms (worse).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>the Quality of sleep (Using Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the intervention on the Quality of sleep. The total score ranges from 0 to 21 with a higher score indicates poor quality of sleep (worse).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>the severity of Anxiety and Depression (using Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the intervention on the severity of Anxiety and Depression. The total score for each subscale of the HADS ranges from 0 to 21 with higher score indicates more severe anxiety or depression (worse).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Quality of Life (using Medical Outcomes Study Short Form 12)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the intervention on Quality of Life. The total score ranges between 0% to 100% with higher score indicates a better quality of life (better).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Cognitive ability (using Montreal Cognitive Assessment)</measure>
    <time_frame>2 months post intervention.</time_frame>
    <description>The effect of the intervention on Cognitive ability. The total score ranges from 0 to 30 points with a score of 25 or less indicating cognitive impairment (worse).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">50</enrollment>
  <condition>Multiple Sclerosis</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Otago Exercise Program</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive the Otago Exercise Program for 8 weeks plus health awareness videos about topics related to MS.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients will receive health awareness videos only about topics related to MS.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Otago Exercise Program</intervention_name>
    <description>A Home-based Exercise Program to improve strength and balance and prevent falls.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Otago Exercise Program</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Age of 18 years and older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Both genders&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. All types of multiple sclerosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Independent in ambulation even with the use of an assistive device.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. An Expanded Disability Status Scale (EDSS) score ≤ 6.5.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. The diagnosis of other neurological or musculoskeletal disorders that affect balance.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. If the patient had a relapse within that last four weeks.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. wheelchair users.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. If the patient is engaged in any exercise program.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alia A Alghwiri</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>University of Jordan</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Alia A Alghwiri, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+962798525162</phone>
    <email>a.ghwiri@ju.edu.jo</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jennifer A Muhaidat, PhD</last_name>
    <email>j.muhaidat@ju.edu.jo</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 28, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Jordan</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Alia A. Alghwiri</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Otago Exercise Program</keyword>
  <keyword>Falls</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Multiple Sclerosis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Sclerosis</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>March 23, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/08/NCT04818008/SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

