<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="5524">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04832152</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>412579-19406</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04832152</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Telehealth Intervention for Autism Spectrum Disorder</brief_title>
  <official_title>Testing the Feasibility of a Teletherapy Plus Parent Coaching Intervention for Children With Autism</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Thomas Jefferson University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Montefiore Medical Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Thomas Jefferson University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) is one of the most frequently occurring childhood-onset&#xD;
      neurodevelopmental disorders affecting 1 in every 54 children. Most children with ASD&#xD;
      experience challenges participating in daily activities (e.g.: eating, sleeping, bathing,&#xD;
      grooming, playing, etc.) and receive occupational therapy intervention to address these. The&#xD;
      COVID-19 pandemic has restricted in-person therapy for many of these children and there is an&#xD;
      urgent need for evidence-based, validated telehealth intervention. This project will adapt an&#xD;
      evidence-based occupational therapy intervention, termed OT4ASD to a telehealth delivery&#xD;
      model. The aims of the project are to: 1) adapt the existing intervention protocol to a&#xD;
      telehealth delivery model, 2) train therapists and evaluate the therapist's ability to&#xD;
      conduct OT4ASD, 3) determine if OT4ASD delivered via the telehealth is acceptable and&#xD;
      feasible to parents and interventionists; and 4) whether children improve in the daily living&#xD;
      skills. OT4ASD follows a systematic protocol and uses active, individually-tailored sensory&#xD;
      motor activities that are specifically designed to address the child's needs. The&#xD;
      investigators believe this will be the first telehealth manualized protocol to address the&#xD;
      sensory motor symptoms of ASD and measure outcomes at the daily life activity and&#xD;
      participation levels.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) is one of the most frequently occurring childhood-onset&#xD;
      neurodevelopmental disorders affecting 1 in every 54 children1. As a lifelong condition,&#xD;
      individuals with ASD experience a range of intellectual, behavioral, sensory, motor, and&#xD;
      functional challenges that impact successful participation in daily life activities and&#xD;
      tasks. As a result, occupational therapy (OT) intervention is a frequently requested and&#xD;
      utilized service in ASD, and clinically validated OT approaches are needed. In a series of&#xD;
      studies funded by the NIH and autism foundations, our team manualized and studied an OT&#xD;
      intervention that targets the sensory and motor factors impacting participation in daily life&#xD;
      activities and tasks and showed significant improvements in those that received the&#xD;
      intervention in comparison to controls 2-4. In this project, the investigators plan to adapt&#xD;
      our existing protocol to a telehealth model of service delivery, and evaluate its feasibility&#xD;
      and preliminary effectiveness.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The COVID-19 global pandemic created a call to action for healthcare providers to design&#xD;
      unique and innovative methods for therapeutic service delivery. This shift creates an urgent&#xD;
      need for remote solutions so that therapeutic services can be delivered in safely and&#xD;
      effectively. Since the onset of the COVID-19 pandemic, families have reported regression in&#xD;
      adaptive functioning in addition to a negative impact on social skills and increased anxiety,&#xD;
      and an impact to daily routines of children with ASD5. In a recent survey of families with&#xD;
      children with ASD, 95% of the parents reported that disruptions in services/therapies&#xD;
      negatively impacted their child's behaviors and only 35% of families were receiving&#xD;
      telehealth services/therapies6. To address these increased needs for children with ASD and to&#xD;
      meet the need of manualized telehealth intervention, the investigators propose to adapt the&#xD;
      existing intervention to a telehealth delivery model. This intervention, termed occupational&#xD;
      therapy for children with Autism Spectrum Disorder (OT4ASD) targets the sensory motor factors&#xD;
      that impact behavior and participation in life activities and tasks. This project is&#xD;
      significant in that it will address the need for evidence-based OT services for children with&#xD;
      ASD using an innovative telehealth model. Given that many children with ASD require treatment&#xD;
      for the sensory and motor symptoms that impact their optimal participation in a range of&#xD;
      daily life activities and tasks, and that the current COVID 19 pandemic has compromised&#xD;
      access to this therapy, this project is urgently needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Innovation: Telehealth offers an emerging and innovative approach for OT intervention.&#xD;
      Research shows that children with ASD require intensive intervention to assure best outcomes&#xD;
      and telehealth offers an innovative solution for providing therapy during a pandemic. To the&#xD;
      investigator's knowledge, this will be the first telehealth manualized protocol to address&#xD;
      the sensory motor symptoms of ASD and measure outcomes at the activity and participation&#xD;
      levels of the ICF framework. Importantly, the investigators will adapt an evidence-based,&#xD;
      manualized intervention with solid data on outcomes to a telehealth model. The protocol will&#xD;
      operationalize the data-driven decision making (DDDM) approach into an on-line format. DDDM&#xD;
      is innovative in that it explicitly guides the therapist to contextualize intervention within&#xD;
      the child and family's real life participation challenges and use data from assessment to&#xD;
      individualize the intervention. DDDM measures outcomes at the proximal (sensory and motor&#xD;
      factors) and distal (functional/participation-based goals) levels facilitating an&#xD;
      intervention that is context-specific and participation-oriented.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Methods: The project will first adapt the existing protocol into a telehealth delivery model&#xD;
      using a formative approach that includes a modified Delphi process to obtain input and&#xD;
      consensus from experts in telehealth and autism interventions and key stakeholders (parents&#xD;
      and clinical interventionists). Next, the investigators will conduct a feasibility trial to&#xD;
      assess the acceptability, satisfaction and implementation fidelity as well as gather data on&#xD;
      clinically meaningful outcomes. Outcomes will be measured at the proximal and distal levels&#xD;
      using validated outcome measures to assure information gained is relevant and scientifically&#xD;
      rigorous. Data from the feasibility trial will be used to support an R01 application to&#xD;
      conduct a randomized trial of OT4ASD.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To implement the project, the investigators utilize a highly skilled team of clinicians and&#xD;
      scientists with experience in conducting randomized trials in autism who will work&#xD;
      collaboratively to translate knowledge gained into useful information that will impact the&#xD;
      lives of families and children with ASD. Our approach is consistent with contemporary models&#xD;
      of evidence-based practice and rehabilitation science promoting promote high integrity,&#xD;
      evidence-based information from research that targets relevant and meaningful areas for each&#xD;
      child and family. The timeline is ambitious and the investigators feel well-equipped to meet&#xD;
      it given past experiences and expertise.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In summary, this project addresses an urgent need to provide rehabilitation services to&#xD;
      children with ASD using remote technology. It will operationalize best practices in&#xD;
      telehealth to adapt an existing evidence-based OT intervention and utilize a skilled and&#xD;
      experienced team of investigators. As such, this project is consistent with the AACPDM&#xD;
      mission to promote excellence in research and services for persons with childhood-onset&#xD;
      disabilities.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>The purpose of this project is to adapt an existing, evidence-based occupational therapy intervention for children with ASD to a telehealth delivery model. The main objectives of the project are to 1) adapt the manual so that it operationalizes best-practices of occupational therapy telehealth50,51, 2) test its feasibility, and 3) evaluate preliminary outcomes.&#xD;
Design: In the formative research aspect of this project will use survey methodology and a modified Delphi process to adapt our current intervention to a telehealth delivery model (Aim 1).&#xD;
In Aim 2 we will conduct a feasibility trial (Figure 2) to assess therapists' fidelity, participant recruitment and retention, acceptability of the protocol by parents and therapists, and clinically meaningful differences.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
    <masking_description>none. This is a feasiblity trial</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Daily Living Skills Change Score - Pediatric Evaluation of Disabilities Inventory</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in daily living skills (on a scale of 0 to 25) measured with the Pediatric Evaluation of Disabilities Inventory. Change score range 0-25.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Autism Behaviors Pervasive Developmental Disorders Behavioral Inventory T Score</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change is autism behaviors and sensory approach behaviors. Raw scores are converted to T Score</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Goal Attainment Scale T Score</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Rating of individual goals. Rating Scale -2 to +2 is converted to T-Score</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Sensory Processing Measure</measure>
    <time_frame>up to 14 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>Change in sensory hypo or hyper reactivity. T scores range from 40 to 80</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">10</enrollment>
  <condition>Autism Spectrum Disorder</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Feasibility trial group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>One group (arm) trial where all will receive treatment.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>OT4ASD</intervention_name>
    <description>Occupational therapy will focus on education and coaching of families/caregivers of children with autism spectrum disorder to help them adapt their daily routines to address their child's sensory needs.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Feasibility trial group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of Autism Spectrum Disorder&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Between the ages of 4 years 0 months and 12 years 0 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Evidence of sensory symptoms based on the Sensory Processing Measure&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Family is willing to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physically able to participate in active, sensorimotor activities&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary (visual or auditory) uncorrected sensory deficits&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Do not meet age or diagnostic criteria&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>4 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>12 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Roseann C Schaaf, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>6102912179</phone>
    <email>roseann.schaaf@jefferson.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Rachel L Dumont, M.S.</last_name>
    <phone>6107641035</phone>
    <email>rachel.dumont@jefferson.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 9, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Autistic Disorder</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Autism Spectrum Disorder</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Yes</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Publication in high impact autism journal, and presentation at international autism research meetings.</ipd_description>
    <ipd_info_type>Study Protocol</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Statistical Analysis Plan (SAP)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_info_type>Informed Consent Form (ICF)</ipd_info_type>
    <ipd_time_frame>Data will be available following completion of the study and publication of findings.</ipd_time_frame>
    <ipd_access_criteria>Upon written request (reviewed by principal investigator) information will be shared.</ipd_access_criteria>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

