<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="139">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04817319</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>APHP200933</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04817319</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Risk of Contamination by COVID-19 During Oral Care With Aerosolization</brief_title>
  <acronym>Bu-Covid</acronym>
  <official_title>Risk of Contamination by COVID-19 During Oral Care With Aerosolization</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Institut National de la Santé Et de la Recherche Médicale, France</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The sudden Covid-19 pandemic has led all healthcare workers to adapt to an unprecedented&#xD;
      situation by continuing to provide care while protecting themselves and their patients.&#xD;
      Medical care with aerosolization systems is particularly of risk because of the strong&#xD;
      propagation of the droplets they generate, especially during oral care. Considering the high&#xD;
      risk of transmission of the SARS-CoV-2 virus in dental structures remain essential and still&#xD;
      very challenging. The need to put in place care procedures to protect the nursing staff and&#xD;
      patients is definitely more than necessary. Dental protection equipments against this&#xD;
      emergent virus have progressively integrated daily practice, but, to the knowledge of the&#xD;
      investigators, no study has precisely evaluated their efficiency.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The main objective of this study is to estimate the risk of dental practitioners to be&#xD;
      contaminated by SARS-CoV-2 during dental procedures with or without aerosolization&#xD;
      procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For this, after their informed consent, vaccinated dental practitioners or practitioners with&#xD;
      a positive covid serological tests of the dental department of Charles Foix hospital will&#xD;
      receive individually forty to fifty COVID+ patients. COVID + patients will be included a&#xD;
      maximum of one week after the diagnosis of the pathology. Patient care will be determined and&#xD;
      performed according to standard practice as part of their standard management and without&#xD;
      interference with the study. The usual measures to protect caregivers. The included patients&#xD;
      will undergo an oral dental procedure either with aerosolisation or not. Then, SARS-CoV 2&#xD;
      samples will be collected using viral swabs on different spots, followed by detection and&#xD;
      quantification by PCR. Swabbing will be achieved on:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The facial skin, nasal, ocular and oral mucosa of the practitioners.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The protection equipment of the practitioners (FFP2 masks, visors,surgical calot,gloves)&#xD;
           .&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The environment (dental Chair, surgical light, turbine, contra-angle, on the ground..)&#xD;
           The presence of viral loads in areas used by COVID + patients will be evaluated by PCR&#xD;
           after swabbing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will provide insight into the risk of SARS-CoV 2 contamination for practitioners&#xD;
      performing dental procedures in COVID + patients. This risk will be assessed at the level of&#xD;
      the facial skin and oral mucous membranes, which are the doors of entry of the virus.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will thus make it possible to assess the protective capacity of the protection&#xD;
      protocol implemented in investigators' department in this epidemic situation. This will be&#xD;
      assessed depending on whether or not aerosolization is used, its type and the nature of the&#xD;
      ventilation in the operating room.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Introduction The outbreak of severe acute respiratory syndrome with coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV&#xD;
      2) in Wuhan, China, in December 2019, quickly turned into a global pandemic (12 March 2020,&#xD;
      WHO) leading most countries to take exceptional health measures. Indeed, in the absence of a&#xD;
      proven treatment against COVID-19, the preventive approach aimed at reducing the risk of&#xD;
      transmission; containment, barrier measures, has been put forward in many countries.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In this context, healthcare workers are in the front line of SARS-CoV 2 and present a high&#xD;
      risk of contamination. Among them, dentists have been identified as the health professionals&#xD;
      most at risk of contamination by SARS-CoV2. Indeed, SARS-CoV2 is transmitted, directly or&#xD;
      indirectly, by respiratory secretions via airborne particles called aerosols. The virus can&#xD;
      thus be detected in secretions from the nasopharynx but also in saliva.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For the specialities covering the ENT sphere, the main routes of contamination are blood,&#xD;
      saliva droplets and direct contact with the patient. For SARS-CoV 2, its high contagiousness&#xD;
      adds to the risk factors related to the proximity of the oral cavity of patients during care.&#xD;
      Contact with nebulisers such as ultrasound (used for scaling), turbines or contra-angles&#xD;
      (used for tooth and jawbone milling) contribute to aerosol and splash formation. Aerosols&#xD;
      remain suspended in the air for several minutes, and can therefore increase the risk of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV2 infection. Aerosols from an infected patient can increase the risk of infection for&#xD;
      ENT professionals and the risk of spreading the virus to other patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For example, oral health care has been reduced to emergencies only in many countries. The&#xD;
      same is true in France where the recommendations of the ARS and the Order of Dental Surgeons&#xD;
      have followed the same objectives .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Globally, the only available studies on dental care during COVID have reviewed the&#xD;
      organisation and procedures in place in dental departments.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, no study has assessed the specific risk of SARS-CoV 2 contamination for&#xD;
      practitioners, especially for procedures performed with aerosolisation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is therefore essential to assess the risk of contamination for practitioners performing&#xD;
      care on a cohort of COVID+ patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Research hypothesis The hypothesis of this research project is that the protection protocols&#xD;
      (patient circuit, personal protective equipment (PPE)), implemented in the oral medicine&#xD;
      department of the Charles Foix Hospital, effectively protect oral health care workers from a&#xD;
      Covid-19 infection, whether for care with or without nebulisation (aerosolisation). These&#xD;
      protocols, once validated in this study, would be applicable and can be generalised.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of the study population and rationale for its choice The patients: COVID+&#xD;
      patients who will undergo a dental procedure will be included at most one week after the&#xD;
      diagnosis of the pathology. This is because the viral load is increased in the saliva of an&#xD;
      infected patient within this time frame (would increase the risk of infection in oral health&#xD;
      professionals .&#xD;
&#xD;
      Practitioners: these are the dental surgeons, oral surgeons, interns and externs in dental&#xD;
      surgery affiliated with the odontology department of the Charles Foix Hospital (APHP). These&#xD;
      practitioners are at risk of contamination during aerosolisation procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of procedures or products used in accordance with standard practice The patients&#xD;
      included will all undergo an oral procedure with or without aerosolisation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The care of COVID+ patients follows the procedure established in the Charles Foix during this&#xD;
      health crisis. Patient care will be determined and carried out according to usual practice as&#xD;
      part of their standard care and without interference with the study. The usual protective&#xD;
      measures for caregivers include: FFP2 masks, visors, gloves, caps, and gowns. Hydro-alcoholic&#xD;
      rubbing before and after care is performed systematically&#xD;
&#xD;
      The risk of contamination of practitioners will be assessed in the following way:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  A description of the projection areas (and therefore contamination) on the PPE and the&#xD;
           environment. For this purpose, fluorescein will be added to the mouthwash for&#xD;
           non-aerosolised procedures and to the irrigation system for aerosolised procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The procedure rooms will be exposed to a UV lamp. Pictures will be taken to visualise&#xD;
           the contaminated areas. An estimate of the level of contamination for each procedure&#xD;
           will be made by counting the number of fluorescent sprays per unit of total area.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  At the end of each procedure, surface swabs will be taken from the PPE (visors and&#xD;
           gloves) as well as from the facial skin and mucous membranes (oral, ocular, nasal) of&#xD;
           the practitioner, followed by detection and quantification by PCR (main evaluation&#xD;
           criterion).&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  The presence of viral loads on the areas used by COVID+ patients will be assessed by PCR&#xD;
           after swabbing.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Biological collection The RNA samples taken during the research will not be the subject of a&#xD;
      biological collection.&#xD;
&#xD;
      During the research, the collections will be kept and analysed in Cordeliers laboratory&#xD;
      (INSERM U1138 unit) under the responsibility of François Ferré. They will be destroyed at the&#xD;
      end of the PCR analyses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Risks and vigilance Adverse effects observed in patients participating in the research are&#xD;
      reported by the investigators in accordance with the local vigilance plans set up in the&#xD;
      context of healthcare activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data management The patients' medical and dental data will be collected on the same day on a&#xD;
      dedicated database (Excel type).The PCR data of the practitioners will be collected at the&#xD;
      Cordeliers Research Centre and stored on a dedicated database (Excel type), the PCR results&#xD;
      will then be sent to Dr Ferré (Dispose).&#xD;
&#xD;
      A correspondence database (Excel file) linking the subject's identity to the pseudonymised&#xD;
      identifier will be kept within the hospital department in a secure computer file on a single&#xD;
      workstation identified and secured by the password of the coordinating investigator.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In accordance with GCP :&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the sponsor is responsible for obtaining the agreement of all parties involved in the&#xD;
           research to ensure direct access to all research sites, source data, source documents&#xD;
           and reports for quality control and audit purposes by the sponsor,&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  the investigators will make available to the persons in charge of monitoring, quality&#xD;
           control, in the event of an audit of the research involving the human person, the&#xD;
           documents and individual data strictly necessary for this control, in accordance with&#xD;
           the legislative and regulatory provisions in force Source documents, defined as any&#xD;
           original document or object that can be used to prove the existence or accuracy of a&#xD;
           data item or fact recorded during the research, will be kept for 15 years by the&#xD;
           investigator or by the hospital in the case of a hospital medical file.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Within the framework of the research, additional examinations (serological examinations&#xD;
      linked to the COVID status of patients, biological examinations, imaging, etc.) will be&#xD;
      scanned and kept in the ORBIS computerised medical file dedicated to the patient.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The persons responsible for the quality control of research involving the human person&#xD;
      (article L.1121-3 of the public health code), will take all the necessary precautions to&#xD;
      ensure the confidentiality of the information relating to the research, to the persons who&#xD;
      take part in it and in particular with regard to their identity as well as the results&#xD;
      obtained.&#xD;
&#xD;
      These persons, in the same way as the investigators themselves, are subject to professional&#xD;
      secrecy (in accordance with the conditions defined by articles 226-13 and 226-14 of the penal&#xD;
      code).&#xD;
&#xD;
      During research involving the human person and at its conclusion, the data collected on the&#xD;
      persons involved and transmitted to the sponsor by the investigators (or any other&#xD;
      specialist) must be made non-identifying.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Under no circumstances should the names of the persons concerned or their addresses appear in&#xD;
      clear text. Only the coded (pseudonymised) identifiers of the subjects included will be&#xD;
      recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sponsor will ensure that each person who takes part in the research has given his/her&#xD;
      consent to access his/her individual data which are strictly necessary for the quality&#xD;
      control of the research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The AP-HP is the owner of the data and no use or transmission to a third party can be made&#xD;
      without its prior agreement.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical aspects Seventy odontological procedures will be evaluated in the study. This&#xD;
      number of 70 procedures was set to allow a sufficiently informative estimate of the&#xD;
      proportions of procedures resulting in muco-cutaneous contamination of the practitioners who&#xD;
      performed the procedures. Thus, if the observed frequency is 10% (7 out of 70), the estimate&#xD;
      of the percentage will be known with a precision close to 10% IC95% = [4%; 19.5%], and under&#xD;
      the expected hypothesis that no contamination would be observed among 70 procedures, the 95%&#xD;
      confidence interval will then make it possible to exclude a risk of contamination higher than&#xD;
      5% (IC95%=[0%; 5. 1%]) and thus to be able to conclude with robustness that there is a very&#xD;
      low risk of contamination of odontological procedures in COVID+ patients under the usual&#xD;
      protective conditions.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical analyses will be performed at the end of the inclusion period (6 months). The URC&#xD;
      of the Pitié-Salpétrière Hospital will be responsible for the statistical analysis of the&#xD;
      data from the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of the statistical methods&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Subgroup analyses by Cochran test:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ocular mucosa/Nasal mucosa/Oral mucosa/Facial skin&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Face / PPE&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Oral procedures with aerosolization/ Oral procedures without aerosolization&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Ventilated rooms/ Non-ventilated rooms&#xD;
&#xD;
      Ethical and legal aspects The Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris is the promoter of this&#xD;
      research and by delegation the Clinical Research and Innovation Department (DRCI) is&#xD;
      responsible for its missions, in accordance with article L.1121-1 of the public health code.&#xD;
      Assistance Publique - Hôpitaux de Paris reserves the right to interrupt the research at any&#xD;
      time for administrative reasons.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The practitioner and the patient who meet the selection criteria can only be included in the&#xD;
      study after they have received the study information notes and have indicated that they do&#xD;
      not object to participating.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In accordance with article L1121-1-1 of the Public Health Code, no non-interventional&#xD;
      research may be performed on a person if he or she has objected to it after having been given&#xD;
      the information provided for in article L11222-1 of the same code.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A copy of the information document is given to the person prior to participation in the&#xD;
      research.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The information given to the subject will be notified in his or her medical file.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator or the qualified person who collects the subject's non-opposition will&#xD;
      record it in his/her medical file.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Requesting an opinion from the Committee for the Protection of Persons (CPP) The AP-HP, as&#xD;
      the promoter, obtains a favourable opinion from the relevant CPP for research that meets the&#xD;
      definition of 3° of article L.1121-1 of the Public Health Code, prior to its implementation,&#xD;
      within the framework of its competences and in accordance with the legislative and regulatory&#xD;
      provisions in force.&#xD;
&#xD;
      FUNDING A financial contribution from the Fondation des Gueules Cassées is expected to&#xD;
      finance the purchase of reagents necessary for the PCR.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the risk of skin and mucous membrane contamination of practitioners during oral care performed on patients diagnosed with COVID +.</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after the beginning of the study</time_frame>
    <description>Percentage of odontological procedures leading to the detection of SARS-CoV 2 on the face (skin surface and facial mucous membranes) of practitioners performing procedures on COVID + patients</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the presence of SARS-CoV 2 on the face and facial mucous membranes of practitioners after the dental procedure depending on whether: • the procedure involves aerosolization (turbine, ultrasonic scaler,…),</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after the beginning of the study</time_frame>
    <description>Calculation of the percentages of procedures leading to the detection of SARS-CoV 2 on the face (skin surface and facial mucous membranes) of the practitioners performing the interventions depending on whether the procedure involves aerosolization or not.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the presence of SARS-CoV 2 on the face and facial mucous membranes of practitioners after the dental procedure depending on whether: • the procedure does not involve aerosolization (intraoral examination, intraoral X-ray, biopsy)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after the beginning of the study</time_frame>
    <description>Calculation of the percentages of procedures leading to the detection of SARS-CoV 2 on the face (skin surface and facial mucous membranes) of the practitioners performing the interventions depending on whether the procedure involves aerosolization or not.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Determine the presence of SARS-CoV 2 on personal protective equipment (PPE) depending on whether: • the procedure involves aerosolization (contra-angle, ultrasonic scaler),</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after the beginning of the study</time_frame>
    <description>Calculation of the percentages of procedures leading to the presence of SARS-CoV 2 detected on PPE depending on whether the procedure involves aerosolization or not</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the risk of contamination of practitioners, PPE and surfaces depending on the type of aerosolization used (contra-angle, ultrasonic scaler)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after the beginning of the study</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of viral loads and projections on PPE and the face (skin surface and facial mucous membranes) according to the aerosolizations used (contra-angle, ultrasound)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the risk of contamination of practitioners, PPE and surfaces depending on the type of aerosolization used (contra-angle, ultrasonic scaler)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after the beginning of the study</time_frame>
    <description>Comparison of the exposure time.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the presence of viral loads in areas used by COVID + patients</measure>
    <time_frame>6 months after the beginning of the study</time_frame>
    <description>PCR test on the surfaces of areas used by COVID + patients</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Contamination by COVID 19 During Oral Care</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Major patients diagnosed with Covid + requiring oral care.</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Procedure</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Oral care with/without aerosolization</intervention_name>
    <description>These treatments involve instruments that produce aerosolization: ultrasonic scaler, rotary instrumentation for caries care, dental extraction, tooth polishing.&#xD;
These care correspond to examinations of the oral cavity, intraoral X-rays or even periodontal pocket probing.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Major patients diagnosed with Covid + requiring oral care.</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        COVID + patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Over the age of 18&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tested positively a maximum of one week before inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Requiring oral care&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Affiliates or beneficiaries of Social Security • Informed and not opposed to&#xD;
             participating in the research&#xD;
&#xD;
        Practitioners&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age under 65&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of comorbidity (hypertension, obesity, diabetes)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed and not opposed to participating in the research&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        COVID + patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  State of health incompatible with oral care.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient under guardianship / curators&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant or breastfeeding patients&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnant / breastfeeding woman&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>François Ferré, Degree Associate professor</last_name>
    <phone>0033) 6 95 17 69 65</phone>
    <email>francois.ferre@aphp.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Dental care</keyword>
  <keyword>Aerosols</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

