<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2345">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04842721</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04842721</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effect of Hypertonic Saturated Saline Mouth Rinse on Covid-19 Virus in Vivo.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Effect of Prolonged Mouth Rinse With Hypertonic Saturated Saline Solution on the Naso-Pharyngeal Viral Load of Covid-19 Virus in Vivo.</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Rafik Batroussy</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Batroussy, Rafik</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Sars-Cov2 virus is transmitted through the respiratory route and by direct contact with&#xD;
      contaminated surfaces and subsequent contact with nasal, oral or ocular mucosa. Many studies&#xD;
      have found that the oral cavity and specifically the saliva may be a high-risk route for&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 infection. Thus, strategies reducing salivary viral load could contribute to&#xD;
      reduce the risk of transmission. Furthermore, studies have shown that SARS-CoV persists for&#xD;
      two days in oral mucous membranes before its diffusion to the lower respiratory tract. This&#xD;
      offers an interesting preventive and therapeutic window of opportunity for the control of&#xD;
      this disease. In addition, Naso-pharyngeal viral load was linked with lung disease severity&#xD;
      in a study of 12 patients with pneumonia.**. Some current studies around the world, as listed&#xD;
      on ClinicalTrials.gov, are testing the effect of some common mouth rinses/gargles on the&#xD;
      Covid-19 viral load, including Chlorhexidine gluconate, Hydrogen peroxide Povidone Iodine,&#xD;
      Saline (1.102% w/v, slightly hypertonic) and Alcohol.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study aims to test whether Prolonged Hypertonic Saline Mouth Rinse would&#xD;
      reduce/eliminate*** the viral load in the Oro- Naso-Pharyngeal cavity, and could therefore be&#xD;
      used as a strategy to reduce transmission risk in clinical and social settings.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigator hypothesizes that COVID-19-positive participants who use Hypertonic Saline&#xD;
      Prolonged Rinse treatment will have an reduction/elimination of their Covid viral load, will&#xD;
      develop a negative Covid test 7 days after intervention completion and will improve their&#xD;
      clinical symptoms, potentially reducing lung disease severity.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to determine if prolonged rinsing (15 minutes) of mouth without&#xD;
      gargling using a Hypertonic Saturated Sodium Chloride solution would reduce/eliminate the&#xD;
      Upper Respiratory viral load in Covid-19 infected patients compared to a placebo (Plain Water&#xD;
      Rinse). Patients who have been tested positive for COVID-19 using Nucleic Acid Test via Nose&#xD;
      or Throat Swabs within 7 days prior to the start of the trial will be instructed to use&#xD;
      either of the two treatment arms (Active or Placebo) for 15 minutes twice daily for two days&#xD;
      and retested for Covid 7 days after the last treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
      A randomized blinded controlled study, whereas a number of patients (at least 20) with&#xD;
      clinically-confirmed Covid-19 infection within 7 days prior to the start of the study, are&#xD;
      equally divided into 2 groups, Active and Control groups, using Active and Control Mouth&#xD;
      rinses respectively. The Active Rinse is a 25 ml of Hypertonic Saturated Saline solution made&#xD;
      by mixing 10 grams of Sodium Chloride (Table Salt) in 25 ml of Tap water with some salt&#xD;
      crystals deposited. The Control Rinse is a 25 ml of Plain Tap Water. Each Patient of both&#xD;
      groups will be asked to keep the solution still in his/her mouth, close to the back of the&#xD;
      mouth, for 15 minutes without gargling and without swallowing. After 15 minutes the solution&#xD;
      will be spit out and mouth will be rinsed with plain water several times. The process will be&#xD;
      done twice a day for 2 days. Patients of both groups will be tested once for Covid-19 7 days&#xD;
      after the last treatment.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">July 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">October 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>A randomized blinded controlled study, whereas a number of patients (at least 20) with clinically-confirmed Covid-19 infection within 7 days prior to the start of the study, are equally divided into 2 groups, Active and Control groups, using Active and Control Mouth rinses respectively. The Active Rinse is a 25 ml of Hypertonic Saturated Saline solution made by mixing 10 grams of Sodium Chloride (Table Salt) in 25 ml of Tap water with some salt crystals deposited. The Control Rinse is a 25 ml of Plain Tap Water. Each Patient of both groups will be asked to keep the solution still in his/her mouth, close to the back of the mouth, for 15 minutes without gargling and without swallowing. After 15 minutes the solution will be spit out and mouth will be rinsed with plain water several times. The process will be done twice a day for 2 days. Patients of both groups will be tested once for Covid-19 7 days after the last treatment.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Participant)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Viral Load Outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>The Hypertonic Saturated Mouth Rinse intervention will be considered effective in reducing/eliminating Covid presence in the Oro-Nasopharyngeal area if the PCR Covid test performed 7 days post termination of the study has a negative result.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Clinical Symptoms Outcome</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days</time_frame>
    <description>A reduction in the Clinical symptoms of Covid (like fever, shortness of breath, dry cough, reduced lung functions, ..) will be monitored and statistically analyzed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">20</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Hypertonic Saturated Saline Mouth Rinse Active Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The Active Rinse is a 25 ml of Hypertonic Saturated Saline solution made by mixing 10 grams of Sodium Chloride (Table Salt) in 25 ml of Tap water with some salt crystals deposited.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Plain Water Control Arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>The Control Rinse is a 25 ml of Plain Tap Water.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Hypertonic Saturated Saline Mouth Rinse Active Arm</intervention_name>
    <description>Each Patient of this groups will be asked to keep the solution still in his/her mouth, close to the back of the mouth, for 15 minutes without gargling and without swallowing. After 15 minutes the solution will be spit out and mouth will be rinsed with plain water several times. The process will be done twice a day for 2 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Hypertonic Saturated Saline Mouth Rinse Active Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo Plain Water Mouth Rinse Arm</intervention_name>
    <description>Each Patient of this groups will be asked to keep the water still in his/her mouth, close to the back of the mouth, for 15 minutes without gargling and without swallowing. After 15 minutes the water will be spit out. The process will be done twice a day for 2 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Plain Water Control Arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tested positive for Covid in the past 7 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Have the ability to perform mouth rinse twice daily for 2 days and to undergo Covid&#xD;
             testing by Oro or Naso-Pharyngeal swabs.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  No need for a ventilator for oxygenation support&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Can understand and read English&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Lives in Alberta Canada&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Requiring mechanical ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unable to perform mouth rinses twice times daily for 2 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients that are tested negative for COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who have been eating or drinking within an hour before or after each session&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of an antiseptic mouthwash within 7 days prior or after the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient who are intubated or too sick to give consent for the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not able to speak in English or lacking the decision-making capacity to consent for&#xD;
             study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Inability to comply with protocol&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Rafik Batroussy, BSc.Pharm.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Independent</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Rafik Batroussy, BSc.Pharm.</last_name>
    <phone>4037964441</phone>
    <email>rafikbatroussy@hotmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Rafik Batroussy</name>
      <address>
        <city>Calgary</city>
        <state>Alberta</state>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC7582358/</url>
    <description>Antiviral Activity of Reagents in Mouth Rinses against SARS-CoV-2</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.cnn.com/2020/11/03/health/covid-test-negative-contagious-wellness/index.html</url>
    <description>Viral load under detectable levels can result in a False Negative PCR Covid test</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 13, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 13, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Batroussy, Rafik</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Rafik Batroussy</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>BSc.Pharm., RPEBC</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Rinse, Mouth Rinse, Mouthwash, Mouth Wash</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

