<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="477">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04784403</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>UB-EPI-2020-01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04784403</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>SCREENING AND SEROEPIDEMIOLOGY OF SARS-CoV-2 INFECTION AT THE UNIVERSITY OF BARCELONA: A CROSS-SECTIONAL STUDY</brief_title>
  <acronym>UB-GTMS-COVID</acronym>
  <official_title>SCREENING AND SEROEPIDEMIOLOGY OF SARS-CoV-2 INFECTION AT THE UNIVERSITY OF BARCELONA: A CROSS-SECTIONAL STUDY</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Dr. Francisco Ciruela Alférez</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Gerencia Territorial del Área Metropolitana Sur - Instituto Catalán de la Salud</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Hospital Universitario de Bellvitge</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Fundació IDIBELL</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Barcelona</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      BACKGROUND: On January 7, 2020, the Chinese authorities identified as the agent responsible&#xD;
      for the cases of atypical pneumonia of unknown etiology a new type of virus of the&#xD;
      Coronaviridae family that has subsequently been named SARS-CoV-2, whose genetic sequence was&#xD;
      shared by Chinese authorities on January 12 (taxonomy ID: 2697049). On January 30, 2020, the&#xD;
      director general of the World Health Organization (WHO), following the advice of the&#xD;
      Emergency Committee convened in accordance with the International Health Regulations (2005),&#xD;
      declared that the COVID-19 outbreak started in Wuhan, China in December 2019, being a public&#xD;
      health emergency of international concern. On March 11, the WHO declared the global&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      So far, in the absence of effective vaccines or antiviral drugs, efforts have focused on&#xD;
      identifying cases and their contacts. Both the cases and their contacts are isolated for&#xD;
      about 14 days with the intention of minimizing the spread of this infection and avoiding an&#xD;
      increase in the number of affected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the time of writing this new version of the protocol, we are immersed in the second wave&#xD;
      of the COVID-19 pandemic. The projections of the natural history of the disease and the&#xD;
      estimates of possible infections by SARS-CoV-2, carried out at the end of the first wave,&#xD;
      made it possible to determine the feasibility of this second wave with the onset of cold from&#xD;
      the autumn.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given this scenario, the University of Barcelona, together with the Gerencia Territorial del&#xD;
      Área Metropolitana Sud, has planned to carry out, a study of seroprevalence and screnning of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 in the population of Universidad de Barcelona users.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The results of this study will help to make preventive decisions in the face of SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      infection at the UB, in relation to its teaching and administrative activities. In addition,&#xD;
      this cross-sectional study can serve as the base study for a future follow-up study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HYPOTHESIS: The incidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection in the group of students and workers at the&#xD;
      University of Barcelona is similar to the incidence in the general population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MAIN OBJECTIVE:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Estimate the incidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection in the UB community.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Estimate the SARS-CoV-2 seroprevalence infection in the UB community.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      BACKGROUND: On January 7, 2020, the Chinese authorities identified as the agent responsible&#xD;
      for the cases of atypical pneumonia of unknown etiology a new type of virus of the&#xD;
      Coronaviridae family that has subsequently been named SARS-CoV-2, whose genetic sequence was&#xD;
      shared by Chinese authorities on January 12 (taxonomy ID: 2697049).&#xD;
&#xD;
      On January 30, 2020, the director general of the World Health Organization (WHO), following&#xD;
      the advice of the Emergency Committee convened in accordance with the International Health&#xD;
      Regulations (2005), declared that the COVID-19 outbreak started in Wuhan, China in December&#xD;
      2019, being a public health emergency of international concern. On March 11, the WHO declared&#xD;
      the global SARS-CoV-2 pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      So far, in the absence of effective vaccines or antiviral drugs, efforts have focused on&#xD;
      identifying cases and their contacts. Both the cases and their contacts are isolated for&#xD;
      about 14 days with the intention of minimizing the spread of this infection and avoiding an&#xD;
      increase in the number of affected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the level of microbiological clinical practice, the diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection can&#xD;
      be made by:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Detection of the presence of the target nucleic acid sequences in the RNA of SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
           (RdRP gene of SARSCoV-2 and gene N and Orf1ab present in SARS and SARSCoV-2, gene E of&#xD;
           SARS) in the Patient specimen by reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction&#xD;
           (RT-PCR).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Detection of antibodies: total immunoglobulins and IgG.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the time of writing this new version of the protocol, the country is immersed in the&#xD;
      second wave of the COVID-19 pandemic. The projections of the natural history of the disease&#xD;
      and the estimates of possible infections by SARS-CoV-2, carried out at the end of the first&#xD;
      wave, made it possible to determine the feasibility of this second wave with the onset of&#xD;
      cold from the autumn. Some of the factors that supported this hypothesis are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. At the end of the first wave, herd immunity against the virus was not reached. The&#xD;
           results of the ENE-COVID study, published in the Lancet magazine in July this year,&#xD;
           indicated that in our environment only 6% have achieved immunity.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Many respiratory viruses have a seasonal behavior and their circulation increases in the&#xD;
           autumn and winter months. This is why a similar behavior was assumed in this new&#xD;
           SARS-CoV-2 virus, experiencing greater transmissibility with the drop in temperature and&#xD;
           increase in humidity, typical of winter periods.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Observing the evolution of the 1918 pandemic flu, the first wave was in 1918, but this&#xD;
           was followed by a second and third wave, in 1919 and 1920 respectively. However, the&#xD;
           second wave presented the peculiarity of being triggered in other areas where the first&#xD;
           wave had not been so intense.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Given this scenario, the University of Barcelona, together with the Gerencia Territorial del&#xD;
      Área Metropolitana Sud, has planned to carry out, a study of seroprevalence and screnning of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 in the population of UB users. The results of this study will help to make&#xD;
      preventive decisions in the face of SARS-CoV-2 infection at the UB, in relation to its&#xD;
      teaching and administrative activities. In addition, this cross-sectional study can serve as&#xD;
      the base study for a future follow-up study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      HYPOTHESIS: The incidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection in the group of students and workers at the&#xD;
      University of Barcelona is similar to the incidence in the general population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The seroprevalence of SARS-CoV-2 infection in the group of students and workers at the&#xD;
      University of Barcelona is similar to the seroprevalence of the general population.&#xD;
&#xD;
      MAIN OBJECTIVE&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Estimate the incidence of SARS-CoV-2 infection in the UB community.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Estimate the SARS-CoV-2 seroprevalence infection in the UB community.&#xD;
&#xD;
      SECONDARY OBJECTIVES&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Estimate the factors associated with the incidence in the UB community.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -  Estimate the factors associated with seroprevalence in the UB community&#xD;
&#xD;
      STUDY DESIGN Cross-sectional study with epidemiological information to determine the&#xD;
      incidence and prevalence of SARS-CoV-2 infection in the UB population, by PCR and serology&#xD;
      tests to detect antibodies.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 14, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 24, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 24, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Ecologic or Community</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of people with a positive SARS-CoV-2 PCR.</measure>
    <time_frame>one day</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of people with a positive SARS-CoV-2 PCR.</measure>
    <time_frame>one day</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of people with a positive total immunoglobulin titer and positive IgG for SARS-CoV-2.</measure>
    <time_frame>one day</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of people with a positive total immunoglobulin titer and positive IgG for SARS-CoV-2.</measure>
    <time_frame>one day</time_frame>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Number of people with a positive SARS-CoV-2 Ig total titer and a negative IgG.</measure>
    <time_frame>one day</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Estimation of associated factors ith the main variable (age, sex, university group and variables of exposure and preventive measures)</measure>
    <time_frame>one day</time_frame>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">3356</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV-2 Infection</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Students and workers at the University of Barcelona</arm_group_label>
    <description>The study population will be randomly selected from the different groups of the University:&#xD;
Students from the different centers and type of studies (undergraduate / graduate).&#xD;
Administrative and service personnel.&#xD;
Teaching and Research Staff.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>SARS-CoV-2 PCR and serology tests</intervention_name>
    <description>Once the informed consent has been signed, the selected subjects must complete an epidemiological survey and go to a UB sample collection center to perform a PCR and serology test for SARS-CoV-2.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Students and workers at the University of Barcelona</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>epidemiological survey</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The target population of this study is made up of students and workers at the University of&#xD;
        Barcelona:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Students from the different centers and type of studies (undergraduate / graduate).&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Administrative and service personnel.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Teaching and Research Staff.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult population (18 years or more), of both sexes.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person linked (with identification card) to the University of Barcelona.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Acceptance to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        There are no exclusion criteria.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sebastià Videla Cés, MD PhD</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Hospital Universitario de Bellvitge</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Esteve Fernández Muñoz, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Universidad de Barcelona</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Francisco Ciruela Alférez</name>
      <address>
        <city>L'Hospitalet De Llobregat</city>
        <state>Barcelona</state>
        <zip>08907</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.mscbs.gob.es/ciudadanos/ene-covid/docs/ESTUDIO_ENE-COVID19_SEGUNDA_RONDA_INFORME_PRELIMINAR.pdf</url>
    <description>ene-COVID19 study: first round national study of the sero-epidemiology of the infection by SARS-COV-2 in Spain. Preliminary report June 3, 2020</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.mscbs.gob.es/profesionales/saludPublica/ccayes/alertasActual/nCov-China/documentos/ITCoronavirus.pdf</url>
    <description>Scientific-technical information report on coronavirus disease, COVID-19 in Spain. Center for Coordination of Health Alerts and Emergencies. July 3, 2020.</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/situation-reports/20200817-weekly-epi-update-1.pdf?sfvrsn=b6d49a76_4</url>
    <description>Situation report Nro. 168 about coronavirus disease (COVID-19). World Health Organization. 16 July 2020.</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Pollán M, Pérez-Gómez B, Pastor-Barriuso R, Oteo J, Hernán MA, Pérez-Olmeda M, Sanmartín JL, Fernández-García A, Cruz I, Fernández de Larrea N, Molina M, Rodríguez-Cabrera F, Martín M, Merino-Amador P, León Paniagua J, Muñoz-Montalvo JF, Blanco F, Yotti R; ENE-COVID Study Group. Prevalence of SARS-CoV-2 in Spain (ENE-COVID): a nationwide, population-based seroepidemiological study. Lancet. 2020 Aug 22;396(10250):535-544. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)31483-5. Epub 2020 Jul 6.</citation>
    <PMID>32645347</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>5. Albert Bosch. SARS-CoV-2: ¿No solo un virus? Ciclo de webinars. Patógenos Online. Grupo Especializado en Biología de Microrganismos Patógenos (GEBMP). Sociedad Española de Microbiología, 30 de junio de 2020.</citation>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 21, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 3, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 3, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 3, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Barcelona</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Dr. Francisco Ciruela Alférez</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Sponsor's representative</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-COV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>prevalence</keyword>
  <keyword>Associated factors</keyword>
  <keyword>University of Barcelona</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

