<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4061">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04785807</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>69HCL20_0678</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04785807</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>STRESS From in Charge Relative Facing the Announcement of Decisions Limiting or Stopping Treatments in Emergency Room During the COVID-19 Epidemic</brief_title>
  <acronym>COVER ACC</acronym>
  <official_title>STRESS From in Charge Relative Facing the Announcement of Decisions Limiting or Stopping Treatments in Emergency Room During the COVID-19 Epidemic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hospices Civils de Lyon</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hospices Civils de Lyon</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In the context of the COVID-19 pandemic, the emergency reception services had to be radically&#xD;
      reorganized. In this tense environment, professionals must face ethical dilemmas, make&#xD;
      referral decisions and prioritize patients. Due to the limited number of visits to many&#xD;
      hospitals, interactions with relatives and families of patients are mainly conducted by&#xD;
      phone. These limitations will continue as long as the context of uncertainty over the course&#xD;
      of the pandemic persists. Limitation or discontinuation of treatment (LDT) announcements were&#xD;
      therefore also impacted and the exceptional situation related to COVID-19 reinforces the&#xD;
      difficulties encountered by professionals in usual time (place of announcement, inappropriate&#xD;
      lack of time, etc.). Thus, LDTs are most often done over the phone without the families being&#xD;
      able to go to the hospital. Because of this, these announcements can be more traumatic.&#xD;
      Investigators have already highlighted in a recent study the lack of communication between&#xD;
      caregivers and families in the context of LDT announcements and the context of COVID 19&#xD;
      exacerbated these aspects given the limitations of visits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators therefore propose to study the experiences of families who are notified of&#xD;
      a decision to limit or stop treatment by phone in the emergency room during the COVID-19&#xD;
      crisis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Post traumatic syndrome evaluated thanks to the Revised impact event scale (IES-R)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after limitation or discontinuation of treatment announcement</time_frame>
    <description>The primary endpoint is the evaluation of Post traumatic syndrome among the family member or person of trust of a patient who received a limitation or discontinuation of treatment, 30 days after this announcement. The post traumatic syndrome will be evaluated thanks to the Revised impact event scale (IES-R) giving a score going from 0 to 88. The greater the score, the worse the outcome is.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety level at day 7, assessed using the Hospitalized Anxiety and Depression Scale-(HADS)</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of Anxiety among the family member or person of trust of a patient who received a limitation or discontinuation of treatment, 7 days after this announcement. Anxiety will be assessed using the Hospitalized Anxiety and Depression Scale, giving two scores (one for anxiety, one for depression) going from 0 to 21. The greater the score, the worse the outcome is.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Depression level at day 7, assessed using the Hospitalized Anxiety and Depression Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>7 days after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of Depression among the family member or person of trust of a patient who received a limitation or discontinuation of treatment 7 days after this announcement, using the Hospitalized Anxiety and Depression Scale, giving two scores (one for anxiety, one for depression) going from 0 to 21. The greater the score, the worse the outcome is.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Anxiety level at day 30, assessed using the Hospitalized Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of Anxiety among the family member or person of trust of a patient who received a limitation or discontinuation of treatment 30 days after this announcement, using the Hospitalized Anxiety and Depression Scale, giving two scores (one for anxiety, one for depression) going from 0 to 21. The greater the score, the worse the outcome is.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Depression level at day 30, assessed using the Hospitalized Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS)</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of Depression among the family member or person of trust of a patient who received a limitation or discontinuation of treatment, 30 days after this announcement. Anxiety will be assessed using the Hospitalized Anxiety and Depression Scale, giving two scores (one for anxiety, one for depression) going from 0 to 21. The greater the score, the worse the outcome is.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of socio-demographic factors</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>In order to determine anxiety and depression risk factors, the individual socio-demographic factors such as recourse to psychological support, consumption of psychoactive substances (caffeine, tobacco, psychotropic drugs, anxiolytics) will be described.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Description of clinical factors</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>In order to determine anxiety and depression risk factors, the factors linked to the patient (COVID infection, death) will be described.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">140</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Post Traumatic Stress Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Anxiety</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Evaluation arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Post traumatic, Anxiety and depression evaluation</intervention_name>
    <description>Family member of person or trust of patient who had a limitation or discontinuation of treatments will be identified and asked to fulfilled a hospitalized anxiety and depression scale and the revised Impact Event scale 7 and 30 days after the limitation or discontinuation of treatments announcement</description>
    <arm_group_label>Evaluation arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age over 18 years old.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person of trust designated in writing or contact person if designated by the family or&#xD;
             primary caregiver or failing that the family member or person of trust of an adult&#xD;
             patient deemed unfit to receive the information (advanced dementia (lower MMS) to 10),&#xD;
             disturbance of consciousness). Only one person per family will be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  having been informed of a LAT decision in the emergency room by telephone during the&#xD;
             pandemic&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Having consented to participate in the study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Affiliated with social security&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Person of trust, family or close friend unable to understand or write in French.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Marion DOUPLAT, MD</last_name>
    <phone>04.78.86.28.54</phone>
    <phone_ext>+ 33</phone_ext>
    <email>marion.douplat@chu-lyon.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Julien BERTHILLER</last_name>
    <phone>04 72 11 80 67</phone>
    <phone_ext>+ 33</phone_ext>
    <email>julien.berthiller@chu-lyon.fr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>HADS</keyword>
  <keyword>IES-R</keyword>
  <keyword>Family</keyword>
  <keyword>Limitation or discontinuation of treatment</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

