<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3814">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04823988</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>10000376</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>000376-M</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04823988</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Emotional, Social, Cognitive and Behavioral Sequalae of the COVID-19 Pandemic.</brief_title>
  <official_title>Emotional, Social, Cognitive and Behavioral Sequalae of the COVID-19 Pandemic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institutes of Health Clinical Center (CC)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Title: Emotional, Social, Cognitive and Behavioral Sequalae of the COVID-19 Pandemic&#xD;
&#xD;
      Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      COVID-19 has caused a high rate of deaths. The steps taken to control its spread have caused&#xD;
      social isolation, changes in lifestyle, economic turmoil, and increased work-related stress.&#xD;
      As a result, there has been a rise in mental and physical health problems. These burdens are&#xD;
      particularly severe for people with a history of mental illness. Researchers want to learn&#xD;
      more about the relationship between stressors related to COVID-19 and self-rated measures of&#xD;
      anxiety and other variables.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective:&#xD;
&#xD;
      To better understand the impact of this stressful time on people s lives and families. Also,&#xD;
      to learn the strategies people have been using to deal with the COVID-19 pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Eligibility:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Adults ages 18 and older.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Design:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This is an online study.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will fill out surveys online. The surveys will ask about their mood, anxiety,&#xD;
      medical history, substance use, and COVID-19 stressors.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will complete 2 online tasks. For the first task, they will tap a computer key&#xD;
      when they see certain images. Then they will answer questions about the task. For the second&#xD;
      task, they will stare at the center of a computer screen. When they see certain images, they&#xD;
      will indicate the location of that image as quickly as possible.&#xD;
&#xD;
      It will take about 2 hours for participants to complete the surveys and tasks. They may be&#xD;
      contacted again if additional data is needed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Some participants may have taken part in other NIH studies. If so, their new data may be&#xD;
      linked to their previously collected data.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Title:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Emotional, Social, Cognitive and Behavioral sequalae of the COVID-19 pandemic&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Description:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The goal of this protocol is to examine individual consequences of the COVID-19 pandemic, in&#xD;
      the transition resolution phase with the arrival and distribution of the vaccine.&#xD;
      Specifically, this protocol will capture the 'after-effects' of the pandemic at all levels of&#xD;
      functioning (cognitive, emotional, social, behavioral), as well as its material impact&#xD;
      (financial, occupational, educational). Particular attention will be directed to (1) the&#xD;
      family structure (impact of the pandemic on adults as care-takers) (2) beliefs about and role&#xD;
      of the introduction of the vaccine, and (3) the changes resulting from the prominent role&#xD;
      that virtual communication has been playing in our society. Both negative and positive&#xD;
      consequences will be probed. These effects will be carefully analyzed in function of age,&#xD;
      gender, SES, race, family structure, psychopathology, and physical health.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This protocol is a follow-up of protocol 20MN112, titled Impact on Anxiety and Motivation of&#xD;
      COVID-19 and Predictors of Individual Responses. Protocol 20MN112 was initiated in the early&#xD;
      days of the pandemic (April 2020) and collects data on individual responses to the active&#xD;
      phase of the pandemic. As we are conducting interim analyses, we have identified a number of&#xD;
      questions to query more thoroughly, such as parenting, role of uncertainty, gender&#xD;
      differences and the cumulative effects of environmental and personal stress. Most&#xD;
      importantly, this ongoing protocol does not cover responses to the oncoming availability of&#xD;
      the vaccine, and the potential 'return to normality.'&#xD;
&#xD;
      The same basic structure as protocol 20MN112 will be used: online questionnaires and&#xD;
      cognitive tasks. (1) Questionnaires: We will use questionnaires to reliably gather&#xD;
      'explanatory' or 'predictive' measures, particularly regarding mental health and belief&#xD;
      systems. To this aim, we will use well-normed and validated instruments (i.e., ASI, BDI, BRS,&#xD;
      , DSM XC with substance questions, Hollingshead, Intolerance of Uncertainty scale, MASQ,&#xD;
      Neuro QoL CFQ, PSS, PROMIS Social Isolation scale, STAI, PSWQ, LSAS, BFI). We will also adapt&#xD;
      questionnaires to fit the specific focus on the COVID pandemic (Parent questionnaire,&#xD;
      psychiatric history form, psychiatric history form, vaccine questionnaire, demographic&#xD;
      questionnaire, COVID clinical mental health history, COVID adult survey, and clinical history&#xD;
      checklist - medical). (2) Cognitive Tasks: We will continue to use a threat-biased attention&#xD;
      task (dot-probe task), a modified version of the motivation finger-tapping task, and a&#xD;
      standard loss aversion task. These tasks will provide objective measures of the impact of the&#xD;
      prolonged effects of the pandemic context on cognitive function. This research will use a&#xD;
      study website to consent, survey participants online, and tasks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The primary objective is to examine the impact of the long-standing threat presented by the&#xD;
      pandemic and its associated societal changes (e.g., social isolation, financial burden) on&#xD;
      cognitive, emotional, social, behavioral. This research will identify risk and resilience&#xD;
      factors among study participants and provide clues for interventions tailored to individual&#xD;
      characteristics (predictive measures).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Endpoints:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The endpoints are mental health, attention biases and reward-related behavioral patterns&#xD;
      associated with COVID-19 stressors in function of pre-existing clinical phenotype (based on&#xD;
      retrospective measurements).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Population:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The sample size will be up to 3000 healthy volunteers and anxiety participants. Participants&#xD;
      will be males and females, 18 years and older. They must be English-speaking. In addition to&#xD;
      the general population, participants to SNFA studies will also be invited to permit focused&#xD;
      analyses of the use of collected pre-pandemic data as predictors of responses to the&#xD;
      pandemic. NIMH individuals will include participants who have completed SFNA/NIMH studies&#xD;
      (protocols 01-M-0185, 02-M-0321, 03-M-0093, 14-M-0114, 17-M-0042, 17-M-0046, 17-M-0181).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Phase:&#xD;
&#xD;
      N/A&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of Sites/Facilities Enrolling Participants:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The protocol is situated at the NIH Clinical Center with no additional supporting sites. The&#xD;
      study itself will be conducted entirely online through a secure study website where consent&#xD;
      and study measures will be completed and repeated as specified.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Description of Study Intervention:&#xD;
&#xD;
      There are no study interventions as this is a descriptive behavioral health survey study,&#xD;
      including questionnaires and computer tasks.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Duration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      We will recruit participants for one year.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participant Duration:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study will take approximately two hours for participants to complete. They may contacted&#xD;
      again if additional data need to be collected. Therefore, participants are expected to be&#xD;
      'active' for the duration of the study, i.e., 1 year.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 19, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">January 27, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">November 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Online self-report measures</measure>
    <time_frame>Study date</time_frame>
    <description>The primary objective is to examine the impact of COVID-19 pandemic and the 'precarious' availability of the vaccine on mental health and cognitive function, in function of a host of factors, including parental situation, history of mental illness, demographic factors, clinical history, and other demographic variables.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Comparison of questionnaire and neuroimaging data with baseline data</measure>
    <time_frame>Study visit</time_frame>
    <description>The secondary objective is to focus on participants who already completed SNFA studies prior to the pandemic, and for whom we have comprehensive screening data, and resting state MRI scans. These pre-COVID data will be used as predictors of responses to the chronic COVID-19 pandemic.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">3000</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy Volunteer</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Adults 18 and over</arm_group_label>
    <description>Adults 18 and over</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Community sample of convenience&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        -  INCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In order to be eligible to participate in this study, an individual must meet all of the&#xD;
        following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. 18 years of age and older.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Able to read and write English.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Able to provide informed consent online using study website.&#xD;
&#xD;
        EXCLUSION CRITERIA:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. There are no exclusion criteria for this study.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Monique Ernst, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Morgan Andrews, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>Not Listed</phone>
    <email>nimhhealthyvolunteer@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Bethesda</city>
        <state>Maryland</state>
        <zip>20892</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 29, 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 30, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 31, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 13, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 13, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Estimate">April 14, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Social Isolation</keyword>
  <keyword>virtual</keyword>
  <keyword>Vaccine</keyword>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>Chronic Covid</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

