<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4730">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04798599</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>TeleDent-COVID19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04798599</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Information and Communication Technologies (ICTS) in Dentistry for SUS</brief_title>
  <official_title>Using Information and Communication Technologies (ICTs) to Solve the Repressed Demand for Primary Dental Care in the SUS Due to the COVID-19 Pandemic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Sao Paulo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Federal University of Paraíba</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Federal University of São Paulo</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Sao Paulo</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      At the time of the COVID-19 pandemic, thousands of children had their dental care interrupted&#xD;
      or postponed, generating a pent-up demand for primary care. In order to minimize the impact&#xD;
      of this outage of face-to-face care, information and communication technologies could be an&#xD;
      alternative and even likely to be envisioned within the Brazilian Unified Health System&#xD;
      (SUS). In this sense, this study sought to show the impact of the use of information and&#xD;
      communication technologies (ICT) in the resolution of the pent-up demand for primary dental&#xD;
      care to children in the SUS, due to the COVID-19 pandemic, proposing the use of&#xD;
      telemonitoring, teleorientation and telescreening to resolve and address demands arising from&#xD;
      this outage in primary elective care. The impact of the use of these strategies will be&#xD;
      measured in terms of problem-solving, reduction of waiting time to resolve complaints and&#xD;
      caregivers' perception about received care. For this, two clinical studies were designed and&#xD;
      a primarily trial-based economic evaluation was planned. Mathematical models will be used to&#xD;
      transpose these results into the reality of the SUS, in view of the State Health Secretariat&#xD;
      of São Paulo and different Brazilian scenarios. Finally, the investigators also aim to study&#xD;
      the possibility of implementing these technologies mentioned in the daily life of the SUS,&#xD;
      even after a pandemic, and to check the possibility of incorporating and costing them, as&#xD;
      well as exploring possible social impact and relationship with possible inequities in health.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Project Objectives:&#xD;
&#xD;
      This proposal has as a general objective to show the impact of the use of information and&#xD;
      communication technologies (ICT) on the resolution of the pent-up demand for primary dental&#xD;
      care to children in the SUS, due to the COVID-19 pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To this do so, the following specific objectives are defined:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. To identify the pent-up demand for the outage of dental care and the benefits and&#xD;
           difficulties, as well as the perception of users, in the implementation of new&#xD;
           strategies of non-face-to-face care based on technology (teleservice), using a primary&#xD;
           care cell unit for children and prospecting, through models, this situation for the&#xD;
           scenario of the Unified Health System (SUS).&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Perform different forms of economic evaluation to measure whether the gains achieved&#xD;
           with the implementation of teleservice (telescreening, teleorientation and&#xD;
           telemonitoring) compensate for the additional costs possibly associated with it, or&#xD;
           whether teleservice modalities are associated with long-term resource savings, taking&#xD;
           into account the implementation sized for the Brazilian public health system.&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Explore how the introduction of these technologies could benefit the SUS in the trans&#xD;
           and post-pandemic period, contribute to the correction of possible inequities in health&#xD;
           care and other social aspects, as well as result in possible differences when different&#xD;
           Brazilian scenarios are explored.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>This protocol refers to a randomized, patient-controlled study on a waiting list, nested to a before-after type study to be conducted in a cell unit, simulating a basic dental health unit. Next, a modelling study was idealized, prospecting the situation found for the reality and integral demand of the Unified Health System.&#xD;
The &quot;before-after&quot; study was designed to measure the positive and negative effects resulting from telecare implementation in primary care for children. The randomised controlled study evaluates the impact of teleservice implementation from the patient´s and parents perception and allows comparison with a reference. For that, children potentially eligible for the study will initially be randomized to one group (intervention vs waiting list). On the waiting list, participants will receive the intervention (standardized telecare) and will be evaluated for outcomes of interest two weeks later.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Supportive Care</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>One researcher, who will not participate in teleconsultations (intervention), will be responsible for the questionnaires before the intervention and will randomize the patients. This same researcher will distribute the patients randomly among the dentists responsible for teleconsultations. Dentists will also be blind as to the allocation of the patient to the groups. Also, to the patients/families, it will be not mentioned which group participants are part of. An external operator will be responsible for collecting information about the outcome (questionnaire after the interventions) will also not know which group the patient was allocated. As only the researcher responsible for randomization will know which group the patient belongs to and coordinate all operational parts of the teleconsultations, investigators can ensure the other operators and participants' blinding.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Family/patient´s perception about the dental care</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks after intervention (or one week of waiting - in the case of the control group)</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluation of the quality of dental care to be measured by the SERVQUAL questionnaire (a multi-dimensional research instrument) - total of 22 items and 5 dimensions, comprising 4 items to capture tangibles, 5 items to capture reliability, 4 items for responsiveness, 4 items for assurance and 5 items to capture empathy.&#xD;
A total of 100 points is allocated among the five dimensions. The participants evaluate the degree to which they perceived the proposed service. To identify participants' perceptions, one item asked, &quot;How do you feel about these service attributes that are already provided?&quot;, which was scored on a 5-point Likert-type scale of &quot;very bad (1)&quot; to &quot;very good (5).&quot;</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Increment in caries experience since the interruption of dental care</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical examination focused using dmft and DMFT indices and comparison to those. An previously recorded in participant´s records, resulting in the difference between the indices between these moments (DMFT+dmft final - DMFT+dmft when treatment was interrupted). An examiner unaware of baseline conditions will assess these indices.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Increment or changes in the needs for dental treatment</measure>
    <time_frame>1 year after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Clinical examination focused in detecting if there is need for dental treatment or not (including untreated caries, need for restoration repair, need of gingival or periodontal treatment, need for extractions for any reason). An examiner unware of baseline conditions will assess such needs.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Demand resolution after intervention</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Interview for checking about the resolution of demands pointed out during the baseline consultation.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Need for reorientation about oral hygiene</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks, 3 months, 6 months, 1 year after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Interview for checking doubts about oral hygiene and checklist of items to be accomplished during oral hygiene demonstrated by child. An external examiner will evaluate all listed items. In case of any one is not checked, the need of reorientation is considered.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Perception of caregivers regarding primary care and dental care.</measure>
    <time_frame>2 weeks after intervention</time_frame>
    <description>Semi-structured interviews, applied with guided questions to try to assess participants' and parents' perception, as well as potential barriers and facilitators associated with dental care during the pandemic period with the caregivers of the children who followed the teleservice. For this, individual interviews will be recorded and transcribed.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">368</enrollment>
  <condition>Dental Caries in Children</condition>
  <condition>Dental Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the intervention group there will be the application of the intervention - use of telemonitoring and teleorientation applied to children in primary care in Dentistry.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Waiting list</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In the control group, children waiting to be booked to the intervention (in implementation in the unit because of the pandemic) will be evaluated for the outcomes. Only after the evaluation, the control group's children will be invited to perform the teleconsultation (proposed intervention).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Telemonitoring and teleorientation</intervention_name>
    <description>Teleservice will be performed through a digital platform (Video for Health&quot; - V4H). The service will consist of: a) recognition of the condition identified in the pandemic period, including updates on medical history, current oral health condition, search for dental care in other units, need for referral, change of hygiene habits, b) realization of diet guidance, hygiene and other necessary habits, made from a situational recognition of such habits, c) targeting the needs presented, in which individualized counselling will be given seeking to meet the demand presented by that family nucleus. A dental form developed on the digital platform Google Forms will serve as a guide for the performance of the service and where the collected data will be formally recorded. The guidelines, although individualized for the needs of each child, will follow a pre-defined and standardized structure and based on the best evidence available in the subject.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Intervention</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Control Group - Waiting list</intervention_name>
    <description>No intervention (at least, until the time frame for outcome assessment)</description>
    <arm_group_label>Waiting list</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Children from 3 to 13 years old who are involved in clinical studies and who already&#xD;
        undergo follow-up from 6 to 60 months in the mobile dental unit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Guardian´s participants) who do not accept to participate in the research and if&#xD;
             participants accept.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Children who do not assent with participation in the research (when already literate).&#xD;
             - For children aged 3 to 6 years, included in the research, the waiver of the need to&#xD;
             fill out the term of free and informed assent was requested, considering that these&#xD;
             children are not literate and would not be able to write, to assent with the&#xD;
             participation. t&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>3 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>13 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mariana M Braga, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>USP</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Mariana M Braga, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>55 11 30917835</phone>
    <email>mmbraga@usp.br</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Karina Haibara</last_name>
    <phone>55 11 30917835</phone>
    <email>karina.natal@usp.br</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>University of São Paulo</name>
      <address>
        <city>São Paulo</city>
        <zip>05508000</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Mariana Minatel Braga, Phd</last_name>
      <phone>992014818</phone>
      <email>mmbraga@usp.br</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Maria Eduarda Franco Viganó, Graduation</last_name>
      <phone>(11)99518-1964</phone>
      <email>maria.vigano@usp.br</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Sao Paulo</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Mariana Minatel Braga</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Child</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>Information Technology</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Dental Caries</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stomatognathic Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

