<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="694">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04824365</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>CSI-COVID-19_007</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04824365</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Sodium Pyruvate Nasal Spray Treatment of COVID-19 and Influenza Infections</brief_title>
  <official_title>Two Week Sub-chronic Double-blinded Placebo Controlled Trial Designed to Determine if Sodium Pyruvate Nasal Spray Will Reduce the Symptoms, Duration and Replication of COVID-19 and Influenza Infections</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Cellular Sciences, inc.</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Missouri State University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Dynamic DNA Labs</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Trinity Health Care</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Cellular Sciences, inc.</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>Yes</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cellular Sciences Inc has submitted over 17 human clinicals (phase I, II, III including&#xD;
      animal safety data) to the FDA for the reduction of respiratory inflammation and inflammatory&#xD;
      cytokines including IL-6 the cause of the cytokine storm in COVID patients. These clinicals&#xD;
      demonstrated a reduction of inflammation in all lung and sinus diseases, in patients with&#xD;
      COPD, Pulmonary fibrosis, CF, asthma, sinusitis , the flu and nasal inflammation and&#xD;
      congestion. Inhaled sodium pyruvate reduces inflammation, congestion and in our phase III&#xD;
      clinical study with Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis patients we demonstrated statistically and&#xD;
      clinical significant increase in FEV-1, SaO2, FVC, FEV-1/FVC ratios (form 52% to 86%) and a&#xD;
      decrease in hypoxemia, and a reduction in coughing. Inhaled sodium pyruvate alleviated the&#xD;
      symptoms associated with COVID-19 patients in Pulmonary Fibrosis, and may be a solution to&#xD;
      the lingering COVID-19 symptoms in patients that had the COVID-19 infection for example long&#xD;
      haulers. In flu and COVID infected mice, nebulized sodium pyruvate decreased morbidity,&#xD;
      weight loss, inflammatory cytokines and decreased viral titers compared to placebo controls.&#xD;
      The study to be done at Missouri State University is titled ( Two week sub-chronic&#xD;
      double-blinded placebo controlled trial designed to determine if sodium pyruvate nasal spray&#xD;
      will reduce the symptoms, duration and replication of COVID-19 and influenza infections)&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Inhibition of Viral Replication, Reduction of the &quot;Cytokine Storm&quot; and reduction of COVID-19&#xD;
      symptoms- Potential Treatment and Preventative for COVID-19 and Flu&#xD;
&#xD;
      In numerous human clinical trials (17, phase I, II, III clinical trials) submitted to the&#xD;
      FDA, with Pulmonary Fibrosis, COPD and Cystic Fibrosis patients, inhaled sodium pyruvate&#xD;
      reduced nasal and lung inflammation and congestion by reducing inflammatory cytokines&#xD;
      including the IL-6 cytokine that causes the so-called cytokine storm with no known adverse&#xD;
      reactions. Cellular Sciences received Orphan Drug Designations for Pulmonary Fibrosis and&#xD;
      Cystic Fibrosis. Mice studies conducted by Dr. Lupfer at Missouri State University&#xD;
      substantiated our finding by testing nebulized sodium pyruvate in flu (influenza A H1N1&#xD;
      virus) infected mice that decreased morbidity, weight loss, proinflammatory cytokines, and&#xD;
      decreased viral titers (virus numbers) compared to the Placebo Control. Additionally, treated&#xD;
      mice consumed more chow during infection indicating improved symptoms (same results reported&#xD;
      in a pilot mice COVID-19 study). There were notable improvements in pro-inflammatory cytokine&#xD;
      production (IL-1β) and lower virus titers (viral numbers) on days 7 post infection in mice&#xD;
      treated with Sodium pyruvate compared to the Placebo Control animals. As pyruvate acts on the&#xD;
      host immune response, metabolic pathways and not directly on the virus, our data demonstrate&#xD;
      that sodium pyruvate is a promising treatment option that is safe, effective, and unlikely to&#xD;
      elicit antiviral resistance. Furthermore, we have preliminary data that suggest it may work&#xD;
      similarly during other respiratory virus infections including COVID19/SARS-CoV-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In a Phase III Placebo Controlled Clinical Trial with Idiopathic Pulmonary Fibrosis Patients,&#xD;
      inhaled sodium pyruvate, a Non-Steroidal Nasal Spray (N115) demonstrated a statistically and&#xD;
      clinically significant increase in FEV-1, SaO2, FVC, FEV-1/FVC ratios (from 52% to 86%), and&#xD;
      a statistically and clinically significant reduction in coughing, hypoxemia and a reduction&#xD;
      in nasal and lung inflammation. Inhaled sodium pyruvate alleviated the symptoms associated&#xD;
      with the COVID-19 infections in Patients with COPD and Pulmonary Fibrosis. Nasal Nitric Oxide&#xD;
      reduces the rate, duration and severity of viral infections in healthy young children and in&#xD;
      healthy adults from the Flu, Rhinovirus and Coronavirus. The literature has reported that&#xD;
      Nitric Oxide is elicited and inhibits viral replication in pigs infected with porcine&#xD;
      respiratory coronavirus. Additionally Nasal Nitric Oxide levels decreases from normal levels&#xD;
      found in healthy adults, in patients with asthma (87%), COPD (73%) CF (44%) and Primary&#xD;
      Ciliary Dyskinesia (7%). The rate of infections increases with decreasing levels of nasal&#xD;
      nitric oxide. Young children, 6-17 years of age, produce (142%) more nitric oxide than&#xD;
      healthy adults, which may explain their resistance to COVID-19. Recently, researchers&#xD;
      announced that a high percentage of COVID-19 infected patients that were hospitalized were&#xD;
      Diabetics or were Pre-Diabetic. The literature has reported that elevated levels of glucose&#xD;
      in patients with diabetes mellitus cause a deficiency in the production of nitric oxide by&#xD;
      blunting nitric oxide synthesis, which may explain their susceptibility to COVID-19. Sodium&#xD;
      pyruvate increases nitric oxide and is safe for use by Patients with Diabetes. The inhalation&#xD;
      of nasal sodium pyruvate increased the synthesis of nasal nitric oxide to normal levels in&#xD;
      patients with low levels of nitric oxide to increase all lung functions and decrease the rate&#xD;
      of infections.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A clinical survey of 367 patients who took a nasal spray similar to EmphyCorp' s N115&#xD;
      formula, over a two-year period demonstrated a statistically significant decrease in the&#xD;
      number, symptoms, and severity of seasonal flu respiratory tract infections. The number of&#xD;
      flu or colds was reduced by 70% in Children and approximately 52% in Pregnant Women, Patients&#xD;
      with Allergic Rhinitis, Diabetes, and Pulmonary Fibrosis. It has been used successfully by&#xD;
      over 2 million patients globally in over 200 hospitals during the past 5 years to treat nasal&#xD;
      and lung inflammation, congestion in Patients with COPD, Allergic Rhinitis, Pulmonary&#xD;
      Fibrosis, sinusitis, the flu and Cystic Fibrosis, with no adverse events reported. It has&#xD;
      been used by Children, Diabetics, and Hypertensives, with efficacy and with no known side&#xD;
      effects. It has even been shown to be safe for use by Pregnant Women, for whom steroids are&#xD;
      contraindicated as they increase the risk of low birth-weight babies.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Proactive treatments with sodium pyruvate are not toxic and could be of benefit to children&#xD;
      that are afflicted by many respiratory viruses and as a potential treatment for COVID long&#xD;
      haulers.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 3, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2/Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>15 patients will be assigned to the placebo and 15 patients assigned to the drug treatment for both COVID19 and influenza group, for a total of 60 patients.</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Triple (Participant, Care Provider, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the ability of inhaled nasal sodium pyruvate to change COVID-19 or influenza viral titers.</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>RT-PCR will be used to assess viral titers from nasal swabs from COVID19 or influenza patients. Swabs will be collected and tested every 2 days for 14 days or until negative.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the ability of inhaled nasal sodium pyruvate to change the symptoms of COVID-19 or influenza.</measure>
    <time_frame>14 days</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the ability of the nasal spray to improve the symptoms from COVID19 or influenza, a patient log will be used. Signs and symptoms to be logged include fever, body ache, headache, chills, coughing/sneezing, sore throat, congestion, trouble breathing and other (patient supplied). Patients will use a Likert scales from 1 to 10 to assess signs and symptoms, except for fever, which will be recorded as temperature in degrees Fahrenheit. Blood pressure and pulse/Ox will be collected every 2 days by a nurse or PA at the time of nasal swab collection.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Influenza</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>treatment of COVID-19 or influenza infected patients with a sodium pyruvate nasal spray</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this arm, patients will be provided with N115 sodium pyruvate nasal spray and instructed to use it 3x daily for 14 days. This group will be compared to the placebo control group to determine if sodium pyruvate reduces the symptoms, duration and replication of COVIV-19 and influenza infections.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo control treatment of COVID-19 or influenza infected patients</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>In this arm, patients will be provided with a saline nasal spray as a placebo control. Patients will use the saline nasal spray 3x daily for 14 days, similar to the sodium pyruvate drug arm. This will serve as a control for the symptoms, duration and replication of COVIV-19 and influenza infections.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Sodium Pyruvate</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will use a sodium pyruvate nasal spray 3x daily for 14 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>treatment of COVID-19 or influenza infected patients with a sodium pyruvate nasal spray</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>N115</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Saline</intervention_name>
    <description>Subjects will use a saline nasal spray 3x daily for 14 days.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Placebo control treatment of COVID-19 or influenza infected patients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Individuals with a confirmed COVID-19/influenza viral infection, as determined by a&#xD;
             qualified laboratory test. A nasal swab or saliva test analyzed by qPCR for COVID19 or&#xD;
             rapid flu test from nasal swab for influenza.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Individuals who agree to abstain from sexual intercourse, or agree to use condoms or&#xD;
             vaginal diaphragms or other devices designed to prevent contraception, during the&#xD;
             entire course of the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Viral infections other than COVID-19 or influenza.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Clinically significant cardiac disease including uncontrolled congestive heart failure&#xD;
             and unstable angina&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Females of child bearing potential age not on adequate contraception or lactating&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subjects receiving systemic corticosteroid treatment within one month of Screening&#xD;
             Visit&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subjects Less than 18 years of age&#xD;
&#xD;
          7. Hospitalization within last 6 months due to acute exacerbation of airway disease&#xD;
&#xD;
          8. Subjects with a clinically significant abnormal chest x-ray within past 12 months&#xD;
&#xD;
          9. Medication changes within one month of study entry&#xD;
&#xD;
         10. Subjects who have participated in another investigation drug treatment study within&#xD;
             the previous month.&#xD;
&#xD;
         11. Subjects with a current history of alcohol or recreational drug abuse.&#xD;
&#xD;
         12. Subjects who have taken dietary supplements containing pyruvate within 24 hours prior&#xD;
             to the screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion of Women and Minorities Every attempt will be made to include all genders, and&#xD;
        minorities that present with an active COVID-19 or flu infection that are not exempted due&#xD;
        to exclusion criteria.&#xD;
&#xD;
        -&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>40 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ronald Amen, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>VP of Regulatory affairs</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Christopher lupfer, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>901 461 9215</phone>
    <email>Christopherlupfer@MissouriState.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Alain Martin, Ph.D.</last_name>
    <phone>908 237 1561</phone>
    <email>dr.martin@erols.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Missouri State University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Springfield</city>
        <state>Missouri</state>
        <zip>65897</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Christopher Lupfer, Ph.D.</last_name>
      <phone>417-836-6887</phone>
      <email>Christopherlupfer@MissouriState.edu</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Alain Martin</last_name>
      <phone>9082371561</phone>
      <email>dr.martin@erols.com</email>
    </contact_backup>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Christopher lupfer, Ph.D.</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://emphycorp.com</url>
    <description>Summary of previous clinical trials for sodium pyruvate</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Reel JM, Lupfer CR. Sodium Pyruvate Ameliorates Influenza A Virus Infection In Vivo. Microbiology Research. 2021; 12: 258-267.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Abusalamah H, Reel JM, Lupfer CR. Pyruvate affects inflammatory responses of macrophages during influenza A virus infection. Virus Res. 2020 Sep;286:198088. doi: 10.1016/j.virusres.2020.198088. Epub 2020 Jul 4.</citation>
    <PMID>32634445</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 26, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 29, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Influenza, Human</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>February 21, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/65/NCT04824365/Prot_SAP_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>February 9, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/65/NCT04824365/ICF_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

