<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1928">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04764981</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>OLFATO001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04764981</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Olfactory Training for Olfactory Dysfunction After Coronavirus Disease - 19 (COVID-19)</brief_title>
  <official_title>Clinical Outcomes of Olfactory Training for Treatment of Olfactory Dysfunction After COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidade do Estado do Pará</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidade do Estado do Pará</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      It is a randomized controlled clinical trial study that aims to follow a sample of&#xD;
      individuals with persistent olfactory dysfunction post-COVID-19. The aim of this study is&#xD;
      assess the clinical outcomes of olfactory training therapy in the treatment of persistent&#xD;
      olfactory dysfunctions after COVID-19. The sample will consist of 350 participants, being 300&#xD;
      individuals with persistent olfactory dysfunction post-COVID-19 and 50 healthy individuals.&#xD;
      Volunteers' will be separated in two experimental groups (1 and 2 ) and a control group. All&#xD;
      participants will be submitted to clinical evaluation that include the Connecticut&#xD;
      Chemosensory Clinical Research Test (CCCRT), an olfactory test to diagnose anosmia and&#xD;
      hyposmia, and two skull Magnetic Resonance imaging (MRI). Only participants of Experimental&#xD;
      group 1 will be submitted to an olfactory training with essences oils. Experimental group 2&#xD;
      will only receive a clinical follow-up after three months and control group will be only&#xD;
      submitted to neurological exam, olfactory test, MRI imaging and test their ability to&#xD;
      discriminate the essence oils used in olfactory training. As a result, is expected a better&#xD;
      understanding of the characteristics of olfactory dysfunction caused by Severe Acute&#xD;
      Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2) virus infection, as well as the effectiveness&#xD;
      and viability of using Olfactory Training as a therapeutic alternative.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2024</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>Randomized controlled clinical trial study, with 2 experimental groups</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Double (Participant, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>Participants of groups will be evaluated and random inserted in one of the experimental groups. The person responsible for reassessment will be blinded for which group the individual reassessed came from.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>To Assess the effectiveness of olfactory training therapy in the treatment of persistent olfactory dysfunctions after COVID-19</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>The individuals of Experimental group 1 will be submitted to a olfactory training with essence oils, the participants will be reassessed with Olfactory test CCCRT monthly and this results will be compared with the reassessment results of the Experimental group 2 (no intervention group). The results of CCCRT of these two groups will be compared with Control group. The CCCRT olfactory test consists of n-butanol smell threshold test and smell identification test. Olfactory function score will be assessed (0: worst score; 7: best score).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To Investigate by means of skull nuclear magnetic resonance (MRI) exams for possible neural correlates of olfactory dysfunctions present in post-COVID-19 patients</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>MRI imaging of olfactory bulb will be assessed in the individuals of this study, for better understanding of possible lesions at neural sites</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>To Measure by means of a standardized olfactory test the olfactory dysfunctions present in post-COVID-19 patients</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>CCCRT will be used to classify individuals as having normosmia, hyposmia or anosmia</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Propose an olfactory training protocol appropriate to the demands of patients with post-COVID-19 olfactory dysfunction and in accordance with the reality of Brazilian public health services</measure>
    <time_frame>4 years</time_frame>
    <description>The olfactory training using essence oils will be tested in this study as a low cost alternative for therapeutics</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>3</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">350</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>SARS-CoV Infection</condition>
  <condition>Olfactory Disorder</condition>
  <condition>Anosmia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental Group 1: Essences Oils</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The individuals of this group are 150 individuals with olfactory disorder related to COVID-19 that will be submitted to clinical exams, olfactory test and MRI imaging, after that, participants will undergo an olfactory training with essences oils. Each participant in this group will receive a kit with four 30 ml bottles, each containing a circular piece of watercolor paper soaked in one of the four essences oils (rose, eucalyptus, lemon and cloves) used in olfactory training, a manual to make the olfactory training at home and a self-assessment diary which should be filled weekly. Each participant of this group will use the training kit for three months, the olfactory training consists of inhaling each of the substances for 30 seconds, with an interval of 30 seconds between them, twice a day, upon waking up and before bed, the participants will be reassessed with CCCRT after each month of training. The results of this group will be compared with the other groups.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental Group 2: Clinical follow-up</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The individuals of this group are 150 individuals with olfactory disorder related to COVID-19. that will be submitted to clinical exams, olfactory test and MRI imaging, after three months they will be reassessed.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The individuals of this group are 50 healthy individuals, without previous COVID-19 infection, that will be submitted to clinical exams, olfactory test, MRI imaging and the participants will be tested for the ability to identification of the essence oils utilized by Experimental group 1.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Essence oils</intervention_name>
    <description>Consists in olfactory training using essence oils</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental Group 1: Essences Oils</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed diagnosis of COVID-19 by Real Time Polymerase chain-reaction for SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
             or serological tests for SARS-CoV-2 antigens.\&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Olfactory dysfunction confirmed by Connecticut Chemosensory Clinical Research Test&#xD;
             (CCCRC-T).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Smokers&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with diagnosed rhinitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals with diagnosed Neurological diseases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals submitted to brain surgery&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Previous historic of hyposmia and/ or anosmia&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Allergy to any of the substances present in the olfactory test kit&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individuals who are undergoing another treatment for olfactory dysfunction&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Unidade de Ensino E Assistência Em Fisioterapia E Terapia Ocupacional</name>
      <address>
        <city>Belém</city>
        <state>PA</state>
        <zip>66095-661</zip>
        <country>Brazil</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Brazil</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 18, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 18, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 18, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universidade do Estado do Pará</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>ALNA CAROLINA MENDES PARANHOS</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Olfaction Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

