<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2452">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04770740</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>KOVIT</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04770740</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Randomized Controlled Clinical Trial to Investigate Effects of Vitamin K2 in COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>KOVIT</acronym>
  <official_title>A Phase 2, Double Blind, Randomized, Placebo-controlled Clinical Trial to Investigate the Safety and Effects of Oral Vitamin K2 Supplementation in COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Canisius-Wilhelmina Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Kappa Bioscience</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Canisius-Wilhelmina Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) is caused by the severe acute respiratory syndrome&#xD;
      coronavirus-2 (SARS-CoV-2). While the majority of people recover after mild symptoms, a&#xD;
      portion of COVID-19 patients develops respiratory failure. Coagulopathy and thromboembolism&#xD;
      are prevalent in severe COVID-19, and these factors are associated with decreased survival.&#xD;
      Coagulation is an intricate balance between clot promoting and dissolving processes in which&#xD;
      vitamin K plays an essential role. Elastin is a major component of dynamic tissues such as&#xD;
      lungs and arteries, and elastin calcification stimulates elastin degradation and vice versa.&#xD;
      The vitamin K-dependent Matrix Gla Protein (MGP) protects elastin from both calcification and&#xD;
      degradation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although technically feasible, direct quantification of blood vitamin K levels is not an&#xD;
      appropriate method to assess overall vitamin K status due to differences in bioavailability&#xD;
      and half-life time between the two naturally occurring vitamin K forms (vitamin K1 and K2).&#xD;
      Measuring inactive levels of vitamin K-dependent proteins in the circulation is the method&#xD;
      recommended by most experts, as it represents the systemic availability of both vitamin K1&#xD;
      and K2. Dp-uc (dephospho uncarboxylated, i.e. inactive) MGP and proteins induced by vitamin K&#xD;
      absence (PIVKA-II) both inversely correlate with vitamin K status and can be used as&#xD;
      surrogate markers of total vitamin K status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, we found a severely reduced vitamin K status (as quantified by dp-ucMGP) in&#xD;
      COVID-19 patients compared to controls. In COVID-19 patients, low vitamin K status was also&#xD;
      associated with poor outcome (defined as the need for invasive ventilation or death),&#xD;
      accelerated elastin degradation (quantified by plasma (iso)desmosine (DES) a byproduct of&#xD;
      elastin degradation). Based on these finding and previous studies, we hypothesize that&#xD;
      improving vitamin K-status by vitamin K supplementation could have favorable effects on&#xD;
      pulmonary damage and coagulopathy in COVID-19.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The outbreak of coronavirus 2019 disease (COVID-19) has a major impact on health care&#xD;
      worldwide. This infectious disease is caused by the severe acute respiratory syndrome&#xD;
      coronavirus (SARS-CoV-2). The majority of individuals who contract COVID-19 have mild&#xD;
      symptoms, but a significant part develops respiratory failure due to severe pneumonia and/or&#xD;
      acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS). The virus may also have extra pulmonary&#xD;
      manifestations, including coagulopathy and venous thromboembolism, associated with decreased&#xD;
      survival. The pathogenesis of this coagulopathy, and the links between pulmonary and&#xD;
      thromboembolic manifestations of COVID-19 are incompletely understood. In KOVIT trial, the&#xD;
      roll of vitamin K in the pathogenesis of these manifestations will be elucidated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vitamin K in coagulation and elastic fiber metabolism&#xD;
&#xD;
      Coagulation is an intricate balance between clot promoting and dissolving processes in which&#xD;
      vitamin K plays an important role. Pro-coagulation factors II, VII, IX and X depend on&#xD;
      vitamin K for carboxylation to fulfill their biological function. Besides this, vitamin K is&#xD;
      also cofactor of anticoagulant protein C and protein S. A significant proportion of protein S&#xD;
      is extrahepatically synthesized in endothelial cells, in contrast to the pro-coagulant&#xD;
      factors and protein C. Protein S plays a local suppressive role against thrombosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Matrix Gla protein (MGP) is also vitamin K-dependent but not involved in intravascular&#xD;
      coagulation. MGP has been generally studied as an inhibitor of vascular mineralization, and&#xD;
      its role in the pulmonary compartment seems to be comparable. Besides preventing soft tissue&#xD;
      calcification, it also protects against elastic fiber degradation. Elastic fibers are&#xD;
      fundamental matrix components in lungs and have high calcium affinity. Degradation and&#xD;
      mineralization of elastic fibers are related processes. Desphospho-uncarboxylated MGP&#xD;
      (dp-ucMGP) i.e. inactive MGP is a robust biomarker of extrahepatic vitamin K status since it&#xD;
      is inversely associated with vitamin K.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Insufficiency of vitamin K may develop within days of poor intake, particularly in&#xD;
      pathological conditions of increased vitamin K utilization. During times of scarcity,&#xD;
      micronutrients are reserved for use in processes that form the greatest threat to short-term&#xD;
      survival. With regard to vitamin K insufficiency, it appears to be preferentially transported&#xD;
      to the liver for the activation (via carboxylation) of procoagulant factors at the expense of&#xD;
      extrahepatic vitamin K-dependent proteins such as MGP and protein S (figure 1).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessment of vitamin K status&#xD;
&#xD;
      In nature, vitamin K is found in food as vitamin K1 (phylloquinone) and vitamin K2&#xD;
      (menaquinones). Measuring circulating levels of these two forms of vitamin K is technically&#xD;
      feasible but the value of such measurements is limited. Quantification of vitamin K-dependent&#xD;
      proteins that have not been carboxylated yet, is a valuable method reflecting the functional&#xD;
      deficit of vitamin K1 and K2. Determination of dp-ucMGP levels as well as the ratio between&#xD;
      uncarboxylated and carboxylated osteocalcin are validated assays of extrahepatic vitamin K&#xD;
      status.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Dp-ucMGP is a biomarker of extrahepatic vitamin K status. High dp-ucMGP reflects low vitamin&#xD;
      K status and vice versa. Although increasing vitamin K consumption decreases the amount of&#xD;
      dp-ucMGP. Circulating dp-ucMGP concentration can best be regarded as a reflection of the&#xD;
      total extrahepatic vitamin K deficit, which refers to the amount of vitamin K that is needed&#xD;
      to carboxylate all the uncarboxylated vitamin K-dependent proteins in the body. Hepatic&#xD;
      vitamin K status is usually quantified by measuring levels of protein induced by vitamin K&#xD;
      absence (PIVKA)-II (i.e. uncarboxylated prothrombin).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Rationale for study treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recently, a reduced vitamin K status was found, as quantified by dp-ucMGP, in patients&#xD;
      suffering from COVID-19 as compared to controls. In these patients, low vitamin K status was&#xD;
      also associated with poor outcome (defined as the need for invasive ventilation or death) and&#xD;
      accelerated elastic fiber degradation (quantified by plasma (iso)desmosine (DES) a byproduct&#xD;
      of elastin degradation). In contrast, hepatic vitamin K status, measured by inactive factor&#xD;
      II (also called protein-induced by vitamin K absence (PIVKA)-II) was unaffected in most&#xD;
      patients (figure 2). Considering the preferential activation of hepatic over extrahepatic&#xD;
      proteins.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In COVID-19, inflammation causes pulmonary elastic fiber damage, which could also lead to an&#xD;
      upregulation of MGP and a draining of extrahepatic vitamin K. The significant correlation&#xD;
      between increased dp-ucMGP levels, and elastic fiber degeneration and poor prognosis supports&#xD;
      the theory that vitamin K insufficiency contributes to pulmonary pathology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Hypothesis&#xD;
&#xD;
      It is hypothesized that improving vitamin K-status by vitamin K supplementation could have&#xD;
      favorable effects on both pulmonary damage and coagulation abnormalities in COVID-19&#xD;
      patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Objective&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of the KOVIT trial is to evaluate the safety of oral vitamin K2 supplementation&#xD;
      in patients suffering from COVID-19 requiring hospital admission.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 22, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 2</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <intervention_model_description>double blind, randomized, placebo-controlled</intervention_model_description>
    <primary_purpose>Other</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Quadruple (Participant, Care Provider, Investigator, Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma desmosine levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 until day 28 or until discharge if this is earlier.</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma desmosine levels before and during vitamin K supplementation in intervention versus control patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Plasma dp-ucMGP levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 until day 28 or until discharge if this is earlier.</time_frame>
    <description>Plasma dp-uc MGP levels before and during vitamin K supplementation within the intervention group and in intervention versus control patients.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Safety</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 until day 28</time_frame>
    <description>Difference between the number of grade 3 and grade 4 adverse events between the intervention and control group during treatment, with special attention for: progression of respiratory insufficiency, thrombotic events, pulmonary embolism or deep venous thrombosis, bleeding, renal insufficiency, cardiac decompensation, liver enzyme abdnormalities and/or liver failure.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Serum PIVKA-II levels</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1 until day 28 or until discharge if this is earlier.</time_frame>
    <description>Serum PIVKA-II levels before and during vitamin K supplementation in intervention versus control patients.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental: Vitamin K2</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with COVID-19 who get our dietary supplement vitamin K2, three tablets of 333mcg a day, for 14 days or until discharge, whichever occurs earlier.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control: Placebo</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Placebo Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>Patients with COVID-19 who get placebo as control, three tablets a day, for 14 days or until discharge, whichever occurs earlier.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Vitamin K2 in the form of Menaquinone-7 (MK-7)</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will take three tablets of vitamin K2 menaquinone-7 (333mcg) per day. Patients taking vitamin K2 MK-7 will receive the total of 999mcg per day from day 1 until day 14 or discharge, whichever occurs earlier. All subjects can be treated with prophylactic or therapeutic heparin-based (heparin or any low-molecular weight heparin) anticoagulants, according to local hospital protocols. Provided by Kappa Bioscience.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Experimental: Vitamin K2</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Dietary Supplement</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Placebo</intervention_name>
    <description>Patients will take three tablets of placebo containing only inactive ingredients per day, from day 1 until day 14 or until discharge, whichever occurs first. The placebo is provided by Kappa Bioscience.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control: Placebo</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  COVID-19 patients who are admitted to the CWZ with COVID-19, with a laboratory&#xD;
             confirmed SARS-CoV-2 infection within the previous 96 hours&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Respiratory failure requiring supplemental oxygen, defined as requiring supplemental&#xD;
             oxygen to sustain an arterial PO2 ≥70mmHg (measured by arterial blood gas) or an&#xD;
             oxygen saturation of ≥94% (measured using a pulse oximeter)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  At least 18 years old&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Able to safely swallow the study medication or possibility of safely administering&#xD;
             this through a nasogastric tube&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of prophylactic heparin or LWMH according to hospital protocols, or use of&#xD;
             therapeutic dosages if there is a medical indication for this&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Informed consent signed by patient&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Use of oral anticoagulation drugs; patients may be included when they have been&#xD;
             switched to LMWH&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients on vitamin K antagonists with a supra-therapeutic anticoagulation at&#xD;
             admission who require vitamin K supplementation to correct this, or were administered&#xD;
             vitamin K for this reason within the preceding 5 days&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients already using vitamin K supplements at admission&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in another intervention study&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Direct admission to an intensive care unit (ICU) for invasive ventilation at&#xD;
             presentation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Confirmed active pulmonary embolism or deep venous thrombosis prior to inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Known allergy to any of the components of the study medication or placebo&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who are hemodialysis dependent at admission&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pregnancy at the time of inclusion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosed malignancy at the time of inclusion&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>A. Dofferhoff, M.D. PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Canisius-Wilhelmina Hospital</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Margot Visser, M.D.</last_name>
    <phone>0243657657</phone>
    <email>m.visser@cwz.nl</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Jona Walk, M.D. PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+3124368200</phone>
    <email>jona.walk@cwz.nl</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Canisius Wilhelmina Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Nijmegen</city>
        <state>Gelderland</state>
        <zip>6532SZ</zip>
        <country>Netherlands</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Margot Visser, M.D.</last_name>
      <phone>+31-24 365 7657</phone>
      <email>m.visser@cwz.nl</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Jona Walk, PhD, M.D.</last_name>
      <phone>+31-24368200</phone>
      <email>jona.walk@cwz.nl</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Netherlands</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.kappabio.com/</url>
    <description>Kappa Bioscience</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Janssen R, Visser MPJ, Dofferhoff ASM, Vermeer C, Janssens W, Walk J. Vitamin K metabolism as the potential missing link between lung damage and thromboembolism in Coronavirus disease 2019. Br J Nutr. 2020 Oct 7:1-8. doi: 10.1017/S0007114520003979. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33023681</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Dofferhoff ASM, Piscaer I, Schurgers LJ, Visser MPJ, van den Ouweland JMW, de Jong PA, Gosens R, Hackeng TM, van Daal H, Lux P, Maassen C, Karssemeijer EGA, Vermeer C, Wouters EFM, Kistemaker LEM, Walk J, Janssen R. Reduced vitamin K status as a potentially modifiable risk factor of severe COVID-19. Clin Infect Dis. 2020 Aug 27. pii: ciaa1258. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciaa1258. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>32852539</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Canisius-Wilhelmina Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Ton Dofferhoff</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Specialist in Internal Medicine and infectious diseases</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Vitamin K</keyword>
  <keyword>Desmosine</keyword>
  <keyword>Elastic fibers</keyword>
  <keyword>Dp-ucMGP</keyword>
  <keyword>PIVKA-II</keyword>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vitamin K</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vitamin K 2</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Vitamin MK 7</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Not sure yet.</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

