<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="5720">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04813068</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>GN20ON632</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04813068</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Lung Cancer Patients' Attitudes to a Second Course of Radiotherapy</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Qualitative Study of Patients' Attitudes to the Risks and Potential Benefits of Potential Toxicities of Radical Re-irradiation for Lung Cancer</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>University of Glasgow</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Beatson Cancer Charity</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Patients with lung cancer are often treated with high dose x-ray treatment (radical&#xD;
      radiotherapy) to control the disease. After one course of radiotherapy, after a period of&#xD;
      time, there is a risk that the cancer can come back in either the same place or nearby in the&#xD;
      lungs. This happens to about 700 patients in the UK every year. There is no strong evidence&#xD;
      to suggest what the best treatment is in this situation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      One possible treatment is a second course of radiotherapy (re-irradiation). Early studies&#xD;
      show that a re-irradiation may cause significant side effects like breathlessness or problems&#xD;
      swallowing, but may control the cancer for a long period of time. We want to do a clinical&#xD;
      trial to investigate if re-irradiation improves cancer control compared to other treatments&#xD;
      to help guide treatment for patients with recurrent disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Before we can go ahead with the trial, we would like to talk to patients who are have&#xD;
      completed radiotherapy to find out what are their feelings about having a second course of&#xD;
      radiotherapy if needed, and how the side effects from the initial course of radiotherapy or&#xD;
      the projected side-effects from the second course would affect that decision.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This information is vitally important to help develop a trial about re-irradiation in lung&#xD;
      cancer as it will demonstrate if patients would accept a second course of radiotherapy, and,&#xD;
      by accounting for patient concerns in the trial design, will make it more likely to recruit&#xD;
      well.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This study will perform telephone interviews with patients five weeks after completing a&#xD;
      course of radical radiotherapy for lung cancer at the Beatson Cancer Centre. We expect to&#xD;
      interview 16-30 patients. This study will run over the course of 1 year. This research is&#xD;
      funded by the Beatson Cancer Charity and The University of Glasgow.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">December 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Feelings and concerns re: second radiotherapy course</measure>
    <time_frame>Dec 2021</time_frame>
    <description>Explore patients' feelings and concerns about having a second course of radiotherapy for recurrent lung cancer. This will be assessed using thematic analysis of the transcripts of semi-structured interviews, and the outcome will be the identification of themes that participants have expressed with regard to a second course of radiotherapy e.g. &quot;side-effects of radiotherapy&quot;, or &quot;cost of another treatment&quot;.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Choice of treatment in recurrent setting</measure>
    <time_frame>Dec 2021</time_frame>
    <description>Identify factors that patients consider when deciding on potential treatments in the setting of locally recurrent lung cancer (including effect of COVID-19 on treatment choice). This will be assessed using thematic analysis of the transcripts of semi-structured interviews, and the outcome will be the identification of themes that participants have expressed with regard to a choosing a treatment in the event of relapse e.g. &quot;worry about chemotherapy side-effects&quot;, or &quot;risk of infection&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Attitude to side effects in context of possible outcomes</measure>
    <time_frame>Dec 2021</time_frame>
    <description>Investigate how patients' acceptance of side effects changes with the different projected outcomes of re-irradiation. This will be assessed using thematic analysis of the transcripts of semi-structured interviews, and the outcome will be the identification of any hierarchy of side-effects that patients would rather not experience e.g. &quot;I can cope with fatigue but I don't want to be breathless&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Toxicity from previous radiotherapy</measure>
    <time_frame>Dec 2021</time_frame>
    <description>Explore the relationship between the toxicities patients experienced during radiotherapy and their attitudes to a second course of radiotherapy. As part of the semi-structured interview, participants will be asked to grade the severity of symptoms on a three point scale (mild/moderate/severe) and then state if they would consider a second course of radiotherapy if needed (yes/no). There will be scope in the semi-structured interview to expand on any topic, and this will undergo thematic analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Attitude to surveillance scans</measure>
    <time_frame>Dec 2021</time_frame>
    <description>Investigate patients' awareness of surveillance imaging after radical treatment and willingness for scans. This will be assessed using thematic analysis of the transcripts of semi-structured interviews, and the outcome will be the identification of themes that participants have expressed with regard to a surveillance e.g. &quot;I'd prefer to have frequent scans to see if there is any change in the tumour&quot;, or &quot;frequent scans make me anxious&quot;.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Lung Cancer</condition>
  <condition>Recurrence</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Interview arm</arm_group_label>
    <description>Group of patients who have agreed to have a qualitative interview on the topic of recurrence of lung cancer</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Semi-structured interview</intervention_name>
    <description>Semi-structured interview to identify attitudes to re-irradiation in lung cancer</description>
    <arm_group_label>Interview arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Adult patients who are having radical radiotherapy for non-small cell lung cancer in the&#xD;
        Beatson West of Scotland Cancer Centre, who are consent to a semi-structured interview&#xD;
        about their experience of radiotherapy and their feelings on re-treatment if necessary&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 18 years old or above&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pathological or radiological diagnosis of non-small cell lung cancer&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Undergoing radical radiotherapy to the thorax using the following fractionations (55&#xD;
             Gray in 20 fractions, 54 Gray in 36 fractions or any Stereotactic Ablative Body&#xD;
             Radiotherapy (SABR) fractionation that delivers a biological effective dose of greater&#xD;
             than 100Gy10) as part of their primary lung cancer treatment at time of study&#xD;
             enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients receiving concurrent and/or adjuvant systemic therapies are permitted&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Radiotherapy is delivered in the Beatson West of Scotland Cancer Centre&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed, written informed consent&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to complete study processes&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Not fluent in English&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Stephen Harrow, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>NHS Greater Glasgow and Clyde</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Robert Rulach, MBChB</last_name>
    <phone>0141 301 7000</phone>
    <phone_ext>15505</phone_ext>
    <email>robert.rulach@ggc.scot.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Stephen Harrow, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>0141 301 7000</phone>
    <email>stephen.harrow@ggc.scot.nhs.uk</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 22, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 22, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 22, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Lung Neoplasms</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Recurrence</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Transcribed and anonymised interviews will be available on the University of Glasgow research repository after the trial has completed</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>February 18, 2021</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/68/NCT04813068/Prot_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

