<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3295">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04798066</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>HBPCOV01</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04798066</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Intermediate Size Expanded Access Protocol Evaluating HB-adMSC's for the Treatment of Post-COVID-19 Syndrome</brief_title>
  <acronym>LongHaulers</acronym>
  <official_title>Intermediate Size Patient Population Expanded Access Protocol to Evaluate the Safety and Efficacy of HB-adMSCs for the Treatment of Patients With Post COVID-19 Syndrome</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hope Biosciences Stem Cell Research Foundation</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hope Biosciences</source>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is an Intermediate- Size Patient Population Expanded Access Protocol to evaluate the&#xD;
      safety and efficacy of HB-adMSCs for the treatment of patients with Post-COVID-19 Syndrome.&#xD;
      The investigational product will be an add-on treatment to the standard of care.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The dose to use for this Intermediate- Size Patient Population Expanded Access Protocol is&#xD;
      200 million HB-adMSCs, administered through intravenous infusion only, with a treatment&#xD;
      duration of 14 weeks, infusion rate 4-5ml/min and total volume of 250 ml Sodium chloride&#xD;
      0.9%. A total of 5 administrations and a dosing interval of two weeks for the first two&#xD;
      HB-adMSCs administrations and one month after that.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>No longer available</overall_status>
  <study_type>Expanded Access</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <expanded_access_info>
    <expanded_access_type_intermediate>Yes</expanded_access_type_intermediate>
  </expanded_access_info>
  <condition>Post COVID-19 Syndrome</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Autologous HB-adMSC's</intervention_name>
    <description>Autologous adipose derived mesenchymal stem cells</description>
    <other_name>MSC's</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Subject is between the ages of 18-65 years at the time of signing the informed consent&#xD;
             form.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Subject has had a positive SARS-COV-02 test (preferably PCR) within the last 12 months&#xD;
             or has been diagnosed presumptive positive and has been treated for COVID-19 within&#xD;
             the last 12 months.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Subject have not fully recovered from COVID-19 in weeks or months despite a negative&#xD;
             Sars-COV-02 test and has been diagnosed with Post COVID-19 syndrome.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Subject is experiencing 2 or more symptoms for over 12 weeks either continually or&#xD;
             intermittently with relapses not experienced pre-illness, that interferes with normal&#xD;
             daily activities. Symptoms must be new symptoms, or dramatic worsening of symptoms&#xD;
             i.e., subject didn't have symptoms, and had not sought medical treatment for the&#xD;
             symptoms prior to COVID-19, or the symptoms are dramatically worse (in severity and&#xD;
             frequency).&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Extreme fatigue - feeling overtired with low energy and a strong desire to sleep.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Shortness of breath - (dyspnea) a feeling of being winded, difficulty in&#xD;
                  breathing, or a hunger for air.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Cough - hacking, or dry barking sound lingering dry or wet.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Brain fog -a diminished mental capacity marked by the inability to concentrate or&#xD;
                  to think or reason clearly that interferes with daily activities.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Headache - Sharp or dull reoccurring or intermittent that were not present&#xD;
                  pre-illness&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Body aches - muscle soreness or generalized achiness throughout the body.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Joint pain - pain in the joints due to inflammation not experienced before&#xD;
                  illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Chest pain - (angina) feeling pressure, fullness, or tightness in your chest&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Sleep issues - any sleep disturbances in sleep quality that makes sleep see&#xD;
                  inadequate or unrefreshing like insomnia or hypersomnia.&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Loss of Taste/Smell - Diminished sense of taste or smell.&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. Subject must have previously banked their cells at Hope Biosciences, LLC.&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Subject and sexual partner if woman of childbearing potential must use a least 1&#xD;
             highly effective form of birth control* throughout the study and for 6 months after&#xD;
             the last dose of the investigational product. (*Highly methods of birth control&#xD;
             include, true sexual abstinence, bilateral tubal ligation, vasectomy, intrauterine.&#xD;
             device and hormonal contraceptive methods.)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1 -Subject is unable to provide informed consent or to comply with study requirements.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. Subject has currently been diagnosed with active COVID-19 disease. 3. Subjects unwilling&#xD;
        to agree to the use of acceptable methods of contraception throughout the study and for 6&#xD;
        months after the last dose of the investigational product. 4. Pregnant or Breast-feeding&#xD;
        women. 5. Subject has known alcoholic addiction or dependency, uses alcohol daily, or has&#xD;
        current substance use or abuse. 6. Subject has any active malignancy, including evidence of&#xD;
        cutaneous basal, squamous cell carcinoma, or melanoma. 7. Subject has 1 or more significant&#xD;
        concurrent medical conditions (verified by medical records), including the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Poorly controlled diabetes mellitus (PCDM) defined as history of deficient standard of&#xD;
             care treatment and/or pre-prandial glucose &gt;130mg/dl during screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical History of Chronic kidney disease (CKD) diagnosis and/or screening results of&#xD;
             eGFR &lt; 59mL/min/1.73m2.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Presence of New York Heart Association (NYHA) Class III/IV heart failure during&#xD;
             screening visit. (Appendices E) (48)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Any medical history of myocardial infarction in any of the different types, such as&#xD;
             ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) or non-ST-elevated myocardial infarction&#xD;
             (NSTEMI), coronary spasm, or unstable angina.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical history of uncontrolled high blood pressure defined deficient standard of care&#xD;
             treatment and/or blood pressure &gt; 180/120 mm/Hg during screening visit.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Medical history of inherited thrombophilias, recent major general surgery, lower&#xD;
             extremity paralysis due to spinal cord injury, fracture of the pelvis, hips, femur,&#xD;
             cancer of the lung, brain, lymphoma, gynecologic system (ovary or uterus), or&#xD;
             gastrointestinal tract (like pancreas or stomach). 8. Subject has received any stem&#xD;
             cell treatment within 12 months before first dose of investigational product. 9.&#xD;
             Subject has laboratory abnormalities during screening, including the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  White blood cell count &lt; 3000/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Platelet count &lt; 125,000mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absolute neutrophil count &lt; 1500/mm3&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Alanine aminotransferase (ALT) or aspartate aminotransferase (AST) &gt; upper limit of&#xD;
             normal (ULN) x 1.5&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Subject has any other laboratory abnormality, which, in the opinion of the&#xD;
             investigator poses a safety risk or will prevent the subject for completing the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
             10. Subject is unlikely to complete the study or adhere to the study procedures.&#xD;
&#xD;
             11. Subject has a preexisting lung condition such as Chronic obstructive pulmonary&#xD;
             disease (COPD). 12. Subjects with HIV, Hepatitis B and Hepatitis C. 13. Subject has a&#xD;
             previously diagnosed psychiatric condition which in the opinion of the investigator&#xD;
             may affect self-assessments.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hope Biosciences Stem Cell Research Foundation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sugar Land</city>
        <state>Texas</state>
        <zip>77478</zip>
        <country>United States</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United States</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://hopebio.org</url>
    <description>Hope Biosciences LLC</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>http://hopebio.org</url>
    <description>Hope Biosciences Stem Cell Research Foundation</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 11, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 26, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Long Haul COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>Long Haulers</keyword>
  <keyword>Stem Cells</keyword>
  <keyword>Autologous MSCs</keyword>
  <keyword>MSCs</keyword>
  <keyword>Mesenchymal Stem Cells</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Syndrome</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

