<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2433">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04769258</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IGIBD001</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04769258</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Effectiveness and Safety of COVID-19 Vaccine in Patients With IBD Treated With Immunomodulatory or Biological Drugs (ESCAPE-IBD)</brief_title>
  <acronym>ESCAPE-IBD</acronym>
  <official_title>Effectiveness and Safety of COVID-19 Vaccine in Patients With Inflammatory Bowel Disease Treated With Immunomodulatory or Biological Drugs</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Italian Group for the study of Inflammatory Bowel Disease (IG-IBD)</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Italian Group for the study of Inflammatory Bowel Disease (IG-IBD)</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The COVID-19 pandemic has led to initial concerns for patients with Inflammatory Bowel&#xD;
      Disease treated with immunosuppressive drugs, as they could be theoretically exposed to a&#xD;
      higher risk of SARS-CoV-2 infection and/or severe forms of COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although initial studies have not shown an increased risk of developing SARS-CoV-2 disease&#xD;
      related to immunosuppressive therapy, robust data are not yet available to allow for risk&#xD;
      stratification. In this regard, the availability of vaccines represents a cornerstone in the&#xD;
      management of the pandemic. Unfortunately, patients on immunosuppressive drugs have largely&#xD;
      been excluded from the trials of COVID-19 vaccines, creating potential concerns regarding the&#xD;
      validity of their efficacy for IBD patients treated with immunosuppressive agents.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This is a 12-month, prospective, multicentre, case-control, observational study comparing&#xD;
      effectiveness and safety of COVID-19 vaccine in patients with IBD treated with&#xD;
      immunomodulatory drugs (cases) compared with those not treated with the aforementioned drugs&#xD;
      (controls). The study should be regarded as observational because the participants will&#xD;
      receive the intervention (Covid-19 Vaccine) as part of routine medical care (the&#xD;
      administration will be performed outside the study and according to the times and modalities&#xD;
      established by the Italian National Vaccination for the whole Italian population aged 18 and&#xD;
      over). Then, we aim to assess the effect of this intervention in two predefined groups of&#xD;
      individuals (cases and controls). All consecutive patients admitted at each IG-IBD centre&#xD;
      that agree to participate in this study could be screened for inclusion. In case of patient's&#xD;
      refusal to COVID-19 vaccination, this will be recorded in order to estimate the rate of&#xD;
      adherence to the vaccination. Similarly, patients willing to vaccinate but unable to&#xD;
      participate in the study due to logistic problems (for example; long distance from the IBD&#xD;
      centre) will be recorded.&#xD;
&#xD;
      After enrollment, each patient will be visited at baseline; the interval between basal visit&#xD;
      and the subsequent vaccine shall not exceed 10 days. The vaccine will be administered to the&#xD;
      patients according to the times and modalities established by the Italian National&#xD;
      Vaccination Plan. After the last dose of the vaccine, each patient will enter a 12 month&#xD;
      follow-up period. An additional follow-up period will be admitted, as required by clinicians,&#xD;
      in order to further evaluate ongoing adverse events.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At baseline, all enrolled patients will undergo a detailed assessment including:&#xD;
      demographics, smoking status, body mass index, co-morbidities (presence of diabetes, arterial&#xD;
      hypertension, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, heart disease, and so on),&#xD;
      stratification of the disease according to the Montreal classification, activity of the&#xD;
      disease (assessed with Harvey-Bradshaw Index for CD, and Partial Mayo Score for UC), current&#xD;
      medications, laboratory parameters (haemoglobin, white blood cells, C-reactive protein,&#xD;
      faecal calprotectin). Furthermore, all enrolled patients will be tested for the quantitative&#xD;
      detection of IgM and IgG antibodies against SARS-CoV-2. In case of IgM positivity, patients&#xD;
      will be invited to perform a nasopharyngeal swab for the detection of SARS-CoV-2 RNA. The&#xD;
      safety of the vaccine will be assessed by considering the incidence of reported adverse&#xD;
      events, which will be reported by the patients during the 10 days following the&#xD;
      administration of the vaccine (single assessment in case of single-dose vaccine, double&#xD;
      assessment in case of double-dose vaccines, i.e. one evaluation for each dose). After 2 and&#xD;
      12 months from the last dose of the vaccination, the quantitative detection of IgM/IgG&#xD;
      antibodies against SARS-CoV-2 will be repeated. The dosage of antibodies will be centrally&#xD;
      performed at IEO in Milan. In addition, a proactive surveillance will be performed at 3,6,&#xD;
      and 12 months - preferably combined with pre-scheduled direct visits, or alternatively via&#xD;
      remote contacts - to detect new or suspected diagnosis of COVID-19. In case of active&#xD;
      symptoms suspected for COVID-19 without an established diagnosis, patients will be invited to&#xD;
      perform a nasopharyngeal swab for the detection of SARS-CoV-2 RNA. The proactive surveillance&#xD;
      will also involve the occurrence of adverse events to the vaccine and the assessment of&#xD;
      disease activity to detect flare-ups of IBD (see timeline).&#xD;
&#xD;
      All data will be collected anonymously in a specifically arranged eCRF form inside the IG-IBD&#xD;
      registry.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 1, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 1, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>12 Months</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Quantitative serum titer of IgM and IgG against SARS-CoV-2</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months from the vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>To evaluate the quantitative serum titer of IgM and IgG against SARS-CoV-2 after 2 and 12 months from the vaccination in patients with IBD treated with conventional immunosuppressants, biologics, or small molecule drugs (cases) compared with IBD patients not treated with the aforementioned drugs (i.e. off-therapy, or treated with mesalamine only - controls).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of COVID-19 occurrence</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months from the vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the rate of COVID-19 occurrence over a temporal end-point of one year from the last dose of the vaccination</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of adherence to the vaccination</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months from the vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the rate of adherence to the vaccination by identifying the patients not willing to be vaccinated during screening</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of adverse events of the different vaccines</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months from the vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the rate of adverse events of the different vaccines</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Rate of IBD flare-ups</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months from the vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the rate of IBD flare-ups occurring within 3 months from the last dose of vaccine to those occurring thereafter</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Predictors of effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccine</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months from the vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>To assess the predictors of effectiveness of COVID-19 vaccine at baseline.in terms of quantitative serum titer of IgM and IgG against SARS-CoV-2 after 2 and 12 months from the vaccination (primary objective) and of the rate of COVID-19 occurrence over a temporal end-point of one year from the last dose of the vaccination (one of the secondary objectives).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences of effectiveness between patients</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months from the vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>To detect differences of effectiveness between patients treated with different immunomodulators.in terms of quantitative serum titer of IgM and IgG against SARS-CoV-2 after 2 and 12 months from the vaccination (primary objective) and of the rate of COVID-19 occurrence over a temporal end-point of one year from the last dose of the vaccination (one of the secondary objectives).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Differences of effectiveness between the several vaccines</measure>
    <time_frame>12 months from the vaccination</time_frame>
    <description>To detect differences of effectiveness between the several vaccines that will be available.in terms of quantitative serum titer of IgM and IgG against SARS-CoV-2 after 2 and 12 months from the vaccination (primary objective) and of the rate of COVID-19 occurrence over a temporal end-point of one year from the last dose of the vaccination (one of the secondary objectives).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">1380</enrollment>
  <condition>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with IBD treated with immunomodulatory drugs</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with IBD not treated with the immunomodulatory drugs</arm_group_label>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Biological</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Pfizer Comirnaty vaccine</intervention_name>
    <description>COVID 19 vaccines administered to the patients according to the times and modalities established by the Italian National Vaccination Plan. Further vaccines will be evaluated if and when they are available in Italy during the study period.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with IBD not treated with the immunomodulatory drugs</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Patients with IBD treated with immunomodulatory drugs</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Moderna (Moderna vaccine, mRNA-1273)</other_name>
    <other_name>Astrazeneca (Oxford-Astrazeneca, ChAdOx1)</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        690 patients with IBD treated with immunomodulatory drugs (cases) and 690 patients with IBD&#xD;
        not treated withimmunomodulatory drugs (controls)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients of either sex, without racial restriction, aged 18 years or older, willing to&#xD;
             receive the COVID-19 vaccine&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  An established diagnosis of Crohn's disease or Ulcerative Colitis or unclassified&#xD;
             colitis&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current treatment with conventional immunosuppressants (steroids, azathioprine,&#xD;
             6-mercaptopurine, methotrexate), biologics (infliximab, adalimumab, golimumab,&#xD;
             vedolizumab, ustekinumab), or small molecule drugs (tofacitinib): will be included as&#xD;
             cases&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Currently off-therapy or treated with mesalamine only: will be included as controls&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capability to express a written informed consent for COVID-19 vaccination&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Capability to express a written informed consent for the study&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Primary immunodeficiencies and human immunodeficiency virus infection&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Vaccination against SARS-CoV-2 already performed before enrolment&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Contraindications to COVID-19 vaccine or intolerance to its components&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Documented history of previous occurrence of COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Documented history of previous occurrence of asymptomatic SARS-CoV2 infection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Ambrogio Orlando, Director</last_name>
    <phone>+390916802022</phone>
    <email>ambrogiorlando@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Fabio Macaluso, Doctor</last_name>
    <phone>+390916802022</phone>
    <email>fsmacaluso@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 4, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 23, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 24, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 23, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 23, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 24, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Intestinal Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Inflammatory Bowel Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

