<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3020">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04786249</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DELOCOVID</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04786249</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Impact of Rapid Screening for COVID-19 in Delocalized Biology in the Emergency Department</brief_title>
  <acronym>DELOCOVID</acronym>
  <official_title>Impact of Rapid Screening for COVID-19 in Delocalized Biology in the Emergency Department</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19), caused by SARS-CoV-2, first appeared in China, and then&#xD;
      spread around the world. In December 2019, a group of patients with pneumonia of unknown&#xD;
      origin were infected after exposure to the market in Wuhan, Hubei province, China. Very&#xD;
      quickly, a new coronavirus was isolated from a sample of a patient's lower respiratory tract&#xD;
      and the entire virus genome was sequenced. This new coronavirus, named Severe Acute&#xD;
      Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) for its genetic homology with SARS-CoV-2, has&#xD;
      shown worldwide expansion. Thus, on January 30, 2020, the World Health Organization (WHO)&#xD;
      announced the COVID-19 epidemic as a threat to public health at the international level,&#xD;
      then, in March 2020, the global situation degenerated into a pandemic. . Johns Hopkins&#xD;
      University has reported more than 7,600,000 cases of infections and more than 427,000 deaths&#xD;
      as of June 13, 2020. Due to the rapid progression of the COVID-19 pandemic and the limited&#xD;
      capacity of molecular laboratory tests, the concept of delocalized molecular tests appears to&#xD;
      be relevant. Indeed, the urgent need to increase testing for COVID-19 has been clearly&#xD;
      identified as an essential part of the strategy to combat the coronavirus worldwide. In fact,&#xD;
      COVID-19 represents a major public health problem currently causing a rapidly increasing&#xD;
      number of infections and significant morbidity and mortality worldwide. As of July 1, 2020,&#xD;
      more than 10 million people worldwide have been infected with SARS-CoV-2. As of December 20,&#xD;
      2020, this tally is 76,624,363 cases of contamination and 1,690,658 deaths following Johns&#xD;
      Hopkins University&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Early detection with a sensitive technique of COVID-19 is essential to ensure rapid and&#xD;
      appropriate patient management, to contain the epidemic and to better understand the global&#xD;
      epidemiology of the virus. This detection will intensify in the coming months due to the&#xD;
      start of the school year and university as well as the economic recovery. Until now,&#xD;
      laboratory diagnostics have relied primarily on the amplification and detection of viral gene&#xD;
      sequences in upper respiratory tract samples performed in a centralized laboratory. A new&#xD;
      test (Abbott ID NowTM COVID-19) is available on the market. This test is the first in France&#xD;
      to be able to be carried out in a delocalized medical biology examination (DMBE) and makes it&#xD;
      possible to return a result in less than 15 min directly in the clinical department. The&#xD;
      speed of this technique is based on the use of isothermal gene amplification. The&#xD;
      investigators will be the first to evaluate it in France in delocalized biology.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The improvement in diagnostic technique, concomitant with the development of knowledge on the&#xD;
      pathophysiology and specific therapies, has been accompanied by better therapeutic management&#xD;
      of patients with Covid19. To date, dexamethasone represents the first class of drugs proven&#xD;
      to be effective in reducing mortality from COVID-19 in patients with severe disease.&#xD;
      Anticoagulant treatment at a prophylactic dose in hospitalized patients or at risk for the&#xD;
      severe form, and at a curative dose for severe forms is also the subject of strong&#xD;
      recommendations due to the high incidence of venous and arterial thromboembolic events in&#xD;
      these patients. It is also recommended that the use of broad-spectrum antibiotics be reserved&#xD;
      for patients with radiological abnormalities compatible with bacterial superinfection and /&#xD;
      or requiring oxygen therapy greater than or equal to 6 liters / min.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In France, systematic screening for SARS-CoV-2 infection in the emergency room before&#xD;
      hospitalization, an operating room, or transfer to another establishment. At GhPSJ, the&#xD;
      reference RT-PCR technique Simplexa ™ COVID-19 Direct assay has been used routinely since&#xD;
      July 2020 by the microbiology laboratory. It allows a result rendering in a minimum delay of&#xD;
      50 minutes. Since September 7, 2020, the prescription of an RT-PCR is systematically&#xD;
      associated with a dedicated computerized questionnaire on the DxCare® software completed by&#xD;
      the emergency physician. It collects the reason for prescribing RT-PCR: &quot;diagnostic&#xD;
      suspicion&quot;, &quot;bed management&quot;, &quot;preoperative screening&quot;, or &quot;screening for transfer to another&#xD;
      establishment&quot;; the patient's lifestyle; the symptomatic or asymptomatic nature and the&#xD;
      duration of the symptoms. Since October 22, 2020, the DMBE with the Test ID NowTM COVID-19&#xD;
      has been installed and implemented in the Emergency Department. It is used by the trained and&#xD;
      authorized Emergency Nursing team for any patient having a prescription for RT-PCR Sars-CoV-2&#xD;
      by the emergency physician.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators wish to verify the hypothesis that obtaining the rapid diagnosis of&#xD;
      Sars-CoV-2 infection by DMBE in the emergency room (Test ID NowTM COVID-19) makes it possible&#xD;
      to optimize the organizational and medical management of emergency room patients having a&#xD;
      Sars-CoV-2 RT-PCR test. In the literature, there is no study available evaluating the impact&#xD;
      of a rapid examination in delocalized biology on the medical management of patients in an&#xD;
      emergency department.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 24, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 26, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the impact of a short delay in delivering results in delocalized biology on the emergency medical care time, in comparison with the reference method by RT-PCR at the central laboratory of microbiology</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Time of medical care in the emergency department corresponding to the time between the first medical contact (time stamp of the medical observation traced in DxCare®) and the patient's discharge from the Emergency Department (time stamp of the stay in DxCare®)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the impact of the rapid result in DMBE in comparison with the reference method on the final orientation of the patient</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Number of returns home and the number of hospitalizations in conventional services and intensive care.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the impact of the rapid result in DMBE in comparison with the reference method on the bed management</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Number of admissions in single and double rooms</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the impact of the rapid result in DMBE in comparison with the reference method on the number of additional examinations carried out and their deadline</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Number of blood tests, ECG, chest X-ray, chest CT scan without injection, pulmonary CT angiography</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the impact of the rapid result in DMBE in comparison with the reference method on the prescriptions and the timeframe for the implementation of specific therapies against Covid-19 in hospitalized patients</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Introduction of corticosteroid therapy and anticoagulation</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the impact of the rapid result in DMBE in comparison with the reference method on the prescription of antibiotic treatments</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Number of antibiotic treatments</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Compare the primary endpoint for two subgroups of patients according to their treatment schedule</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Number of patients who had a PCR prescription by the day medical team between 8:31 a.m. and 6:30 p.m. and those who had a PCR prescription by the on-call medical team between 6:31 p.m. and 8:30 a.m.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the level of satisfaction and the feelings of the medical and paramedical teams of the Emergency Department regarding the DMBE Test ID Now ™ COVID-19 and its impact</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Staff questionnaire (satisfied or not satisfied)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">2400</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients presenting to the emergency unit of the GhPSJ and for whom a PCR examination is&#xD;
        prescribed by the emergency doctor in charge of the patient during the two periods of 7&#xD;
        weeks:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Period 1 (weeks 37 to 43 of the year 2020): RT PCR SARS-CoV-2 was carried out in the&#xD;
             microbiology laboratory&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Period 2 (44 to 50 of the year 2020): diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection with the ID&#xD;
             Now ™ technique in emergencies in DMBE with respect for the standards and&#xD;
             recommendations of delocalized biology.&#xD;
&#xD;
        The number of patients included will be 1200 per period.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient aged ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient presenting to the emergency unit of the GhPSJ and for whom a PCR examination&#xD;
             is prescribed by the emergency doctor in charge of the patient&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  French-speaking patient&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient under guardianship or curatorship&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient deprived of liberty&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient under legal protection&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patient objecting to the use of their data for this research.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Jean-Claude NGUYEN</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Jean-Claude NGUYEN</last_name>
    <phone>01 44 12 33 33</phone>
    <phone_ext>+33</phone_ext>
    <email>jcnguyen@ghpsj.fr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint-Joseph</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <state>Ile De France</state>
        <zip>75014</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 5, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 16, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Rapid test</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Emergencies</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

