<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1414">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04836754</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Covid-19</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04836754</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>The Effect of Covid-19 on Breast Milk Microbiome and Its Bioactive Components</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effect of Covid-19 on Breast Milk Microbiome and Its Bioactive Components</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Aysu Yıldız Karaahmet</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>The Scientific and Technological Research Council of Turkey</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Halic University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus disease (Covid-19) is a new public health crisis threatening humanity caused by&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2. Although it originated in China's Hubei province in late 2019, it has spread to&#xD;
      many countries around the world. Although Covid-19 first caused infection by affecting the&#xD;
      lung, current data showed that the gastrointestinal tract was also affected by detecting&#xD;
      viral RNA in Covid-19-infected human intestinal epithelial cells and feces. The association&#xD;
      has been confirmed by showing that patients hospitalized with COVID-19 have significant&#xD;
      changes in intestinal bacterioma. These changes have been characterized by a significant&#xD;
      reduction in gut microbiome (BM) diversity associated with gastrointestinal complaints of the&#xD;
      acute phase of infection (e.g. abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea), depletion of&#xD;
      beneficial bacterial symbionts, and enrichment of opportunistic pathogens (e.g.&#xD;
      Streptococcus, Rothia, Actinomyces). In particular, recent studies have evidence that&#xD;
      patients with Covid-19 are more prone to a dysbiosis profile of the gut microbiota, infected&#xD;
      individuals present irregular gut microbiota, and even dysbiosis (disruption of microbiota&#xD;
      balance) in the gut microbiota.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first case reports reported in China suggested that there was no virus found in amniotic&#xD;
      fluid, umbilical cord blood, throat swabs of the newborn, placenta, vaginal fluid, and breast&#xD;
      milk samples infected with Covid-19. The latest data indicate that there is no vertical&#xD;
      transmission to the fetus, and so far, no viruses have been found in the cord blood of&#xD;
      newborns born from Covid-19 positive pregnant women, nasal sampling and amniotic fluid and&#xD;
      placentas of pregnant women. However, the effect of intestinal microbial structure affected&#xD;
      by Covid-19 on breast milk microbiota and the effect of a dysbiosis to occur on infant health&#xD;
      or the effect of the healing properties of breast milk on Covid-19 are still not clearly&#xD;
      known. Our views are that intestinal microbial colonization originating from the&#xD;
      gastrointestinal system affected by Covid-19 will affect breast milk microbial colonization.&#xD;
      However, there is no study on this subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For this purpose, our aim in this study was to determine the breast milk microbiome and&#xD;
      biologically active proteins (secretory immunoglobulin A (sIgA), lysozyme, lactoferrin,&#xD;
      osteoprotegerin (OPG), leptin, adiponectin and β-endorphin (b-) levels of mothers who had&#xD;
      Covid-19 with healthy mothers. will be compared.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Coronavirus disease (Covid-19) is a new public health crisis threatening humanity caused by&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2. Although it originated in China's Hubei province in late 2019, it has spread to&#xD;
      many countries around the world (Wang et al., 2020). In patients with Covid-19, severe cases&#xD;
      of respiratory, hepatic, gastrointestinal and neurological complications and a complex&#xD;
      clinical picture that eventually turns into death are observed (Guo et al., 2020; Li et al.,&#xD;
      2020). The underlying pathophysiological mechanisms are complex and multifactorial, and have&#xD;
      been summarized as a hyper-response of the immune system that causes an inflammatory /&#xD;
      cytokine storm (Li et al., 2020).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Although Covid-19 caused infection by first affecting the lung, current data showed that the&#xD;
      gastrointestinal system was also affected by detecting viral RNA in human intestinal&#xD;
      epithelial cells and feces infected with Covid-19 (Cheng et al., 2002; Wu et al., 2020). This&#xD;
      is thought to be caused by the relationship between the gut microbiota and the lung axis.&#xD;
      Studies have demonstrated that Bacteroidetes and Firmicutes bacteria, which are dominant in&#xD;
      intestinal colonization, are also dominant in the lung (Bacteroidetes, Firmicutes and&#xD;
      Proteobacteria) (Zhang et al., 2020). In short, while intestinal microbiota causes lung&#xD;
      diseases, respiratory tract virus infections also cause confusion in the intestinal&#xD;
      microbiota. In fact, many studies have shown that respiratory infections are associated with&#xD;
      a change in the composition of the gut microbiota (Groves et al., 2020). The high-throughput&#xD;
      16S rRNA amplicon sequence and shotgun metagenomic sequence analyzes demonstrated that&#xD;
      hospitalized COVID-19 patients had significant changes in the intestinal bacterioma, and the&#xD;
      relationship was confirmed. These changes have been characterized by a significant reduction&#xD;
      in gut microbiome (BM) diversity associated with gastrointestinal complaints of the acute&#xD;
      phase of infection (e.g. abdominal pain, nausea, vomiting, diarrhea), depletion of beneficial&#xD;
      bacterial symbionts, and enrichment of opportunistic pathogens (e.g. Streptococcus, Rothia,&#xD;
      Actinomyces) (Gu et al., 2020; Zuo et al., 2020). In particular, recent studies have evidence&#xD;
      that patients with Covid-19 are more prone to dysbiosis profile of the gut microbiota,&#xD;
      infected individuals present irregular gut microbiota and even dysbiosis (disruption of&#xD;
      microbiota balance) in the gut microbiota (Gu et al., 2020; Zuo et al., 2020 ).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The intestinal flora plays a protective role in many metabolic and immune functions of the&#xD;
      host, i.e. against pathogenic colonization of the virus, including training and strengthening&#xD;
      the immune system to fight infections (Fernandes et al., 2019). Looking at the composition of&#xD;
      the gut flora, it is highly dynamic from birth and is shaped by different environmental&#xD;
      factors (e.g. diet, breast milk pre- / probiotics, drugs) resulting in various microbial-host&#xD;
      functions (Koppel, Maini Rekdal, Balskus, 2017; Weiss, Hennet, 2017) . Human gastrointestinal&#xD;
      tract (GIS), 2000 'classified into 12 different phyla, the most common (&gt; 90%) Proteobacteria&#xD;
      (Gram-negative), Firmicutes (Gram-positive), Actinobacteria (Gram-positive) and Bacteroidetes&#xD;
      (Gram-negative) phyla. It is believed that human intestinal viroma, consisting of both&#xD;
      prokaryotic and eukaryotic viruses, shares important information with all microbial&#xD;
      components and can affect overall human health by shaping the structure and function of the&#xD;
      intestinal community (Cani , 2018; Garmaeva et al., 2019).&#xD;
&#xD;
      Breast milk is the bioactive component that most affects the formation of neonatal microbial&#xD;
      colonization in the postnatal period and provides us with information about human future&#xD;
      health. Breast milk is not only the best nutritional source for babies, but it is also known&#xD;
      to contain immune components such as secretory antibodies, immune cells, antimicrobial&#xD;
      proteins (such as lactoferrin and lysozyme), cytokines, and human milk oligosaccharide.&#xD;
      Before the 2000s, breast milk was thought to be sterile, and the presence of bacteria&#xD;
      indicated contamination or infection. However, several researchers have shown that breast&#xD;
      milk has been colonized with bacteria since pregnancy and contains commensal bacteria in&#xD;
      particular. In a study, it was found that Proteobacteria (Gram-negative), Firmicutes&#xD;
      (Gram-positive), Actinobacteria (Gram-positive) and Bacteroidetes (Gram-negative) phyla,&#xD;
      which are dominant in maternal intestinal colonization, are among the breast milk microbes&#xD;
      Firmicutes, Proteobacteria Bacteroidetes and Actinobacteria. It has been proved that breast&#xD;
      milk originates from the mother's gastrointestinal system in this case (Ojo et al., 2018). In&#xD;
      addition, the same study showed that there were bacteria sharing the same strains in the&#xD;
      mother's intestine, the baby's intestine and breast milk, and the mother's commensal bacteria&#xD;
      had vertical transmission to the infant's intestine through breast milk.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Human coronaviruses were defined as enveloped, positive-sensitive, single-stranded RNA&#xD;
      viruses, first described in 1965 (Tyrrell and Bynoe, 1965). There are seven identified&#xD;
      strains known to infect humans. Four of the strains (alphacoronaviruses 229E, NL63, OC43, and&#xD;
      betacoronavirus HKU1) are ubiquitous in humans and cause the common cold. There are questions&#xD;
      about the effect of human coronaviruses on pregnant, maternal and infant health and the&#xD;
      transmission status is not clear. Pregnancy alters a woman's immune system and makes them&#xD;
      more susceptible to infections. However, there is currently no evidence that pregnant women&#xD;
      are more likely to be affected by COVID 19 or serious illness as a result, compared to the&#xD;
      general population. Although the mechanism is unclear, there is limited evidence that one of&#xD;
      the four strains (229E) mentioned above can be transmitted vertically from mothers to infants&#xD;
      (Gagneur et al., 2008). The presence of this virus (229E) in neonatal gastric samples&#xD;
      suggests that a possible mechanism for infection is through breast milk, but this study did&#xD;
      not specifically evaluate breast milk (Gagneur et al., 2008).&#xD;
&#xD;
      The first case reports reported in China suggested that there was no virus in amniotic fluid,&#xD;
      umbilical cord blood, throat swabs of the newborn, placenta, vaginal fluid, and breast milk&#xD;
      samples infected with Covid-19 (Johns et al, 2013). The latest data indicate that there is no&#xD;
      vertical transmission to the fetus, and so far, no viruses have been found in the cord blood&#xD;
      of newborns born from Covid-19 positive pregnant women, nasal sampling and amniotic fluid and&#xD;
      placentas of pregnant women. However, the effect of intestinal microbial structure affected&#xD;
      by Covid-19 on breast milk microbiota and the effect of a dysbiosis to occur on infant health&#xD;
      or the effect of the healing properties of breast milk on Covid-19 are still not clearly&#xD;
      known. Our views are that intestinal microbial colonization originating from the&#xD;
      gastrointestinal system affected by Covid-19 will affect breast milk microbial colonization.&#xD;
      However, there is no study on this subject.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Breast milk is a golden nutrient that provides critical nutrients and bioactive compounds&#xD;
      that support growth and immune development during infancy. Variation in milk components and&#xD;
      bioactive compounds as a result of demographic and genetic factors, the mother's lifestyle&#xD;
      and exposure has both positive and negative effects on infant health (Abrahamsson et al.,&#xD;
      2009; de Andres et al., 2018; Johns et al. , 2013). It has been reported that babies who are&#xD;
      breastfed have a dynamic gut microbiome and the incidence of some diseases has decreased&#xD;
      (Abrahamsson et al., 2009; de Andres et al., 2018). In addition to macro and micronutrients&#xD;
      and bioactive compounds, breast milk contains many types of bacteria. Lactoferrin is one of&#xD;
      the important bioactive components in breast milk. The lactoferrin in breast milk can support&#xD;
      a local intestinal environment, such as microbiota that strengthens the innate defenses of&#xD;
      newborns. Lactoferrin promotes the growth of favorable gut microbiota and the proliferation&#xD;
      of enterocytes through direct anti-inflammatory and immunomodulatory effects.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The action of lactoferrin on cell receptors prevents viral damage, surface accumulation and&#xD;
      cell entry. In this way, it protects and strengthens mucosal immunity and intestinal&#xD;
      epithelial barrier. It is believed that breast milk, particularly lactoferrin, exhibits&#xD;
      potential antiviral effects. The challenge is how effective they are in preventing viral&#xD;
      infections such as coronaviruses (de Andres et al., 2018).&#xD;
&#xD;
      We believe early breastfeeding provides vital prevention during viral outbreaks due to the&#xD;
      high value of colostrum and breast milk and the specific role of lactoferrin, but more&#xD;
      clinical evidence is needed. These effects and mechanisms have not been tested on Covid-19,&#xD;
      but we can consider this approach as they affect other coronaviruses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, breast milk components containing approximately 109 bacteria are known to affect&#xD;
      the baby's own microbiome and immune system (Ruiz et al., 2019). However, contrary to what is&#xD;
      known, breast milk microbiota and its influencing factors are only recently being discovered&#xD;
      and understood (McGuire &amp; McGuire, 2017; Moossavi et al., 2019; Williams et al., 2017). In&#xD;
      addition, while exploring the effects of certain components in breast milk on the nursing&#xD;
      baby, we tend to ignore the dynamic state and effect of other components that could greatly&#xD;
      affect the results. While it was known that the microbiome, which we cannot see with the&#xD;
      naked eye, could affect individuals, it was not thought that our world would change that much&#xD;
      with a single virus, Covid-19. While the microbiome we often ignore because it is invisible&#xD;
      to us reminds us of a world that has profound effects on our health and well-being, how does&#xD;
      Covid-19 affect this world and breast milk? For this purpose, our aim in this study was to&#xD;
      determine the breast milk microbiome and biologically active proteins (secretory&#xD;
      immunoglobulin A (sIgA), lysozyme, lactoferrin, osteoprotegerin (OPG), leptin, adiponectin&#xD;
      and β-endorphin (b-) levels of mothers who had Covid-19 with healthy mothers. will be&#xD;
      compared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of 20 mothers (10 mothers) and healthy (10 mothers) who had Covid-19 in the last&#xD;
      month of pregnancy between April 2021 and June 2021 will be included in the study and the&#xD;
      mothers will be given an appointment on the 15th day and will start with taking breast milk&#xD;
      samples and 16sRNA microbiota. Analyzing the microbiota content of breast milk and the levels&#xD;
      of biologically active proteins (secretory immunoglobulin A (sIgA), lysozyme, lactoferrin,&#xD;
      osteoprotegerin (OPG), leptin, adiponectin and β-endorphin (b)) in breast milk content will&#xD;
      be evaluated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Our hypothesis in this study is that breast milk microbiota will differ in variety and&#xD;
      composition in mothers who have had Covid-19. In this direction, as a result of the research;&#xD;
      Conducting microbial analysis to evaluate the content of microbiota and bioactive components&#xD;
      by taking the milk of mothers who have had Covid-19 during pregnancy,&#xD;
&#xD;
      - In line with the results obtained, it is planned to give correct advice and guidance in&#xD;
      accordance with an urgent problem.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 1, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational [Patient Registry]</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <target_duration>1 Day</target_duration>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>data analysis:maternal and infant health</measure>
    <time_frame>postpartum 15th day</time_frame>
    <description>General Healthy Status</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Microbiological Analysis:human milk</measure>
    <time_frame>postpartum 15th day</time_frame>
    <description>16sRNA analysis</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">30</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Human Milk</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Case group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Pregnant women with Covid-19</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control groups</arm_group_label>
    <description>Pregnant women who do not have Covid-19</description>
  </arm_group>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        The sample of the study: The population of the study will be 20 mothers who are&#xD;
        hospitalized in the obstetrics clinic of the SBU Istanbul Sultangazi Haseki Training and&#xD;
        Research Hospital for emergency delivery, who had Covid-19 during pregnancy (10 mothers)&#xD;
        and healthy (10 mothers). Power analysis to determine the size, G-Power 3.1.9.2. program&#xD;
        (Zuo et al., 2020). According to this calculation, a total of 20 mothers, a minimum of 10&#xD;
        mothers in each group, will be included in the sample, with a 95% confidence interval,&#xD;
        alpha 0.05 and 80% power, with a 20% improvement difference between the two groups.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The cognitive level of the mother is sufficient to understand and answer the&#xD;
             questions,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Having a single pregnancy,&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Mother's ability to read, write and understand Turkish&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The time of delivery is in the range of 37 &lt;GH &lt;42 weeks&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Not having a chronic disease of the mother (Diabetes, hypertension,&#xD;
                  hypothyroidism etc.) Vaginal delivery&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  The mother's not using antibiotic derivative drugs during pregnancy&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Getting 10 points below the Beck Depression Scale&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absence of prematurity, Introuterine Growth Retardation (IUGR) or genetic disease&#xD;
                  in the newborn&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Birth weight in the range of 2500-4000 gr&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absence of a gastrointestinal disease in the newborn&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Feeding more than 50% of the baby with breast milk&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  Absence of Premature Membrane Rupture (PROM) for more than 24 hours at birth&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Expressing breast milk or having problems with the breast,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The mother's use of probiotics before randomization and during pregnancy,&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The inclusion of sampled mothers in other clinical studies at the same time.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>Female</gender>
    <gender_based>Yes</gender_based>
    <gender_description>mothers on the first day after birth</gender_description>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>35 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Aysu Yıldız Karaahmet, Phd.Student</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Halic University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gülümser Dolgun, Profesor</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Istanbul University-Cerrahpasa</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Ceren Ozkul Kocak, Asist prof</last_name>
    <role>Study Director</role>
    <affiliation>Hacettepe University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Aysu Y Yıldız Karaahmet, PhD Student</last_name>
    <phone>05414679620</phone>
    <email>aysuyildiz@halic.edu.tr</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gülümser Dolgun, Professor</last_name>
    <phone>05414679620</phone>
    <email>gdolgun@istanbul.edu.tr</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Haseki Training and Research Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sultangazi</city>
        <state>Istanbul</state>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Aysu Yıldız Karaahmet, phd student</last_name>
      <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Gülümser Dolgun, prof</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
    <investigator>
      <last_name>Ceren Ozkul koçak, Asist prof</last_name>
      <role>Sub-Investigator</role>
    </investigator>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 7, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 7, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 7, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 7, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor-Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Halic University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Aysu Yıldız Karaahmet</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PhD student</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>covid-19</keyword>
  <keyword>human milk</keyword>
  <keyword>microbiota</keyword>
  <keyword>microbiome</keyword>
  <keyword>bioactive ingredient</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

