<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3142">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04836052</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MRC-04-20-1120</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04836052</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Omega-3 Oil Use in COVID-19 Patients in Qatar</brief_title>
  <acronym>Omega3</acronym>
  <official_title>Omega-3 Oil Use in COVID-19 Patients in Qatar: a Randomized Controlled Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Hamad Medical Corporation</agency>
      <agency_class>Industry</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Hamad Medical Corporation</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      COVID-19 infection has been widely spread since December 2019 and causing many comorbidities&#xD;
      and fatalities. The most common clinical presentation of COVID-19 patients admitted to ICUs&#xD;
      is respiratory failure , hypoxia and acute lung injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
      While new therapies and vaccines are urgently being investigated, they may take an inordinate&#xD;
      time to get to right people. Omega-3-oil has been shown to have less proinflammatory&#xD;
      mediators that may have immunomodulating, anti-inflammatory and antiviral effect. Two main&#xD;
      fatty acids in omega-3-oil including eicosapentaenoic acid and docosahexaenoic acid have&#xD;
      shown benefit in patients with ARDS as well.&#xD;
&#xD;
      So, the investigators proposed a randomized controlled study to evaluate the effectiveness of&#xD;
      omega-3-oil supplementation 2 gm PO/NGT/OGT twice daily for 28 days or till discharge or till&#xD;
      death in COVID-19 critically ill patients admitted to ICU who require oxygen support.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The outbreak of Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) due to a novel&#xD;
      coronavirus (COVID-19) has emerged from Wuhan, China in late December 2019 and spread rapidly&#xD;
      worldwide. Until July 16, 2020, there has been more than 13 million confirmed cases worldwide&#xD;
      and ~580,000 deaths attributed to the disease. With the fast evolution of this worldwide&#xD;
      public-health emergency, the general public has demanded the urgent investigation of&#xD;
      potentially beneficial drugs that may improve the outcome of those affected by SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      infection. While new therapies and vaccines are urgently being investigated, they may take an&#xD;
      inordinate time, or never be identified. In the world today, there is only one drug approved&#xD;
      by the FDA for COVID-19 (Remdesivir), while the investigation of several other re-purposed&#xD;
      drugs is potentially suggested for SARS-CoV-2 treatment. Many trials are taking place around&#xD;
      the world, including some utilizing potentially dangerous drugs with considerable side&#xD;
      effects and enormous costs. However, the clinical effectiveness and safety of all&#xD;
      pharmacologic therapies so far have not been fully proven.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The preliminary findings about this disease indicates that patients with cardiovascular risk&#xD;
      factors including diabetes, obesity and other pre-existing cardiovascular diseases have worse&#xD;
      outcomes. Additionally, severe respiratory infection and hypoxia associate with severe&#xD;
      COVID-19 might trigger many pathological pathways which leads to cardiovascular sequelae. In&#xD;
      a cohort of 416 hospitalized patients with COVID-19, myocardial injury defined by an elevated&#xD;
      high sensitivity troponin I level was associated with in-hospital mortality. Another study of&#xD;
      187 hospitalized patients with COVID-19 showed a similar association. Interestingly, the&#xD;
      highest mortality rates were observed among patients with pre-existing cardiovascular&#xD;
      disease. Importantly, none of the published experiences from anywhere in the world has&#xD;
      explored omega-3 oil and its known protective cardiovascular benefits.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Omega-3 fatty acids are found in food such as fish and flaxseed as well as in dietary&#xD;
      supplements labeled omega-3-oil.The beneficiary role of Omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids&#xD;
      (PUFA), namely eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA) and docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) from fish, other&#xD;
      marine sources, and supplements, have been shown to be anti-inflammatory through several&#xD;
      cellular mechanisms including their incorporation into cellular membranes and resulting&#xD;
      altered synthesis of eicosanoids. There is the potential that arachidonic acid (AA,)&#xD;
      eicosapentaenoic acid (EPA) and docosahexaenoic acid (DHA), and other dietary unsaturated&#xD;
      fatty acids can inactivate enveloped viruses. It is thought that these fatty acids and others&#xD;
      cause leakages or lysis of the viral envelopes by disrupting the membrane integrity, amongst&#xD;
      other potential mechanisms. Indeed, the supplementation of EPA and DHA raises the level of&#xD;
      these fatty acids in the phospholipids of cells involved in inflammation in a time and&#xD;
      dose-dependent fashion at the expense of AA4. Li and colleagues reviewed 89 systematic&#xD;
      reviews and meta-analyses investigating fish intake and all-cause mortality, concluding that&#xD;
      fish intake at 2-4 servings per week is associated with the largest risk reduction.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In animal models despite these potential positive effects, there is conflicting evidence in&#xD;
      relation to fish or fish oil consumption for some viral infections. In influenza models, fish&#xD;
      oil-fed mice demonstrated impaired resistance to influenza infection due to their&#xD;
      immunomodulatory and anti-inflammatory properties, which negatively dampened the immune&#xD;
      response of the mice against the infection. In another mouse model, fish oil intake delayed&#xD;
      influenza virus clearance and impaired the immune response in the lungs of mice by disrupting&#xD;
      interferon-γ and immunoglobulin A. A further study indicated that it may be due to the&#xD;
      impairment of virus-specific T lymphocyte cytotoxicity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Despite the potential benefit, there are few human studies with omega 3 and immune and&#xD;
      inflammatory response. The recent proposed benefit for omeg-3-oil is unique, EPA and DHA&#xD;
      which are main fatty acids in omega-3-oils may act as substrates for the synthesis of&#xD;
      specialized pro-resolving lipid mediators such as maresins, resolvins, and protectins, of&#xD;
      which protectins may reduce the replication of influenza and potentially affect the&#xD;
      inflammatory manifestations of respiratory viral diseases.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Notably, an in vitro model of human cells (Huh-7 and VeroE6) infected with a human&#xD;
      coronavirus (HCoV-229E) demonstrated that several bioactive lipids downstream of&#xD;
      phospholipase A2 (PLA2) activation were upregulated by the host cells. It is postulated that&#xD;
      coronaviruses modulate the host lipid profile to optimize and maintain a specific homeostasis&#xD;
      for viral replication. However, exogenous supplementation of AA and linoleic acid suppressed&#xD;
      viral replication by interfering with the optimal host lipid conditions for viral&#xD;
      replication. Notably, exogenous supplementation of AA and linoleic acid was also conserved&#xD;
      when human cells were infected with MERS. However, exogenous supplementation of AA and&#xD;
      linoleic acid suppressed viral replication by interfering with the optimal host lipid&#xD;
      conditions for viral replication. Notably, exogenous supplementation of AA and linoleic acid&#xD;
      was also conserved when human cells were infected with MERS. EPA, DHA, and AA also inhibited&#xD;
      the replication of enterovirus A71 and coxsackievirus A16.While it is suggested that the oral&#xD;
      or intravenous administration of various bioactive lipids could potentially reduce the&#xD;
      severity and/or enhance the recovery of those infected with COVID-19, a dietary prophylactic&#xD;
      approach or a dietary strategy for recovering patients is also worth considering. Further&#xD;
      research is certainly required, as increasing AA via the diet might seem counterintuitive, as&#xD;
      it is mainly proinflammatory.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Other clinical research about several lung infections, found the administration of PUFA can&#xD;
      improve the outcome of the patient in acute pneumonia. Recent study reported that the dietary&#xD;
      supplementation of ω-3 PUFA can exert an overall beneficial effect against acute pneumonia&#xD;
      through the upregulation of the host's specific and nonspecific immune defenses.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Inflammation resolution is strongly dependent on lipid mediators, the specialized&#xD;
      pro-resolution mediators (SPMs). As mentioned above, omega-3 polyunsaturated fatty acids (n-3&#xD;
      PUFAs) are precursors of very potent SPMs, including resolvins, protectins and maresins. In&#xD;
      addition, they are associated with a less aggressive inflammatory initiation, after competing&#xD;
      with omega-6 fatty acids for eicosanoid synthesis. Therefore, it makes sense to consider the&#xD;
      use of n-3 PUFAs for clinical management of COVID-19 patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Recent clinical studies In ARDS patients, the enteral use of n-3 PUFAs has been associated to&#xD;
      oxygenation improvement, reduced duration of mechanic ventilation as well as shorter ICU&#xD;
      length of stay. In another study, critically ill patients receiving parenteral nutrition&#xD;
      therapy enriched with fish oil lipid emulsion (rich in n-3 PUFAs EPA and DHA) were reported&#xD;
      to have decreased infection and sepsis risk (40% to 56%, respectively) and a reduction of&#xD;
      length of hospital and ICU stay by about two day.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As eluded previously, 2 cohort studies from China indicate that a significant proportion of&#xD;
      hospitalized patients with COVID-19 developed some degree of myocardial injury. Coronary&#xD;
      atherosclerotic plaques are more prone to rupture in response to an exacerbated inflammatory&#xD;
      response during SARS-CoV-2. The use of n-3 FA (4-6 g/d) for improving atherosclerotic&#xD;
      cardiovascular disease risk in patients with hypertriglyceridemia is supported by a 25%&#xD;
      reduction in major adverse cardiovascular events in REDUCE-IT.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Furthermore, several drugs will increase triglyceride concentrations in patients with&#xD;
      underlying high triglycerides. The effects of n-3 FA on drug-induced HTG have received&#xD;
      relatively little attention, but n-3 FAs have uniformly been reported to lower triglycerides&#xD;
      when used with interferon-α, antipsychotics, l-asparaginase, oral estrogens, protease&#xD;
      inhibitors, retinoic acid, and sirolimus. In contrast with COVID-19 there is scarce of&#xD;
      information published till now about role of n-3 FAs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Collectively, these findings suggest that omega-3 fatty acids have properties that could&#xD;
      improve oxygenation and outcome of COVID-19 patients. The utilization of omega-3-oil as safe,&#xD;
      available and inexpensive therapy could be a promising therapeutic approach against&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2. Moreover, recent analysis of 8 studies showed that consumption of omega 3 oil up&#xD;
      to 10 gm per day is safe in ICU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      However, due to lack of sufficient clinical data supporting either the beneficial or harmful&#xD;
      effects of omega-3 oil use in patients with COVID-19, the optimal strategy for the management&#xD;
      of in COVID-19 is uncertain and remains to be elucidated - putting together all the known&#xD;
      properties of omega 3 and what is known about the COVID-19, the investigators hypothesize&#xD;
      that omega 3 could have a significant beneficial impact on the clinical outcome of infected&#xD;
      patients. The aim of this study is to investigate in-hospital use of omega-3 oil and&#xD;
      mechanical ventilator days, improvement in oxygenation, need for ventilator in non-ventilated&#xD;
      patients, ICU- length of stay, hospital related length of stay, thrombosis, all-cause&#xD;
      morbidity and mortality in COVID-19 patients in a in randomized prospective controlled trial.&#xD;
&#xD;
      There is no study or evidence on Omega 3 and COVID-19 infection and respiratory failure. The&#xD;
      investigators propose a randomized controlled study to minimize the risk of bias and&#xD;
      confounding factors.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">December 24, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 24, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 24, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 3</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>mechanical ventilator free days</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>28 minus (days patient spent on ventilator if successfully liberated from ventilator)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in oxygenation</measure>
    <time_frame>days 1, 3, 7</time_frame>
    <description>PaO2/FiO2</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital Mortality</measure>
    <time_frame>28 days</time_frame>
    <description>death during 28 days</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">372</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>omega-3-oil arm</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients admitted to ICU in HMC on any kind of oxygen support will get omega-3-oil 2 gm PO/NGT/OGT twice daily for 28 days or till ICU discharge or till death .</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>standard of care arm ( no omega -3-oil )</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>patients admitted to ICU in HMC on any kind of oxygen support will get ( standard of care= No Omega-3-oil ) but their labs will be monitored</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Omega 3 fatty acid</intervention_name>
    <description>omega-3-oil 2 gm twice daily PO/NGT/OGT for 28 days or ICU discharge or death.</description>
    <arm_group_label>omega-3-oil arm</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. adult ICU patients ≥18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. confirmed COVID-19 infection&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. on-Oxygen support (mechanical ventilation, face masks, nasal cannula, etc.)&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. Previous history of omega-3-oil with discontinuation of at least 1 month prior to&#xD;
             admission&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. soya bean oil allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. fish allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. peanut allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. fish oil allergy&#xD;
&#xD;
          5. pregnant women&#xD;
&#xD;
          6. Continuous use of Omega-3-oil till admission&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Sandro Rizoli, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>+97444396157</phone>
    <email>srizoli@hamad.qa</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>AHMED ABDELBARI, Msc</last_name>
    <phone>+974-55810575</phone>
    <email>aabdelbari@hamad.qa</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Hamad Medical Corporation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Doha</city>
        <state>DC</state>
        <zip>3050</zip>
        <country>Qatar</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Sandro Rizoli, phD</last_name>
      <phone>+974-44396157</phone>
      <email>srizoli@hamad.qa</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>AHMED ABDELBARI, Msc</last_name>
      <phone>+974-55810575</phone>
      <email>aabdelbari@hamad.qa</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Qatar</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 14, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 6, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

