<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2167">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04665960</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>NMCSpecialtyH</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04665960</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Infection Control for Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2</brief_title>
  <acronym>IC-COVID-19</acronym>
  <official_title>Expert Statements on Infection Control in Intensive Care Unit for Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome Coronavirus 2</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>NMC Specialty Hospital</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>NMC Specialty Hospital</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The investigators aim to develop expert consensus statements on infection control management&#xD;
      of severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2) in intensive care units&#xD;
      (ICU).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The COVID-19 pandemic has resulted in a considerable change in the infection control&#xD;
      protocols in the hospitals, especially ICU. The ICU management of these patients requires&#xD;
      robust infection control measures in order to prevent cross-transmission of SARS-CoV-2 (to&#xD;
      healthcare workers (HCWs) and other patients) and hospital acquired bacterial or fungal&#xD;
      infections. The understanding of epidemiological characteristics of SARS-CoV-2 and&#xD;
      pathophysiology of coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) along with evidence on transmission of&#xD;
      SARS-COV-2 in controlled healthcare-setting is still evolving. The mode of transmission of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 is airborne, through droplets or fomites. Respiratory interventions performed in&#xD;
      these patients in ICU, such as non-invasive ventilation, high flow nasal oxygen or tracheal&#xD;
      intubation are considered to be aerosol generating procedures and may lead to airborne&#xD;
      transmission of SARS-CoV-2. In the absence of the robust evidence, there are no specific&#xD;
      recommendations available on infection control of SARS-CoV-2 in ICU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The objective of this study is to achieve consensus statements on the infection control&#xD;
      management of SARS-CoV-2 in ICU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The whole process of this study will be done in the form of three-four rounds of Google&#xD;
      Forms-based Delphi surveys. The survey questionnaire, will be prepared by the investigators&#xD;
      after systematic search of available literature and concern areas in the infection control of&#xD;
      SARS-CoV-2 in ICU. The objective is to achieve consensus statements on the infection control&#xD;
      management of SARS-CoV-2 in ICU.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The survey questionnaire is divided into five sections: 1.Design and engineering&#xD;
      2.Health-care workers and visitors 3. Personal protective equipment 4. Patient and procedures&#xD;
      5. Disinfection and sterilisation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The majority of these questionnaire statements are to be rated on Likert scale and others&#xD;
      have multiple choices. The participating experts comments and feedback will be collected&#xD;
      through comment section after each question in round one. All the subsequent surveys will be&#xD;
      iterative and the experts can give their opinion in each round using either open text or&#xD;
      directly to steering group of investigators.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 29, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 25, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Consensus using participating experts opinions.</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days</time_frame>
    <description>For statements with responses on an ordinal 7-point Likert scale, 'agreement' is defined as a score of 5-7, 'neutral' by a score of 4 and 'disagreement' by a score of 1-3. Consensus is defined as achieved when &gt;70% of the experts voted for a given option in Likert scale statement. Median and interquartile range (IQR) were used to describe the central tendency and dispersion of responses. For multiple-choice questions (MCQs), consensus is defined as achieved if &gt;80% of the experts voted for a particular option.&#xD;
Stability in the responses will be assessed from round two onwards. Stability will be assessed between the two concluding rounds for each statement, using the non-parametric chi square (χ2) test. p &lt; 0·05 is considered as a significant variation or unstable.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">40</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>SARS-CoV Infection</condition>
  <condition>SARS Pneumonia</condition>
  <condition>Coronavirus Infection</condition>
  <condition>Infection</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        40 global experts in infectious disease, infection control, sepsis, respiratory failure or&#xD;
        public health and involved in the management of COVD-19 will be invited to participate in&#xD;
        study through e-mail with final expected participation of 35-40 experts.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion criteria for participants Health care professionals involved in the management of&#xD;
        COVID-19 patients with publications and expertise in infectious disease, infection control,&#xD;
        sepsis, respiratory failure or public health.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Those who do not accept the invitation or not meeting any of the inclusion criteria.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>25 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sheila Myatra, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Tata Memorial Hospital, Mumbai, India</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>NMC Specialty Hospital</name>
      <address>
        <city>Dubai</city>
        <zip>7832</zip>
        <country>United Arab Emirates</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>United Arab Emirates</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/hcp/infection-control-recommendations.html</url>
    <description>Center for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). Interim Infection Prevention and Control Recommendations for Healthcare Personnel During the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Pandemic. Updated November 4, 2020.</description>
  </link>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.who.int/westernpacific/emergencies/covid-19/technical-guidance/infection-prevention-control</url>
    <description>World Health Organisation (WHO). Infection prevention and control guidance - (COVID-19). Updated September 11, 2020.</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Odor PM, Neun M, Bampoe S, Clark S, Heaton D, Hoogenboom EM, Patel A, Brown M, Kamming D. Anaesthesia and COVID-19: infection control. Br J Anaesth. 2020 Jul;125(1):16-24. doi: 10.1016/j.bja.2020.03.025. Epub 2020 Apr 8. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32307115</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wax RS, Christian MD. Practical recommendations for critical care and anesthesiology teams caring for novel coronavirus (2019-nCoV) patients. Can J Anaesth. 2020 May;67(5):568-576. doi: 10.1007/s12630-020-01591-x. Epub 2020 Feb 12. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32052373</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 9, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>December 11, 2020</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">December 14, 2020</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 6, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 6, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>NMC Specialty Hospital</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Prashant Nasa</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head Critical Care Medicine</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Infection Control</keyword>
  <keyword>Intensive care unit</keyword>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Infection</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Communicable Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Coronavirus Infections</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Severe Acute Respiratory Syndrome</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

