<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3041">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04794062</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>08092020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04794062</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Myocardial Injury and Quality of Life After COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>Myocardial Injury and Quality of Life in Patients Recovered From the Pneumonia Associated With the Novel Coronavirus Infectious Disease COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Voronezh Regional Clinical Consultative and Diagnostic Center</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Voronezh State Medical University named after N.N. Burdenko</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>Charles University, Czech Republic</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Voronezh Regional Clinical Consultative and Diagnostic Center</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      In this observational study follow-up and dynamic observation will be conducted on the&#xD;
      participants recovered from pneumonia caused by COVID-19. The main goal is an early diagnosis&#xD;
      and detection of myocardial (heart) injury and quality of life in participants recovered from&#xD;
      COVID-19 and follow-up in selected participants with present signs of myocarditis and/or&#xD;
      myocardial fibrosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The main goal of this observational non-interventional study is the evaluation of prevalence&#xD;
      of myocardial injury (heart injury) of the participants recovered from the novel coronavirus&#xD;
      infectious disease (COVID-19). Participants with signs of myocarditis (pericarditis) and/or&#xD;
      myocardial fibrosis, and with a threat of heart failure development and other outcomes are&#xD;
      selected into this study. In this cohort the percentage of participants having myocardial&#xD;
      injury based on the level of high-sensitivity troponin, echocardiography (decreased Left&#xD;
      Ventricle Ejection Fraction, abnormalities of wall motion, Right Ventricle dysfunction,&#xD;
      increased size of heart chambers above referential values, presence of pericardial effusion),&#xD;
      cardiac MRI with contrast enhancement (presence of edema on T2-weighted images, presence of&#xD;
      early and late gadolinium enhancement phenomenon, local motion abnormalities, increased size&#xD;
      of heart chambers above referential values, presence of pericardial effusion). At 6 months of&#xD;
      the dynamic follow-up, MRI with contrast enhancement will be repeated in the participants&#xD;
      with established myocardial injury at inclusion to assess the percentage of the participants&#xD;
      having ongoing myocardial injury.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The secondary goal of the study is evaluation of quality of life of the patients recovered&#xD;
      from the novel coronavirus infectious disease (COVID-19) by the means of EQ-5D and/or DASI&#xD;
      questionnaire using the descriptive system of 5 components of quality of life related to the&#xD;
      wellbeing, and visual analogue scale.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 16, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">March 31, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients (%) recovered from COVID-19 with signs of myocardial injury on cardiac magnetic resonance imaging.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Myocardial injury on magnetic resonance imaging of the heart with contrast enhancement is determined by the presence of any of the following:&#xD;
Signal enhancement of myocardial tissue on T2-weighted images (above 2 times compared to the signal intensity of skeletal muscles);&#xD;
Myocardial tissue signal enhancement on T1-weighted images during the early phase of gadolinium contrast (signal intensity above 4 times compared to the signal intensity of skeletal muscles or absolute enhancement of the signal above 45%);&#xD;
Presence of at least one focus of the signal enhancement of the myocardial tissue during the late phase of gadolinium contrast;&#xD;
Presence of pericardial effusion with the thickening of the pericardial layers more than 3mm;&#xD;
Presence of the left and/or right ventricle wall motion abnormalities;&#xD;
Decrease of the left ventricle ejection fraction below 57% in men and women or decrease of the right ventricle ejection fraction below 52% in men and 51% in women.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Proportion of patients (%) recovered from COVID-19 with signs of myocardial injury on echocardiography.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Myocardial injury on echocardiography is determined by the presence of any of the following:&#xD;
Presence of regional wall motion abnormalities of the left ventricle in a form of akinesia, hypokinesia, dyskinesia, or hyperkinesia of the corresponding segments of the left ventricle;&#xD;
Decrease of the left ventricle ejection fraction below 52% in women and 54% in men;&#xD;
Presence of right ventricular dysfunction in a form of end-diastolic diameter increase above 42 mm at the base and 35 mm at the middle level, or increase of the right ventricle longitudinal size above 86 mm, or decrease of tricuspid annular plane systolic excursion below 17 mm;&#xD;
Presence of pericardial effusion, i.e., presence of free echocardiographic spaces between the pericardial layers during diastole with pericardial layer thickness more than 4mm.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of quality of life of the patients recovered from the COVID-19 by the means of EQ-5D questionnaire.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The quality of life using the EQ-5D questionnaire is analyzed according to this methodology as a 3-point assessment of quality of life in 5 components (dimensions): D1 - mobility and ability to move, D2 - taking care of oneself, D3 - activities of daily life, D4 - pain and/or discomfort, D5 - anxiety/depression with the definition of the participant's individual health profile in a form of &quot;D1, D2, D3, D4, D5&quot;.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of quality of life of the patients recovered from the COVID-19 by the means of EQ-5D visual analogue scale.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>Assessment of quality of life with the help of visual analogous scale (EQ-VAS) in points from 0 to 100, where 100 is the best possible health condition in the patient's view.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluation of quality of life of the patients recovered from the COVID-19 by the Duke Activity Status Index.</measure>
    <time_frame>Up to 12 months</time_frame>
    <description>The Duke Activity Status Index is an assessment tool used to evaluate the functional capacity of patients with cardiovascular disease. Positive responses are summed up to get a total score, which ranges from 0 to 58.2. Higher scores would indicate a higher functional capacity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <condition>Myocardial Injury</condition>
  <condition>Myocarditis Post Infection</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Community population of the Voronezh region in Western Russia, without need of&#xD;
        hospitalization, sent to by the primary care physicians.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Adult patients of age above 18 years with diagnosed SARS-CoV-2 infection based on the&#xD;
             PCR (polymerase chain reaction) and/or quantitative tests of IgM and IgG antibodies in&#xD;
             serum;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Pneumonia development confirmed by chest computed tomography;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Negative PCR test for SARS-CoV-2 at the time of inclusion into the study;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Stable patient state allowing outpatient follow-up;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Signed informed consent.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of convincing data confirming SARS-CoV-2 infection of a participant at the&#xD;
             time of inclusion;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of medical records regarding previous treatment of COVID-19;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Low compliance and unwillingness to undergo defined examinations;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Absence of informed consent.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Roman Khokhlov, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Voronezh Regional Clinical Consultative and Diagnostic Center</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Leonid Khokhlov, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+(420) 774564302</phone>
    <email>leonkhokhlov@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Roman Khokhlov, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+(7) 9103428865</phone>
    <email>khokhlovroman@gmail.com</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Voronezh Region Clinical, Consultative and Diagnostic Center</name>
      <address>
        <city>Voronezh</city>
        <state>Voronezh Region</state>
        <zip>394018</zip>
        <country>Russian Federation</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Roman Khokhlov, MD</last_name>
      <phone>+(7) 9103428865</phone>
      <email>khokhlovroman@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Russian Federation</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://scardio.ru/content/Guidelines/2020/Clinic_rekom_Miokardit.pdf</url>
    <description>Clinical recommendations on myocarditis of the Healthcare Ministry of the Russian Federation</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Tavazzi G, Pellegrini C, Maurelli M, Belliato M, Sciutti F, Bottazzi A, Sepe PA, Resasco T, Camporotondo R, Bruno R, Baldanti F, Paolucci S, Pelenghi S, Iotti GA, Mojoli F, Arbustini E. Myocardial localization of coronavirus in COVID-19 cardiogenic shock. Eur J Heart Fail. 2020 May;22(5):911-915. doi: 10.1002/ejhf.1828. Epub 2020 Apr 11.</citation>
    <PMID>32275347</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Zhou F, Yu T, Du R, Fan G, Liu Y, Liu Z, Xiang J, Wang Y, Song B, Gu X, Guan L, Wei Y, Li H, Wu X, Xu J, Tu S, Zhang Y, Chen H, Cao B. Clinical course and risk factors for mortality of adult inpatients with COVID-19 in Wuhan, China: a retrospective cohort study. Lancet. 2020 Mar 28;395(10229):1054-1062. doi: 10.1016/S0140-6736(20)30566-3. Epub 2020 Mar 11. Erratum in: Lancet. 2020 Mar 28;395(10229):1038. Lancet. 2020 Mar 28;395(10229):1038.</citation>
    <PMID>32171076</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rudski L, Januzzi JL, Rigolin VH, Bohula EA, Blankstein R, Patel AR, Bucciarelli-Ducci C, Vorovich E, Mukherjee M, Rao SV, Beanlands R, Villines TC, Di Carli MF; Expert Panel From the ACC Cardiovascular Imaging Leadership Council. Multimodality Imaging in Evaluation of Cardiovascular Complications in Patients With COVID-19: JACC Scientific Expert Panel. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020 Sep 15;76(11):1345-1357. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2020.06.080. Epub 2020 Jul 22. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32710927</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lindner D, Fitzek A, Bräuninger H, Aleshcheva G, Edler C, Meissner K, Scherschel K, Kirchhof P, Escher F, Schultheiss HP, Blankenberg S, Püschel K, Westermann D. Association of Cardiac Infection With SARS-CoV-2 in Confirmed COVID-19 Autopsy Cases. JAMA Cardiol. 2020 Nov 1;5(11):1281-1285. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2020.3551.</citation>
    <PMID>32730555</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Huang L, Zhao P, Tang D, Zhu T, Han R, Zhan C, Liu W, Zeng H, Tao Q, Xia L. Cardiac Involvement in Patients Recovered From COVID-2019 Identified Using Magnetic Resonance Imaging. JACC Cardiovasc Imaging. 2020 Nov;13(11):2330-2339. doi: 10.1016/j.jcmg.2020.05.004. Epub 2020 May 12.</citation>
    <PMID>32763118</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Puntmann VO, Carerj ML, Wieters I, Fahim M, Arendt C, Hoffmann J, Shchendrygina A, Escher F, Vasa-Nicotera M, Zeiher AM, Vehreschild M, Nagel E. Outcomes of Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance Imaging in Patients Recently Recovered From Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19). JAMA Cardiol. 2020 Nov 1;5(11):1265-1273. doi: 10.1001/jamacardio.2020.3557. Erratum in: JAMA Cardiol. 2020 Nov 1;5(11):1308.</citation>
    <PMID>32730619</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hendren NS, Drazner MH, Bozkurt B, Cooper LT Jr. Description and Proposed Management of the Acute COVID-19 Cardiovascular Syndrome. Circulation. 2020 Jun 9;141(23):1903-1914. doi: 10.1161/CIRCULATIONAHA.120.047349. Epub 2020 Apr 16. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32297796</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Medical rehabilitation during the novel coronavirus 19 disease (COVID-19). Physical and rehabilitation medicine, medical rehabilitation. 2020;2(2):140-189. DOI: https://doi.org/10.36425/rehab34231</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Temporary methodical recommendation &quot;Prophylaxis, diagnosis, and treatment of the novel coronavirus 19 (COVID-19)&quot;, 9th Edition released on 10/26/2020</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Schultz JC, Hilliard AA, Cooper LT Jr, Rihal CS. Diagnosis and treatment of viral myocarditis. Mayo Clin Proc. 2009 Nov;84(11):1001-9. doi: 10.1016/S0025-6196(11)60670-8. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>19880690</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Friedrich MG, Sechtem U, Schulz-Menger J, Holmvang G, Alakija P, Cooper LT, White JA, Abdel-Aty H, Gutberlet M, Prasad S, Aletras A, Laissy JP, Paterson I, Filipchuk NG, Kumar A, Pauschinger M, Liu P; International Consensus Group on Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance in Myocarditis. Cardiovascular magnetic resonance in myocarditis: A JACC White Paper. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2009 Apr 28;53(17):1475-87. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2009.02.007.</citation>
    <PMID>19389557</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ferreira VM, Schulz-Menger J, Holmvang G, Kramer CM, Carbone I, Sechtem U, Kindermann I, Gutberlet M, Cooper LT, Liu P, Friedrich MG. Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance in Nonischemic Myocardial Inflammation: Expert Recommendations. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2018 Dec 18;72(24):3158-3176. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2018.09.072. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>30545455</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Caforio AL, Pankuweit S, Arbustini E, Basso C, Gimeno-Blanes J, Felix SB, Fu M, Heliö T, Heymans S, Jahns R, Klingel K, Linhart A, Maisch B, McKenna W, Mogensen J, Pinto YM, Ristic A, Schultheiss HP, Seggewiss H, Tavazzi L, Thiene G, Yilmaz A, Charron P, Elliott PM; European Society of Cardiology Working Group on Myocardial and Pericardial Diseases. Current state of knowledge on aetiology, diagnosis, management, and therapy of myocarditis: a position statement of the European Society of Cardiology Working Group on Myocardial and Pericardial Diseases. Eur Heart J. 2013 Sep;34(33):2636-48, 2648a-2648d. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/eht210. Epub 2013 Jul 3.</citation>
    <PMID>23824828</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Comparative investigation of informative yield of non-invasive diagnostics methods of inflammatory diseases of myocardium. Russian cardiology journal 2018, (154): 53-59. http://dx.doi.org/10.15829/1560-4071-2018-2-53-59</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Ponikowski P, Voors AA, Anker SD, Bueno H, Cleland JGF, Coats AJS, Falk V, González-Juanatey JR, Harjola VP, Jankowska EA, Jessup M, Linde C, Nihoyannopoulos P, Parissis JT, Pieske B, Riley JP, Rosano GMC, Ruilope LM, Ruschitzka F, Rutten FH, van der Meer P; ESC Scientific Document Group. 2016 ESC Guidelines for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure: The Task Force for the diagnosis and treatment of acute and chronic heart failure of the European Society of Cardiology (ESC)Developed with the special contribution of the Heart Failure Association (HFA) of the ESC. Eur Heart J. 2016 Jul 14;37(27):2129-2200. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehw128. Epub 2016 May 20. Erratum in: Eur Heart J. 2016 Dec 30;:.</citation>
    <PMID>27206819</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Guidelines for the management of myocarditis. Eurasian cardiology journal 2015;3:5-17</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Giustino G, Croft LB, Stefanini GG, Bragato R, Silbiger JJ, Vicenzi M, Danilov T, Kukar N, Shaban N, Kini A, Camaj A, Bienstock SW, Rashed ER, Rahman K, Oates CP, Buckley S, Elbaum LS, Arkonac D, Fiter R, Singh R, Li E, Razuk V, Robinson SE, Miller M, Bier B, Donghi V, Pisaniello M, Mantovani R, Pinto G, Rota I, Baggio S, Chiarito M, Fazzari F, Cusmano I, Curzi M, Ro R, Malick W, Kamran M, Kohli-Seth R, Bassily-Marcus AM, Neibart E, Serrao G, Perk G, Mancini D, Reddy VY, Pinney SP, Dangas G, Blasi F, Sharma SK, Mehran R, Condorelli G, Stone GW, Fuster V, Lerakis S, Goldman ME. Characterization of Myocardial Injury in Patients With COVID-19. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2020 Nov 3;76(18):2043-2055. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2020.08.069.</citation>
    <PMID>33121710</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Life quality of the Russian population by the data from ESSE-RF study. Cardiovascular Therapy and Prevention, 2016; 15(5): 84-90 http://dx.doi.org/10.15829/1728-8800-2016-5-84-90</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Health-related quality of life population indicators using EQ-5D questionnaire. Zdravookhranenie Rossiiskoi Federatsii (Health Care of the Russian Federation, Russian journal). 2018; 62(6): 295-303. (In Russ.) DOI: http://dx.doi.org/10.18821/0044-197Х-2018-62-6-295-303</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kotecha T, Knight DS, Razvi Y, Kumar K, Vimalesvaran K, Thornton G, Patel R, Chacko L, Brown JT, Coyle C, Leith D, Shetye A, Ariff B, Bell R, Captur G, Coleman M, Goldring J, Gopalan D, Heightman M, Hillman T, Howard L, Jacobs M, Jeetley PS, Kanagaratnam P, Kon OM, Lamb LE, Manisty CH, Mathurdas P, Mayet J, Negus R, Patel N, Pierce I, Russell G, Wolff A, Xue H, Kellman P, Moon JC, Treibel TA, Cole GD, Fontana M. Patterns of myocardial injury in recovered troponin-positive COVID-19 patients assessed by cardiovascular magnetic resonance. Eur Heart J. 2021 Feb 18. pii: ehab075. doi: 10.1093/eurheartj/ehab075. [Epub ahead of print]</citation>
    <PMID>33596594</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Petersen SE, Khanji MY, Plein S, Lancellotti P, Bucciarelli-Ducci C. European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging expert consensus paper: a comprehensive review of cardiovascular magnetic resonance normal values of cardiac chamber size and aortic root in adults and recommendations for grading severity. Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2019 Dec 1;20(12):1321-1331. doi: 10.1093/ehjci/jez232. Erratum in: Eur Heart J Cardiovasc Imaging. 2019 Dec 1;20(12):1331.</citation>
    <PMID>31544926</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Douglas PS, Carabello BA, Lang RM, Lopez L, Pellikka PA, Picard MH, Thomas JD, Varghese P, Wang TY, Weissman NJ, Wilgus R. 2019 ACC/AHA/ASE Key Data Elements and Definitions for Transthoracic Echocardiography: A Report of the American College of Cardiology/American Heart Association Task Force on Clinical Data Standards (Writing Committee to Develop Cardiovascular Endpoints Data Standards) and the American Society of Echocardiography. J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019 Jul 23;74(3):403-469. doi: 10.1016/j.jacc.2019.02.027. Epub 2019 Jun 24. Erratum in: J Am Coll Cardiol. 2019 Aug 13;74(6):827.</citation>
    <PMID>31248701</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Lang RM, Badano LP, Mor-Avi V, Afilalo J, Armstrong A, Ernande L, Flachskampf FA, Foster E, Goldstein SA, Kuznetsova T, Lancellotti P, Muraru D, Picard MH, Rietzschel ER, Rudski L, Spencer KT, Tsang W, Voigt JU. Recommendations for cardiac chamber quantification by echocardiography in adults: an update from the American Society of Echocardiography and the European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2015 Jan;28(1):1-39.e14. doi: 10.1016/j.echo.2014.10.003.</citation>
    <PMID>25559473</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Nagueh SF, Smiseth OA, Appleton CP, Byrd BF 3rd, Dokainish H, Edvardsen T, Flachskampf FA, Gillebert TC, Klein AL, Lancellotti P, Marino P, Oh JK, Popescu BA, Waggoner AD. Recommendations for the Evaluation of Left Ventricular Diastolic Function by Echocardiography: An Update from the American Society of Echocardiography and the European Association of Cardiovascular Imaging. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2016 Apr;29(4):277-314. doi: 10.1016/j.echo.2016.01.011.</citation>
    <PMID>27037982</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rudski LG, Lai WW, Afilalo J, Hua L, Handschumacher MD, Chandrasekaran K, Solomon SD, Louie EK, Schiller NB. Guidelines for the echocardiographic assessment of the right heart in adults: a report from the American Society of Echocardiography endorsed by the European Association of Echocardiography, a registered branch of the European Society of Cardiology, and the Canadian Society of Echocardiography. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2010 Jul;23(7):685-713; quiz 786-8. doi: 10.1016/j.echo.2010.05.010.</citation>
    <PMID>20620859</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Klein AL, Abbara S, Agler DA, Appleton CP, Asher CR, Hoit B, Hung J, Garcia MJ, Kronzon I, Oh JK, Rodriguez ER, Schaff HV, Schoenhagen P, Tan CD, White RD. American Society of Echocardiography clinical recommendations for multimodality cardiovascular imaging of patients with pericardial disease: endorsed by the Society for Cardiovascular Magnetic Resonance and Society of Cardiovascular Computed Tomography. J Am Soc Echocardiogr. 2013 Sep;26(9):965-1012.e15. doi: 10.1016/j.echo.2013.06.023.</citation>
    <PMID>23998693</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Devlin NJ, Brooks R. EQ-5D and the EuroQol Group: Past, Present and Future. Appl Health Econ Health Policy. 2017 Apr;15(2):127-137. doi: 10.1007/s40258-017-0310-5. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>28194657</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Alexandrova E.A., Herry J. Populational indicators of quality of life related to the health according to EQ-5D questionnaire. Healthcare of the Russian Federation. 2018; 62(6): 295-303. DOI: http://dx.doi.org/10.18821/0044-197Х-2018-62-6-295-303.</citation>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Hlatky MA, Boineau RE, Higginbotham MB, Lee KL, Mark DB, Califf RM, Cobb FR, Pryor DB. A brief self-administered questionnaire to determine functional capacity (the Duke Activity Status Index). Am J Cardiol. 1989 Sep 15;64(10):651-4.</citation>
    <PMID>2782256</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 15, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 10, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 11, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 10, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 10, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 11, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Voronezh Regional Clinical Consultative and Diagnostic Center</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Roman Khokhlov</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD, Professor, Doctor of Sciences (Dr.Sc.)</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-9</keyword>
  <keyword>myocardial injury</keyword>
  <keyword>myocarditis</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myocarditis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Wounds and Injuries</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <provided_document_section>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Study Protocol and Statistical Analysis Plan</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>Yes</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>No</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>Yes</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>September 16, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/62/NCT04794062/Prot_SAP_000.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
    <provided_document>
      <document_type>Informed Consent Form</document_type>
      <document_has_protocol>No</document_has_protocol>
      <document_has_icf>Yes</document_has_icf>
      <document_has_sap>No</document_has_sap>
      <document_date>September 16, 2020</document_date>
      <document_url>https://ClinicalTrials.gov/ProvidedDocs/62/NCT04794062/ICF_001.pdf</document_url>
    </provided_document>
  </provided_document_section>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

