<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="502">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04771052</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>MP-31-2021-3770</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04771052</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Minimizing the Effects of COVID-19 Hospitalization With the COVID Rehabilitation Program for the Elderly</brief_title>
  <acronym>CORE</acronym>
  <official_title>Minimizing the Effects of COVID-19 Hospitalization With the COVID Rehabilitation Program for the Elderly: the CORE Trial in Response to the Pandemic</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Université de Sherbrooke</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Université de Sherbrooke</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Although evidence from the management of other viral respiratory infections suggest that&#xD;
      early multidisciplinary rehabilitation could mitigate the adverse effects of the severe form&#xD;
      of the illness, and reduce the length of hospital stays (LOS), specific data for COVID-19 are&#xD;
      lacking. Hence, in response to the current pandemic, we propose to implement and assess the&#xD;
      impact of an early standardized multidisciplinary rehabilitation program tailored to frail&#xD;
      older adults on 1) LOS, 2) post-discharge destination, 3) prognostic index and 4) functional&#xD;
      capacity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With a pragmatic multicenter controlled study, the COvid Rehabilitation Program for the&#xD;
      Elderly (CORE) trial will allow to measure the effectiveness of a multidisciplinary program&#xD;
      to minimize the effects of hospitalization and provide the required tools to rapidly&#xD;
      implement an innovative strategy of care for older adults. Indeed, based on the results of&#xD;
      this study, and with the support of scientific and professional organizations, a standardized&#xD;
      program tailored to older adults with COVID-19 will be disseminated in Canada for all medical&#xD;
      units dedicated to the management of the disease. Because of its pragmatic approach, this&#xD;
      study will provide a sustainable multidisciplinary intervention that can be quickly&#xD;
      implemented in any Canadian (or abroad) COVID-19 medical unit. Finally, given that COVID-19&#xD;
      is the third coronavirus infection in the last 20 years, the expected results will provide&#xD;
      guidelines, with decision tree algorithms, for implementation should another coronavirus or&#xD;
      for that matter, any other such type of infection that surface in the future.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Enrolling by invitation</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Case-Control</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Length of stay</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day after discharge</time_frame>
    <description>Length of stay in COVID and subacute unit (days)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-discharge destination</measure>
    <time_frame>1 day after discharge</time_frame>
    <description>(home; long-term care facilities; death) or transfer to a specialized subacute unit (e.g., rehabilitation geriatric unit)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Readmission rate 30 days after discharge</measure>
    <time_frame>30 days after discharge</time_frame>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in patient prognosis</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline (± 2 days after admission in the COVID-19 unit) and before discharge (± 3 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Evaluated using the COVID-19 vulnerability index (symptoms, medical history, and sociodemographic data)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in functional capacity (lower limb function)</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline (± 2 days after admission in the COVID-19 unit) and before discharge (± 3 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Lower limb function is assessed using the 5-repetition sit-to-stand test (reported in seconds)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in functional capacity (handgrip strength)</measure>
    <time_frame>At baseline (± 2 days after admission in the COVID-19 unit) and before discharge (± 3 days)</time_frame>
    <description>Handgrip strength is measured using a handgrip dynamometer (reported in kg)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>2</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">128</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>CORE program</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients admitted to a dedicated COVID-19 units (CHUS Hôtel-Dieu de Sherbrooke - CIUSSS de L'Estrie - CHUS) with medical clearance (physical deconditioning; hemodynamically stable; oxygen therapy by nasal cannula &lt; 4 L/min for saturation &gt; 92%; resting respiratory rate &lt; 24; and heart rate between 50 and 120 beats per minute).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients admitted to a dedicated COVID-19 units (CHAUR de Trois-Rivières, CIUSSS de la Mauricie-et-du-Centre-du-Québec) receiving usual care, matched to CORE a patient with similar characteristics (sex, age, preadmission provenance).</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>COVID Rehabilitation Program for the Elderly (CORE)</intervention_name>
    <description>In the intervention unit, two teams (core team: physiotherapists and service healthcare workers; specialized team: occupational therapist, registered dietician, social worker) are dedicated to the patients hospitalized in COVID-19 unit. To prevent malnutrition, caused by disease-associated inflammation, the Nutrition as Medicine program (prescribed small doses (30 or 60 mL; 2 kcal/mL) of oral nutrition supplement dispensed with medication pass, 1 to 4 times a day), has been systematically implemented (collective prescription). To improve muscle strength, balance and tissue oxygenation and concomitantly reduce immobilization and risk of falls, each patient has a private pedal exerciser, resistance elastic bands and free weights to perform a progressive, monitored and individualized rehabilitation program thrice a day.</description>
    <arm_group_label>CORE program</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients admitted to the COVID unit at CHUS Hôtel-Dieu de Sherbrooke - CIUSSS de L'Estrie -&#xD;
        CHUS (CORE program) or CHAUR de Trois-Rivières, CIUSSS de la&#xD;
        Mauricie-et-du-Centre-du-Québec (Controls)&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with medical clearance (physical deconditioning; hemodynamically stable;&#xD;
             oxygen therapy by nasal cannula &lt; 4 L/min for saturation &gt; 92%; resting respiratory&#xD;
             rate &lt; 24; and heart rate between 50 and 120 beats per minute). Controls were paired&#xD;
             with those of the CORE program according to age, sex and pre-admission origin&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  None&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CIUSSS de l'Estrie-Centre hospitalier universitaire de Sherbrooke (CHUS)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Sherbrooke</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>J1J 3H5</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Centre hospitalier affilié universitaire régional (CHAUR)</name>
      <address>
        <city>Trois-Rivières</city>
        <state>Quebec</state>
        <zip>G8Z 3R9</zip>
        <country>Canada</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Canada</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 23, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 24, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 25, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 24, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 24, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 25, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

