<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="1224">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04790994</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>2020-A01838-31</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04790994</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 Prevalence in UNIVI Geriatric Institutions: Epidemiological Study of Immunological Status With Rapid Serological Tests</brief_title>
  <official_title>COVID-19 Prevalence in UNIVI Group Nursing Homes and Geriatric Healthcare Institutions: Epidemiological Study of Immunological Status With Rapid Serological Tests for Diagnostic Guidance</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Centre Médical Porte Verte</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Centre Médical Porte Verte</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      To date, little information is available on the prevalence of Covid-19 and data are lacking&#xD;
      on the proportion of patients, institutional residents and caregivers who have actually been&#xD;
      exposed to SARS Cov-2.&#xD;
&#xD;
      With the NG Biotech rapid serological test, an individual's immunological status (presence of&#xD;
      IgM and IgG antibodies) can be determined in 15 minutes on a finger-prick blood sample.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The proposed trial will be a noninterventional study of immunological status among the&#xD;
      residents and caregivers of 26 nursing homes and 4 geriatric healthcare institutions&#xD;
      belonging to the UNIVI Group who are representative of the institutional geriatric population&#xD;
      in France. The NG Biotech rapid test will be carried out concomitantly with polymerase chain&#xD;
      reaction (PCR) tests performed within the framework of a national screening campaign. Data on&#xD;
      risk factors in staff members and on specific COVID 19 symptoms in residents will also be&#xD;
      collected.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will terminate for residents and caregivers whose tests are both negative (absence&#xD;
      of infection and no exposure to the virus). For residents and caregivers who have at least&#xD;
      one positive test, follow-up visits will be scheduled in order to study the serology time&#xD;
      course and the occurrence of reinfection (follow-up questionnaire).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Type of study: multicentric prospective observational Study location: 26 nursing homes and 4&#xD;
      geriatric hospitals belonging to the UNIVI Group in France&#xD;
&#xD;
      Context:&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the end of the Covid-19 containment period in France, data published by Public Health&#xD;
      France revealed that frail and dependent elderly people in nursing homes and geriatric&#xD;
      healthcare institutions had paid a heavy tribute. As of May 4, 2020, the majority of reported&#xD;
      Covid-19 cases (n=4,600; 63%) had occurred in nursing home residents and more than one-third&#xD;
      (n=2,664; 37%) in patients in geriatric healthcare institutions. A total of 71,216 Covid-19&#xD;
      cases of which 33,948 (48%) were confirmed by reverse transferase polymerase chain reaction&#xD;
      (RT-PCR) tests were reported to health authorities (Agence Régionale de Santé, ARS). Among&#xD;
      reported cases, there were 12,726 deaths. Three-quarters of these deaths (9,501; 75%)&#xD;
      occurred in geriatric institutions, the vast majority (99%) in nursing homes and 3,321 (25%)&#xD;
      in hospitals. Reports of infection among staff members of these institutions reached 39,294&#xD;
      cases, of which 18,175 (46%) were confirmed by RT- PCR.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The confinement allowed a significant and continuous decrease in the number of Covid cases in&#xD;
      French geriatric institutions since the beginning of April. The proportion of new cases&#xD;
      observed among institutionalized geriatric residents has since fallen sharply, particularly&#xD;
      in the most affected geographic regions. This is why deconfinement should be gradual and&#xD;
      should be constantly reassessed on the basis of national and regional epidemiological data.&#xD;
      Each nursing home should to take into account its own daily data showing the number of new&#xD;
      diagnoses or suspected cases among residents and caregivers, keeping in mind the risk of&#xD;
      transmission by visitors in the event of a recurrence of the epidemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In France, the deconfinement strategy began on April 20, 2020 in Île-de-France. Family visits&#xD;
      under strict conditions were authorized in geriatric institutions. Currently, the modus&#xD;
      operandi is accompanied by a PCR test campaign in order to have an inventory of the COVID&#xD;
      status of all institutional residents and caregivers. Thus, any resident with a positive PCR&#xD;
      test will be isolated until recovery and any caregiver with a positive PCR test will be&#xD;
      quarantined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For nursing home admissions, in accordance with ARS guidelines, a PCR test may be requested&#xD;
      upon prescription from the institution's coordinating physician. Room confinement for newly&#xD;
      admitted residents will be determined by the institution's geographical localization.&#xD;
      Administrative districts are classified in two zones, red and green. For institutions in the&#xD;
      red zone, room confinement with close medical supervision is compulsory for 14 days,&#xD;
      corresponding to the viral incubation time. For institutions in the green zone, room&#xD;
      confinement is not mandatory, but close medical surveillance is recommended.&#xD;
&#xD;
      What could NG Biotech rapid serological tests bring to the deconfinement strategy? These&#xD;
      tests make it possible to determine an individual's immunological status (presence of IgM and&#xD;
      IgG antibodies) in 15 minutes on a finger-prick blood sample. The test cannot be used in the&#xD;
      acute phase of the disease, but makes it possible to confirm the serological status of an&#xD;
      asymptomatic patient 15 days after the first clinical signs. Test sensitivity (ability to&#xD;
      identify antibodies) is 100%. Serological testing does not answer the same question as PCR.&#xD;
      PCR directly detects the presence of the virus, optimal in the first 7 days, it can remain&#xD;
      positive for up to 3 weeks or even beyond. The serological test provides information on&#xD;
      whether or not there is contact with the virus. If the serological test is positive in an&#xD;
      asymptomatic patient, the patient is likely more than 15 days from symptom onset. It does not&#xD;
      provide information on the risk of contagiousness. For nursing homes and geriatric healthcare&#xD;
      institutions, use of serological testing, common law is applicable. The superior French&#xD;
      health agency (Haute Autorité de Santé, HAS) specifies that these tests are indicated for&#xD;
      epidemiological study or as a diagnostic catch-up tool (Place of rapid serotests in the&#xD;
      strategy for the management of the COVID-19, HAS, May 14, 2020). The HAS recommendation&#xD;
      specifies that rapid diagnostic tests must be performed by: - Professionals and staff who&#xD;
      have previously received training in the use of COVID-19 rapid diagnostic tests - Doctors&#xD;
      practicing in private practice - Doctors, medical biologists, midwives working in an&#xD;
      institution or in a healthcare service (e.g. specialized screening structures) - Nurses or&#xD;
      laboratory technicians working in an institution or in a healthcare service under the&#xD;
      supervision of a doctor or a medical biologist - Midwives or nurses working in a prevention&#xD;
      structure or an associative structure involved in health prevention - Community pharmacists -&#xD;
      Employees or volunteers, non-healthcare professionals working in a prevention structure or an&#xD;
      association structure, provided that they have previously received training in the use of&#xD;
      rapid diagnostic tests.&#xD;
&#xD;
      To date, little information is available on the prevalence of Covid-19 and data are lacking&#xD;
      on the proportion of patients, institutional residents and caregivers who have actually been&#xD;
      exposed to SARS Cov-2. Likewise, in the scientific literature, there is uncertainty among&#xD;
      people who have acquired immunity as to the persistence of neutralizing antibodies at 6&#xD;
      months and the risk of re-infection with COVID 19 after a primary infection. A major campaign&#xD;
      of serological tests is in preparation in the geriatric institutions of the UNIVI Group. This&#xD;
      study is based on this campaign using data collected in 26 nursing homes and 4 geriatric&#xD;
      healthcare institutions. In total, around 2,000 residents, and 2,000 caregivers will be&#xD;
      tested. The residents and caregivers of the tested institutions are representative of the&#xD;
      institutionalized geriatric population in France. It is thus proposed to carry out a&#xD;
      non-interventional study among residents and caregivers in nursing homes and in healthcare&#xD;
      institutions belonging to the UNIVI Group. NG Biotech rapid tests will be performed&#xD;
      concomitantly with PCR tests made within the framework of the national screening campaign.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 24, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 16, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 16, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Among asymptomatic residents and caregivers in French nursing homes and geriatric healthcare institutions belonging to the UNIVI Group: prevalence of covid 19</measure>
    <time_frame>three months</time_frame>
    <description>positive RT-PCR test and/or (for residents) clinical diagnosis recorded in the medical file</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Exposure to SARS Cov-2 Among asymptomatic residents and caregivers in French nursing homes and geriatric healthcare institutions belonging to the UNIVI Group</measure>
    <time_frame>three months</time_frame>
    <description>positive NG Biotech rapid serological test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Recurrence of Covid-19 at 1, 3 and 6 months among residents and caregivers who had at least on positive test at inclusion (RT-PCR test or NB Biotech rapid serological test)</measure>
    <time_frame>Time Frame: one, three and six months after inclusion]</time_frame>
    <description>RT-PCR in favor of Covid-19 recurrence and/or positive results of an NG Biotech rapid serological test.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Risk factors for Covid-19 infection in caregivers</measure>
    <time_frame>three months</time_frame>
    <description>analysis of the questionnaire items: age; sex; occupation; type of housing; family composition; means of transportation; contact with an infected person</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Covid-19 symptoms among residents</measure>
    <time_frame>three months</time_frame>
    <description>analysis of symptoms reported on the questionnaire</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Prevalence of Covid-19 at 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>three months</time_frame>
    <description>positive test (RT-PCR or NB Biotech rapid serological test) and/or (for residents) suspected or definitive diagnosis of Covid-19 recorded in the medical file.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">1145</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        1145 residents and 1134 professionals in 26 nursing homes and 4 geriatric hospitals&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residents of participating nursing home - who benefited from a rapid diagnostic&#xD;
             orientation serological test for COVID-19 - having given their agreement&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  All staff members (doctors, nurses, health executives, caregivers, physiotherapists,&#xD;
             ASH, stretcher bearers, psychologists, dieteticians, administrative staff,&#xD;
             secretaries, ...) - who benefited from a rapid diagnostic orientation serologic test&#xD;
             for COVID-19 - having given their agreement&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Refusal to participate&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>CentreMédicalPorteVerte</name>
      <address>
        <city>Versailles</city>
        <zip>78000</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 10, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 9, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 10, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 9, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 9, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 10, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

