<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4086">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04766983</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>20/01/2021-0002005-U</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04766983</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Incidence of VAP in Patients With Severe COVID-19</brief_title>
  <acronym>CoV-AP</acronym>
  <official_title>Cohort Study to Evaluate the Incidence of Ventilator-associated Pneumonia by Means of Bronchoalveolar Lavage in Patients With Severe SARS-CoV-2 Infection</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Fondazione IRCCS Ca' Granda, Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Fondazione IRCCS Ca' Granda, Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Combined retrospective and prospective cohort study to evaluate the incidence of&#xD;
      microbiologically confirmed VAP in mechanically ventilated patients with COVID-19. In the&#xD;
      retrospective part, microbiological data are based on bi-weekly surveillance ETA. In the&#xD;
      prospective part, microbiological data are based on ETA and BAL performed on VAP suspicion.&#xD;
      In the prospective part, immunological and virological analyses will be performed on&#xD;
      biological samples (blood, respiratory tract) collected from patients at VAP diagnosis.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Ventilator-associated pneumoniae (VAP) is the most common infection acquired in the intensive&#xD;
      care unit (ICU). To date, there is no diagnostic gold standard for VAP, and its diagnosis is&#xD;
      based on scores that include radiologic, clinical, laboratory, and microbiologic parameters.&#xD;
      In addition, there is no univocal recommendation regarding the type of microbiological&#xD;
      diagnostics. Some guidelines suggest the use of noninvasive methods (endotracheal aspiration,&#xD;
      ETA) with semiquantitative cultures, while others suggest the collection of distal&#xD;
      respiratory samples (bronchoalveolar lavage, BAL) with quantitative cultures. While the&#xD;
      former method is characterized by higher sensitivity and lower specificity, the latter in&#xD;
      contrast has higher specificity. To date, there is no evidence that one method is superior to&#xD;
      the other in terms of clinical outcome.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In patients with severe SARS-CoV-2 infection, COVID-19 disease itself and immunomodulatory&#xD;
      therapies have a direct impact on most of the clinical, laboratory and radiologic parameters&#xD;
      required to achieve VAP diagnosis. In this setting, a diagnostic approach characterized by&#xD;
      higher sensitivity coupled with lower specificity could lead to of a high number of false&#xD;
      positives. The greatest risk is that of an overdiagnosis of VAP and a consequent&#xD;
      overtreatment, with the related therapeutic toxicity and increased antibiotic resistance.&#xD;
&#xD;
      At the investigators' Hospital, the diagnosis of VAP is based on clinical-radiological&#xD;
      suspicion according to the Johanson score (new finding or progression of infiltrates on lung&#xD;
      radiography + at least two of the following three clinical criteria: fever &gt; 38°C,&#xD;
      leukocytosis or leukopenia, purulent secretions), widely validated in non-COVID patients.&#xD;
      Until the end of 2020, microbiological data to confirm the diagnosis of clinically suspected&#xD;
      VAP and to guide antibiotic therapy were based on the performance of biweekly surveillance&#xD;
      ETA. In view of the limited specificity of this approach in COVID-19 setting, from the end of&#xD;
      2020 patients with SARS-CoV-2 infection and suspected VAP undergo, if clinically possible, to&#xD;
      collection of distal respiratory specimens by performing BAL/mini-BAL.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The present prospective-retrospective cohort study aims to evaluate the incidence of&#xD;
      microbiologically confirmed VAP with BAL (prospective part) and biweekly surveillance ETA&#xD;
      (retrospective part) in mechanically ventilated patients with COVID-19 in the ICU. In the&#xD;
      prospective part, immunological and virological analyses will be performed on biological&#xD;
      samples (blood, respiratory tract) collected from patients at VAP diagnosis.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study will last 12 months.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 22, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">April 30, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">January 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Other</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence of VAP</measure>
    <time_frame>1,000 ventilator days</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence of clinically suspected and microbiologically confirmed VAP by means of BAL</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>number of episodes with concordance in bacterial isolates between BAL and ETA performed on VAP suspicion</measure>
    <time_frame>1,000 ventilator days</time_frame>
    <description>microbiological concordance of respiratory specimens collected by BAL and ETA on VAP suspicion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>number of episodes with concordance in bacterial isolates between BAL performed on VAP suspicion and the preceding surveillance ETA</measure>
    <time_frame>1,000 ventilator days</time_frame>
    <description>microbiological concordance of respiratory specimens collected by BAL on VAP suspicion and the preceding bi-weekly surveillance ETA</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>number of episodes with concordance in cellular phenotype between BAL and peripheral blood on VAP suspicion</measure>
    <time_frame>1,000 ventilator days</time_frame>
    <description>immunological analysis of cellular phenotype in BAL and peripheral blood collected on VAP suspicion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>number of episodes with concordance in lymphocyte-monocyte activation between BAL and peripheral blood on VAP suspicion</measure>
    <time_frame>1,000 ventilator days</time_frame>
    <description>immunological analysis of lymphocyte-monocyte activation in BAL and peripheral blood collected on VAP suspicion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>number of episodes with concordance in SARS-CoV-2 viral quantification between BAL, ETA and nasopharyngeal swab on VAP suspicion</measure>
    <time_frame>1,000 ventilator days</time_frame>
    <description>virological analysis of SARS-CoV-2 viral quantification in BAL, ETA and nasopharyngeal swab collected on VAP suspicion (subgroup analysis)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>number of episodes with concordance in SARS-CoV-2 sequencing between BAL, ETA and nasopharyngeal swab on VAP suspicion</measure>
    <time_frame>1,000 ventilator days</time_frame>
    <description>virological analysis of SARS-CoV-2 sequencing in BAL, ETA and nasopharyngeal swab collected on VAP suspicion (subgroup analysis)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>3</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Ventilator Associated Pneumonia</condition>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>VAP - BAL positive</arm_group_label>
    <description>Clinically suspected VAP, microbiologically confirmed by BAL</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>VAP - BAL negative</arm_group_label>
    <description>Clinically suspected VAP, not microbiologically confirmed by BAL</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>NO VAP</arm_group_label>
    <description>No clinically suspected VAP during mechanical ventilation</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Diagnostic Test</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>bronchoalveolar lavage</intervention_name>
    <description>BAL and ETA are performed as per clinical practice on clinical suspicion of VAP (Johanson score)</description>
    <arm_group_label>VAP - BAL negative</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>VAP - BAL positive</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Nasopharyngeal swab, Bronchial aspirate, bronchoalveolar lavage&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Mechanically ventilated patients with severe SARS-CoV-2 infection&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Retrospective part all patients admitted to the ICU for COVID-19-related respiratory&#xD;
        failure since the beginning of the pandemics will be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Prospective part&#xD;
&#xD;
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age ≥ 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection by means of reverse transcription polymerase chain&#xD;
             reaction (RT-PCR)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Respiratory failure requiring mechanical ventilation&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mechanical ventilation ongoing for less than 48h&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age &lt; 18 years&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  mechanical ventilation ongoing for more than 48h&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Giacomo Grasselli, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, IRCCS Ca' Granda Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico Foundation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Andrea Gori, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Infectious Diseases Unit, IRCCS Ca' Granda Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico Foundation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Mauro Panigada, MD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Intensive Care Unit, IRCCS Ca' Granda Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico Foundation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Alessandra Bandera, MD, PhD</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Infectious Diseases Unit, IRCCS Ca' Granda Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico Foundation</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Giacomo Grasselli, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+39 02 5502.3285</phone>
    <email>giacomo.grasselli@unimi.it</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Andrea Gori, MD</last_name>
    <phone>+39 02 5503.4763-4762</phone>
    <email>andrea.gori@unimi.it</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>IRCCS Ca' Granda Ospedale Maggiore Policlinico Foundation</name>
      <address>
        <city>Milan</city>
        <state>MI</state>
        <zip>20122</zip>
        <country>Italy</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Giacomo Grasselli, MD</last_name>
      <email>giacomo.grasselli@unimi.it</email>
    </contact>
    <contact_backup>
      <last_name>Andrea Gori, MD</last_name>
      <email>andrea.gori@unimi.it</email>
    </contact_backup>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Italy</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>http://systems.jhu.edu</url>
    <description>COVID-19 cases worldwide</description>
  </link>
  <reference>
    <citation>Wu Z, McGoogan JM. Characteristics of and Important Lessons From the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) Outbreak in China: Summary of a Report of 72 314 Cases From the Chinese Center for Disease Control and Prevention. JAMA. 2020 Apr 7;323(13):1239-1242. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.2648.</citation>
    <PMID>32091533</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Grasselli G, Pesenti A, Cecconi M. Critical Care Utilization for the COVID-19 Outbreak in Lombardy, Italy: Early Experience and Forecast During an Emergency Response. JAMA. 2020 Apr 28;323(16):1545-1546. doi: 10.1001/jama.2020.4031.</citation>
    <PMID>32167538</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Rosenthal VD, Al-Abdely HM, El-Kholy AA, AlKhawaja SAA, Leblebicioglu H, Mehta Y, Rai V, Hung NV, Kanj SS, Salama MF, Salgado-Yepez E, Elahi N, Morfin Otero R, Apisarnthanarak A, De Carvalho BM, Ider BE, Fisher D, Buenaflor MCSG, Petrov MM, Quesada-Mora AM, Zand F, Gurskis V, Anguseva T, Ikram A, Aguilar de Moros D, Duszynska W, Mejia N, Horhat FG, Belskiy V, Mioljevic V, Di Silvestre G, Furova K, Ramos-Ortiz GY, Gamar Elanbya MO, Satari HI, Gupta U, Dendane T, Raka L, Guanche-Garcell H, Hu B, Padgett D, Jayatilleke K, Ben Jaballah N, Apostolopoulou E, Prudencio Leon WE, Sepulveda-Chavez A, Telechea HM, Trotter A, Alvarez-Moreno C, Kushner-Davalos L; Remaining authors. International Nosocomial Infection Control Consortium report, data summary of 50 countries for 2010-2015: Device-associated module. Am J Infect Control. 2016 Dec 1;44(12):1495-1504. doi: 10.1016/j.ajic.2016.08.007. Epub 2016 Oct 11.</citation>
    <PMID>27742143</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Papazian L, Klompas M, Luyt CE. Ventilator-associated pneumonia in adults: a narrative review. Intensive Care Med. 2020 May;46(5):888-906. doi: 10.1007/s00134-020-05980-0. Epub 2020 Mar 10. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32157357</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Kalil AC, Metersky ML, Klompas M, Muscedere J, Sweeney DA, Palmer LB, Napolitano LM, O'Grady NP, Bartlett JG, Carratalà J, El Solh AA, Ewig S, Fey PD, File TM Jr, Restrepo MI, Roberts JA, Waterer GW, Cruse P, Knight SL, Brozek JL. Executive Summary: Management of Adults With Hospital-acquired and Ventilator-associated Pneumonia: 2016 Clinical Practice Guidelines by the Infectious Diseases Society of America and the American Thoracic Society. Clin Infect Dis. 2016 Sep 1;63(5):575-82. doi: 10.1093/cid/ciw504. Erratum in: Clin Infect Dis. 2017 May 1;64(9):1298. Clin Infect Dis. 2017 Oct 1;65(7):1251.</citation>
    <PMID>27521441</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Torres A, Niederman MS, Chastre J, Ewig S, Fernandez-Vandellos P, Hanberger H, Kollef M, Li Bassi G, Luna CM, Martin-Loeches I, Paiva JA, Read RC, Rigau D, Timsit JF, Welte T, Wunderink R. International ERS/ESICM/ESCMID/ALAT guidelines for the management of hospital-acquired pneumonia and ventilator-associated pneumonia: Guidelines for the management of hospital-acquired pneumonia (HAP)/ventilator-associated pneumonia (VAP) of the European Respiratory Society (ERS), European Society of Intensive Care Medicine (ESICM), European Society of Clinical Microbiology and Infectious Diseases (ESCMID) and Asociación Latinoamericana del Tórax (ALAT). Eur Respir J. 2017 Sep 10;50(3). pii: 1700582. doi: 10.1183/13993003.00582-2017. Print 2017 Sep.</citation>
    <PMID>28890434</PMID>
  </reference>
  <verification_date>January 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 27, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 20, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 23, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 20, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 20, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 23, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia, Ventilator-Associated</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Pneumonia</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>Undecided</sharing_ipd>
    <ipd_description>Anonymized data will be shared upon written request to the study director</ipd_description>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

