<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2154">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04830943</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>COVID-NGF/AUH_SAH/2020</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04830943</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Cerebrolycin for Treatment of Covid-related Anosmia and Ageusia</brief_title>
  <official_title>The Effectiveness of Cerebrolycin for Treatment of Post-covid Olfactory and Gustatory Dysfunctions: A Pilot Study</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Assiut University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Assiut University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The loss of smell and taste is a prominent symptom of COVID-19. Studies found that patterns&#xD;
      of smell loss due to Covid-19 infection differ from that of other respiratory viruses being&#xD;
      much more profound in the Covid-19 patents and did not associate with runny, congested, or&#xD;
      blocked-up nose. The researchers suggest that smell and taste testing can be used for fast&#xD;
      COVID-19 screening. Studies found that the Covid-19 virus has similarities with severe acute&#xD;
      respiratory syndrome coronavirus (SARS-CoV), which has been reported to enter the brain, via&#xD;
      smell receptors in the nose. The sudden onset and relatively fast recovery in some patients&#xD;
      suggest that COVID-19 anosmia is not caused by damage to the central nervous system but&#xD;
      rather by the loss of smell information before it gets to the brain (smell receptors). They&#xD;
      also found that it has different behavior from other respiratory viruses as it causes&#xD;
      over-reaction of the immune system (or a cytokine storm). Trials to treat post-COVID anosmia&#xD;
      using local steroid applications, snifﬁng of strong odors or scents or use of different&#xD;
      vitamins (for several weeks to months) did not provide rapid, satisfactory or even&#xD;
      significant recovery of olfactory dysfunction. Fortunately, the olfactory neurons can&#xD;
      regenerate, however, studies reported variable prognoses, some patients recovered within&#xD;
      weeks which others may have persistent deficits for months or even a year. In this study, the&#xD;
      researchers hypothesize that cerebrolysin, a drug of neurotrophic and neuroprotective&#xD;
      properties, can be used to treat patients with persistent post-COVID anosmia or ageusia or&#xD;
      promote functional recovery of smell and taste deficits.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Initial descriptions of the COVID-19 pandemic have focused on its acute severe&#xD;
      manifestations. After several months, data have emerged about the mild disease and Post-COVID&#xD;
      syndrome. The diminished senses of smell (or hyposmia/anosmia) and taste (or&#xD;
      hypogeusia/ageusia) have been commonly reported in the pandemic. Hyposmia/anosmia and&#xD;
      hypogeusia/ageusia have also been reported with previous coronaviruses. In late March, the&#xD;
      professional society of Ear, Nose, and Throat (ENT) in the United Kingdom (UK) published an&#xD;
      advisory on evidence from South Korea, China, and Italy that signiﬁcant number of COVID-19&#xD;
      positive patients also lost smell and/or taste. Based also on several other reports which&#xD;
      reported that 66-88% of patients have lost smell and/or taste due to COVID-19 infection, the&#xD;
      American Academy of Otolaryngology-Head and Neck Surgery and World Health Organization (WHO)&#xD;
      have added anosmia and ageusia to the list of symptoms of COVID-19. The prognosis of such&#xD;
      deficits seems variable. Some reported recovery within few weeks; while many reported&#xD;
      persistence of deficits for several months or even more than a year after the onset of the&#xD;
      condition. Furthermore, some patients developed respiratory symptoms later after anosmia&#xD;
      while others remained asymptomatic. The exact mechanisms for these deficits are still under&#xD;
      research. In animal models, the investigators found that coronaviruses could impair the&#xD;
      olfactory neuroepithelium through the expression of angiotensin-converting enzyme type 2&#xD;
      (ACE2) in the sustentacular cells or damage the receptors. Treatment trials of post-COVID&#xD;
      anosmia included the application of nasal corticosteroids, regular snifﬁng of different odors&#xD;
      and strong scents, and treatment with antioxidants and vitamins. However, none was&#xD;
      therapeutically effective. Previous preclinical and clinical studies have shown that&#xD;
      treatment with neurotrophic polypeptides can promote neurological recovery for many&#xD;
      neurodegenerative and acquired nervous system diseases. As the olfactory neurons are capable&#xD;
      of regeneration, the researchers propose that treating patients with prolonged post-COVID&#xD;
      anosmia or ageusia with cerebrolysin, a drug of neurotrophic and neuroprotective properties&#xD;
      may promote recovery of olfactory and gustatory dysfunctions. Cerebrolysin is a mixture of&#xD;
      peptides purified from pig brains, including (and not limited to) brain-derived neurotrophic&#xD;
      factor (BDNF), glial cell line-derived neurotrophic factor (GDNF), nerve growth factor (NGF),&#xD;
      and ciliary neurotrophic factor (CNTF).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">August 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">March 30, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 28, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>The smell and taste questionnaire component of the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey (NHNES). And the modified Arabic translated and validated sniffin' sticks odor identification test was used for objective olfactory evaluations.</measure>
    <time_frame>The within subject change in sniffin' sticks test between baseline and 12- and -24 assessment time frame</time_frame>
    <description>The NHNES questions have been selected to characterize the variation, timing and associated-symptoms of both olfactory and gustatory systems. sniffin' sticks odor identification test, a total of 16 scents were presented via a pen device to patients for 3 seconds followed by a forced choice from 4 given options with a total possible score of 16 points. According to the results, patients were classified as normosmic (score between 12-16), hyposmic (score between 9-11) or anosmic (score 8 or below). The increase in at least 4 points from baseline indicates a clinically meaningful improvement. sniffin' sticks odor identification test has high internal reliability across a wide range of population.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The short modified version of the Questionnaire of Olfactory Disorders-Negative Statements (sQOD-NS)</measure>
    <time_frame>The within subject chage in QOD-NS between baseline and assessment frame</time_frame>
    <description>sQOD-NS is a seven-item patient-reported outcome questionnaire including social, eating, annoyance, and anxiety questions. Each item is rated on a scale of 0-3, with higher scores reflecting better olfactory-specific QOL. The total score ranges from 0 (severe impact on QoL) to 21 (no impact on QoL).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Globas Rating for smell (GRS)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 12 weeks, 18 weeks and 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>GRS is a single-item, global rating that asks the patient to rate his current sense of smell as follow: excellent, very good, good, fair, poor or absent</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>The Globas Rating for taste (GRT)</measure>
    <time_frame>6 weeks, 12 weeks, 18 weeks and 24 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>GRT is a single-item, global rating that asks the patient to rate his current sense of taste as follow: excellent, very good, good, fair, poor or absent</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>1</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19 Related Anosmia and Aguesia</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Olfactory and gustatory disorders after covid 19 infection</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Cerebrolysin Dose:10 ml ampoule (1ml contains 215.2 mg cerebrolysin) once daily through intramuscular injection five times per week, for a total of 20 treatments (for 4 weeks), after which the cycle was repeated again for at least 8 more weeks.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Cerebrolysin</intervention_name>
    <description>Cerebrolysin will be prescribed in a dose of 10 ml ampoule once daily through intramuscular injection (1ml contains 215.2 mg cerebrolysin) for five times per week, for a total of 20 treatments (for 4 weeks), after which the cycle was repeated again for at least 8 more weeks.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Olfactory and gustatory disorders after covid 19 infection</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Neurotropic factors</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  A random sample of at least 100 adults with sudden hyposmia/anosmia and/or&#xD;
             hypoageusia/ageusia during COVID-19 pandemics which persist till the onset of the&#xD;
             study. Persisting symptoms were defined by the presence at day 30 or day 60 of&#xD;
             anosmia/ageusia.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients who experienced persistent olfactory and/or smell manifestations after&#xD;
             recovery from their initial acute COVID-19 illness.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Prior neurologic, medical or psychiatric disease.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Other known infection at onset&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nasal congestion&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Nasal polyps&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Surgery or head trauma or radiation for head and neck cancers as may result in injury&#xD;
             to the nerves that control smell&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Exposure to toxic chemicals (such as pesticides and solvents)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cocaine or other drug abuse&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>20 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>60 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Sherifa A Hamed, M.D.</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Assiut University, Faculty of Medicine</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assiut University Hospitals, Faculty of Medicine</name>
      <address>
        <city>Assiut</city>
        <zip>71516</zip>
        <country>Egypt</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Egypt</country>
  </location_countries>
  <reference>
    <citation>Chachkhiani D, Soliman MY, Barua D, Isakadze M, Villemarette-Pittman NR, Devier DJ, Lovera JF. Neurological complications in a predominantly African American sample of COVID-19 predict worse outcomes during hospitalization. Clin Neurol Neurosurg. 2020 Oct;197:106173. doi: 10.1016/j.clineuro.2020.106173. Epub 2020 Aug 25.</citation>
    <PMID>32877769</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Shrestha GS, Khanal S, Sharma S, Nepal G. COVID-19: Current Understanding of Pathophysiology. J Nepal Health Res Counc. 2020 Nov 13;18(3):351-359. doi: 10.33314/jnhrc.v18i3.3028.</citation>
    <PMID>33210623</PMID>
  </reference>
  <reference>
    <citation>Veinbergs I, Mante M, Mallory M, Masliah E. Neurotrophic effects of Cerebrolysin in animal models of excitotoxicity. J Neural Transm Suppl. 2000;59:273-80.</citation>
    <PMID>10961439</PMID>
  </reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Lechien JR, Chiesa-Estomba CM, De Siati DR, Horoi M, Le Bon SD, Rodriguez A, Dequanter D, Blecic S, El Afia F, Distinguin L, Chekkoury-Idrissi Y, Hans S, Delgado IL, Calvo-Henriquez C, Lavigne P, Falanga C, Barillari MR, Cammaroto G, Khalife M, Leich P, Souchay C, Rossi C, Journe F, Hsieh J, Edjlali M, Carlier R, Ris L, Lovato A, De Filippis C, Coppee F, Fakhry N, Ayad T, Saussez S. Olfactory and gustatory dysfunctions as a clinical presentation of mild-to-moderate forms of the coronavirus disease (COVID-19): a multicenter European study. Eur Arch Otorhinolaryngol. 2020 Aug;277(8):2251-2261. doi: 10.1007/s00405-020-05965-1. Epub 2020 Apr 6.</citation>
    <PMID>32253535</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>December 24, 2020</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Assiut University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Sherifa Ahmed Hamed</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Professor of Neurology</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>; anosmia</keyword>
  <keyword>; ageusia</keyword>
  <keyword>; cerebrolysin</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Olfaction Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Cerebrolysin</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

