<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="257">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04832919</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>3P30DA011041-23S1</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04832919</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>A Nurse-Community Health Worker-Family Partnership Model: Addressing Uptake of COVID-19 Testing and Control Measures</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Nurse-Community Health Worker-Family Partnership Model to Increase COVID19 Testing in Urban Underserved and Vulnerable Communities</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>New York University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>New York University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>Yes</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Historically, health disparities in the US are concentrated among underserved communities and&#xD;
      socially vulnerable populations. The disproportionate COVID-19 related morbidity and&#xD;
      mortality in communities of color and socioeconomic disadvantage acutely highlight this&#xD;
      persistent public health problem, drawing attention to the urgent need for more equitable&#xD;
      reach of testing, prevention, and control measures. The proposed research addresses this need&#xD;
      using a 2-arm randomized controlled trial (RCT) that will evaluate the effectiveness of the&#xD;
      Nurse-Community Health Worker (CHW)-Family Partnership intervention in promoting COVID-19&#xD;
      testing uptake, adoption of COVID control measures, and mutual aid capacity at the household&#xD;
      level in an underserved and vulnerable population disproportionately affected by COVID-19.&#xD;
      Enrolled households will be randomly assigned to either the intervention group where families&#xD;
      will receive the Nurse-CHW-Family Partnership intervention including the offer of in-home&#xD;
      testing and referral to seasonal influenza vaccination services, or the treatment-as-usual&#xD;
      control group, which will be used to measure actual testing rates among public housing&#xD;
      residents in relation to participant and household characteristics. The study hypothesis is&#xD;
      that the Nurse-CHW-Family Partnership intervention will improve household-level COVID-19&#xD;
      testing uptake, adoption of COVID control measures, and mutual aid capacity relative to the&#xD;
      treatment-as-usual control. related to COVID-19 mitigation in other high-risk settings.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      We will recruit and follow a randomly-chosen sample of NYCHA public housing residents in the&#xD;
      proposed target community who meet multiple criteria for being considered vulnerable or&#xD;
      underserved. Our study will address knowledge gaps regarding COVID-19 testing, treatment, and&#xD;
      household prevention strategies, and generate new knowledge related to the epidemiology of&#xD;
      COVID-19 in these communities. Working with our community partners, we will create an&#xD;
      acceptable and feasible intervention and testing infrastructure in advance of the influenza&#xD;
      season, with a view toward designing best practices for sustainable COVID-19 testing,&#xD;
      prevention, and preparedness for vaccination trials. We will implement a 2-arm RCT that will&#xD;
      evaluate the effectiveness of the Nurse-CHW-Family Partnership Intervention in promoting&#xD;
      COVID testing uptake, adoption of COVID control measures, and household mutual aid capacity.&#xD;
      We will recruit members of randomly selected households in their homes using area sampling&#xD;
      methods used with excellent results in our previous research in the target community.&#xD;
      Participants will complete a baseline assessment and the entire household will be randomized&#xD;
      to either the experimental or a treatment-as-usual control condition, which will be used to&#xD;
      measure actual testing rates among public housing residents in relation to participant and&#xD;
      household characteristics. The baseline sample will include 270 households, and 810&#xD;
      individual household members, randomized in a 2:1 ratio, intervention:control. Families will&#xD;
      complete follow-up assessments at 6 and 9 months following the baseline. In-home testing and&#xD;
      referral to seasonal influenza vaccination services will be offered to the intervention&#xD;
      group; whereas the control group will receive treatment as usual at multiple NYC Department&#xD;
      of Health COVID-19 testing sites that are within walking distance of each of the three&#xD;
      housing complexes. Test acceptance will be recorded, and incentives will be paid for study&#xD;
      visits, not for testing.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">April 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Prevention</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Household COVID-19 Testing Uptake</measure>
    <time_frame>Delayed Follow-Up (9 Months)</time_frame>
    <description>All medical services delivered by nurses during home-visits (such as COVID-19 test administration) will be carefully documented by the investigative team. At the time of the assessment, we will obtain self-reported information COVID-19 testing uptake by study participants in the treatment and control groups.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Symptoms, Diagnoses, and Testing Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Delayed Follow-Up (9 Months)</time_frame>
    <description>An adapted form of the (PhenX Toolkit) COVID-19 Symptoms, Diagnoses, and Testing Scale will be used to measure COVID-19 testing. Respondents will be asked questions regarding whether they or their family/household have had symptoms for COVID, their COVID-19 testing history, and whether they have tested positive for COVID-19.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Avoidant Behaviors Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Delayed Follow-Up (9 Months)</time_frame>
    <description>An adapted version of the COVID-19 Avoidant Behaviors Scale (PhenX Toolkit) will be used to measure the secondary study outcome of COVID-19 control measure uptake. Respondents will be asked regarding their engagement in behaviors associated with COVID-19 exposure (e.g., &quot;Had close contact (within 6 feet) with people who do not live with you. [Yes/No/Unsure];&quot; &quot;Gone out to a bar, club, or other place where people gather. [Yes/No/Unsure]) and questions regarding their uptake of COVID-19 control (e.g., &quot;Worn a mask or other face covering. [Yes/No];&quot; &quot;Washed your hands with soap or used hand sanitizer several times per day. [Yes/No]).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Seasonal Influenza Vaccine Uptake</measure>
    <time_frame>Delayed follow up (9 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Referral to seasonal influenza vaccination services by study nurses to intervention group participants will be carefully documented by the investigative team. At the time of the delayed assessment, we will obtain self-reported information and documentation of influenza vaccine uptake by study participants in the treatment as usual control group.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Improved Household &amp; Family Mutual Aid</measure>
    <time_frame>Delayed follow up (9 months)</time_frame>
    <description>A set of measures will assess the degree of mutual support, strengthened cohesiveness, and families' abilities to adjust to the COVID-19 pandemic, as evidenced by the reported overall impact of COVID-19 on family dynamics and relationships, psychological distress, food and housing insecurity, substance use, and sexual behavior.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Household Environment Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Delayed follow up (9 months)</time_frame>
    <description>The COVID-19 Household Environment Scale will be used to measure the secondary study outcome household/family mutual aid. The scale measures household togetherness and conflict. To assess household togetherness, participants are asked to rate, on a 7-point scale, how much more or less togetherness there was (as compared to before COVID-19) regarding 15 topics (e.g., &quot;Engaging in conversation;&quot; &quot;Helping others together&quot;). To assess household conflict, participants are asked to rate, on a 7-point scale, how much more or less conflict there was (as compared to before COVID-19) about 15 topics (e.g., &quot;Home maintenance;&quot; &quot;Decisions about visitors to the home&quot;).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Household COVID-19 Testing Uptake</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate follow up (6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>All medical services delivered by nurses during home-visits (such as COVID-19 test administration) will be carefully documented by the investigative team. At the time of the immediate assessment, we will obtain self-reported information COVID-19 testing uptake by study participants in the treatment and control groups.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Symptoms, Diagnoses, and Testing Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate follow up (6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>An adapted form of the (PhenX Toolkit) COVID-19 Symptoms, Diagnoses, and Testing Scale will be used to measure COVID-19 testing. Respondents will be asked questions regarding whether they or their family/household have had symptoms for COVID, their COVID-19 testing history, and whether they have tested positive for COVID-19.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Avoidant Behaviors Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate follow up (6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>An adapted version of the COVID-19 Avoidant Behaviors Scale (PhenX Toolkit) will be used to measure the secondary study outcome of COVID-19 control measure uptake. Respondents will be asked regarding their engagement in behaviors associated with COVID-19 exposure (e.g., &quot;Had close contact (within 6 feet) with people who do not live with you. [Yes/No/Unsure];&quot; &quot;Gone out to a bar, club, or other place where people gather. [Yes/No/Unsure]) and questions regarding their uptake of COVID-19 control measures (e.g., &quot;Worn a mask or other face covering. [Yes/No];&quot; &quot;Washed your hands with soap or used hand sanitizer several times per day. [Yes/No]).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Seasonal Influenza Vaccine Uptake</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate follow up (6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>Referral to seasonal influenza vaccination services by study nurses to intervention group participants will be carefully documented by the investigative team. At the time of the immediate assessment, we will obtain self-reported information and documentation of influenza vaccine uptake by study participants in the treatment as usual control group.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Improved Household &amp; Family Mutual Aid</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate follow up (6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>A set of measures will assess the degree of mutual support, strengthened cohesiveness, and families' abilities to adjust to the COVID-19 pandemic, as evidenced by the reported overall impact of COVID-19 on family dynamics and relationships, psychological distress, food and housing insecurity, substance use, and sexual behavior.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Household Environment Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Immediate follow up (6 months)</time_frame>
    <description>The COVID-19 Household Environment Scale will be used to measure the secondary study outcome household/family mutual aid. The scale measures household togetherness and conflict. To assess household togetherness, participants are asked to rate, on a 7-point scale, how much more or less togetherness there was (as compared to before COVID-19) regarding 15 topics (e.g., &quot;Engaging in conversation;&quot; &quot;Helping others together&quot;). To assess household conflict, participants are asked to rate, on a 7-point scale, how much more or less conflict there was (as compared to before COVID-19) about 15 topics (e.g., &quot;Home maintenance;&quot; &quot;Decisions about visitors to the home&quot;).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">810</enrollment>
  <condition>COVID-19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Nurse-Community Health Worker-Family Partnership</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The experimental arm will receive the Nurse-Community Health Worker-Family Partnership Intervention</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Standard of Care</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>No Intervention</arm_group_type>
    <description>The control arm will receive standard access to NYC Department of Health COVID-19 testing sites and standard COVID-19 public health messaging</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Nurse-Community-Family Partnership Intervention</intervention_name>
    <description>Nurses conduct home visits on a monthly basis for the first five months post-baseline. During visits, nurses emphasize the importance of infection control measures and, jointly with household members, develop and follow-up on the implementation of an infection control plan tailored to the unique circumstances of the household. Nurses deliver training on infection control skills necessary for optimal implementation of the plan. Nurses offer at-home SARS-CoV-2 testing to all members of the household. Nurses conduct triage, medical case management, monitoring, and follow-up of individuals identified to have COVID-19 or any other acute health emergencies. CHWs conduct visits on a bi-weekly basis for the first five months post-baseline. CHWs deliver healthcare information and medical mistrust counseling in a culturally relevant and linguistically appropriate fashion; and provide social support, navigate household members to social welfare/vocational/economic/psychosocial services.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Nurse-Community Health Worker-Family Partnership</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Residence in one of the public housing complexes in Mott Haven, South Bronx&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  English or Spanish-speaking&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Age 10 years or older&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Willing and able to provide informed consent or assent&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Non-resident of one of the public housing complexes in Mott Haven, South Bronx&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Neither English nor Spanish speaker&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Younger than 10 years old, unless household index case tests antigen positive. In this&#xD;
             instance, all members of family will be included.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Unwilling or unable to provide informed consent or assent&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>10 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Vincent M Guilamo-Ramos, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>212-998-4306</phone>
    <email>vincent.ramos@nyu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Holly Hagan, PhD</last_name>
    <phone>212-998-5221</phone>
    <email>hh50@nyu.edu</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 2, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 6, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 2, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 2, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 6, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19 testing</keyword>
  <keyword>Behavioral COVID-19 Mitigation Measures</keyword>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

