<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="196">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04775563</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>IRE-3639</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04775563</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>COVID-19 Vaccine Hesitancy Among Rheumatic Diseases Patients</brief_title>
  <official_title>COVID-19 Vaccine Hesitancy Among Mexican Rheumatic Diseases Patients</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>National Institute of Medical Sciences and Nutrition, Salvador Zubiran</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>National Institute of Medical Sciences and Nutrition, Salvador Zubiran</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Rheumatological diseases (RD) are an important group of different clinical entities and&#xD;
      specific diseases that affect a significant proportion of the world population. In Mexico,&#xD;
      the RD have a relevant representation in the adult population. COVID-19 vaccination has been&#xD;
      proposed as a measure to contain the COVID-19 pandemic. The vaccines have been shown to be&#xD;
      effective and reasonably safe in the population without significant risk factors, which has&#xD;
      allowed their approval to attend the health emergency. At present, there is little scientific&#xD;
      information that allows a solid recommendation on vaccination for COVID-19 in patients with&#xD;
      RD, although most authorities have spoken in favor of vaccination in immunocompromised&#xD;
      patients, as are a relevant number of patients with RD. However, it is desirable to achieve&#xD;
      herd immunity to facilitate the impact of vaccination on the transmission of SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
      infection. For this, it is required that around 70% -80% of the target population be&#xD;
      vaccinated, which implies not only access to the vaccine but also accepting to be vaccinated.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Vaccine hesitancy is defined as the delay or refusal to accept the vaccine when it is&#xD;
      available by health services. Sometimes, they conceptualize it as a continuum and also&#xD;
      includes the high demand from the population for the vaccine; In this continuum, there are&#xD;
      variations in acceptance and rejection and multiple possible combinations, from acceptance&#xD;
      with great concern about the decision to rejection of certain vaccines but not others. It is&#xD;
      a complex, contextual, changing phenomenon, specific for each vaccine and the referred&#xD;
      disease and probably influenced by cultural determinants.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The objectives are:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. - To measure the phenomenon of vaccine hesitancy in Mexican patients with RD from two&#xD;
           Health Institutions in Mexico City.&#xD;
&#xD;
        2. - Translate and adapt the &quot;Oxford Covid-19 vaccine hesitancy scale&quot; to patients with RD&#xD;
           and validate this version in a population of patients with RD from two Health&#xD;
           Institutions in Mexico City&#xD;
&#xD;
        3. Explore factors associated with the phenomenon of vaccine hesitancy.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">February 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">October 1, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">August 30, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Other</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Cross-Sectional</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Measure the phenomenon of vaccine hesitancy among rheumatic diseases patients</measure>
    <time_frame>At study inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Identify the percentage of patients with rheumatic diseases that present COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy using the instrument developed by Freeman et al (translation, cultural adaptation, and validation performed)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Identify factors associated with COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy among rheumatic diseases patients</measure>
    <time_frame>At study inclusion</time_frame>
    <description>Identify factors associated with COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy among rheumatic diseases patients using an instrument locally development</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">740</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Rheumatic diseases outpatients</arm_group_label>
    <description>All the rheumatic diseases outpatients from the National Institute of Medical Sciences and General Hospital.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy scale in rheumatic diseases</intervention_name>
    <description>The instrument was developed by Freeman et al, prior to its application, translation, cultural adaptation, and validation were performed.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Rheumatic diseases outpatients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>COVID-19 vaccine hesitancy associated factors</intervention_name>
    <description>The instrument includes questions about the doctor-patient relationship, perception of the COVID-19 vaccine, perception of risk of COVID-19 infection, perception of the severity of the pandemic in Mexico, perception of the severity of their rheumatic disease, perception of the control of comorbidities, perception of the intensity of the immunosuppressive treatment, positioning of the patient towards vaccines for COVID-19</description>
    <arm_group_label>Rheumatic diseases outpatients</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        All the rheumatic diseases outpatients from the National Institute of Medical Sciences and&#xD;
        Nutrition and General Hospital.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a rheumatic disease diagnosis according to their primary rheumatologist&#xD;
             who agree to participate&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Patients with a not confirmed rheumatic disease&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>99 Years</maximum_age>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Instituto Nacional de Ciencias Médicas y Nutrición Salvador Zubirán</name>
      <address>
        <city>Mexico City</city>
        <zip>14080</zip>
        <country>Mexico</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Virginia Pascual-Ramos, MD</last_name>
      <phone>00525555734111</phone>
      <phone_ext>533</phone_ext>
      <email>virtichu@gmail.com</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Mexico</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 1, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 1, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>National Institute of Medical Sciences and Nutrition, Salvador Zubiran</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Virginia Pascual Ramos</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>PI</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>vaccines, rheumatic diseases</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Rheumatic Diseases</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Collagen Diseases</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <intervention_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Vaccines</mesh_term>
  </intervention_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

