<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="5563">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04778930</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>SCosta</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04778930</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Physical Therapy for Improving Functionality, Gait and Participation in Cerebral Palsy</brief_title>
  <acronym>FIMAPACE</acronym>
  <official_title>Effectiveness of Physical Therapy for Improving the Functionality, Gait and Participation in the Environment in Children and Adolescents With Cerebral Palsy: Randomized Clinical Trial</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Alcala</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Alcala</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      Cerebral Palsy is a non-progressive nature lesion of the Central Nervous System, with a wide&#xD;
      spectrum of impairments at body structure and function, which has a great impact at activity&#xD;
      and participation in the environment. The intensity of participation is influenced by&#xD;
      multiple factors, among which independent mobility stands out, through the functional&#xD;
      activity of walking. Children and adolescents with Cerebral Palsy present limitations in gait&#xD;
      function both at the level of body structure and activity and improving these aspects is one&#xD;
      of the main therapeutic objectives in their treatment.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Physical Therapy interventions based on task learning and achieving objectives have proven to&#xD;
      be effective in improving functional skills, gait and participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Due to COVID-19, interventions have been interrupted or reduced in periodicity. For this&#xD;
      reason, it is essential to provide alternatives to Physical Therapy interventions for&#xD;
      children and adolescents with Cerebral Palsy. Telehealth may play an important role both in&#xD;
      maintaining function and in monitoring individuals, in addition to bringing the Physical&#xD;
      Therapist closer to the natural environment of the child / adolescent through digital&#xD;
      platforms.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Therefore the aim of this clinical trial is to verify that a Physiotherapy intervention that&#xD;
      combines face-to-face sessions with telecare in natural settings is effective in improving&#xD;
      the functional activity of walking and participation in the environment of children and&#xD;
      adolescents with Cerebral Palsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The study population are children and adolescents diagnosed with Cerebral Palsy; ages 6-17&#xD;
      years old. The sample of 66 subjects (33 in each group) will be recruited in care centers for&#xD;
      children and adolescents with Cerebral Palsy in Alcalá de Henares.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The outcome variables are: participation in the environment (Spanish version of the&#xD;
      Children's Assessment of Participation and Enjoyment - CAPE), gait speed (10-meter walk test&#xD;
      - 10MM), gait endurance (6-minute walk test - 6MM), gross motor function (Spanish version of&#xD;
      the Gross Motor Function Measure - GMFM-SP) and static and dynamic balance (Spanish version&#xD;
      of the Pediatric Balance Scale - PBS). They will be collected in three moments: baseline&#xD;
      assessment (V0); intermediate assessment (V1) at 6 weeks at the end of each group&#xD;
      intervention; Final assessment (V2) 3 months after baseline.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Group A Physical Therapy intervention group will receive 18 sessions, 3 times a week, for 6&#xD;
      consecutive weeks; on the one hand, 12 face-to-face sessions of approximately 90 minutes&#xD;
      duration, in which the Physical Therapy treatment will be carried out based on training of&#xD;
      specific tasks directed to objectives and training of gait with a treadmill; In addition, a&#xD;
      therapeutic education program will be carried out, with 6 telehealth sessions, which will&#xD;
      include action observation therapy. Subjects in Group B (control group) will receive their&#xD;
      usual Physiotherapy intervention regimen for 6 weeks at their referral center and the same&#xD;
      telehealth Therapeutic Education program of the intervention group. The face-to-face sessions&#xD;
      of the intervention group will be carried out in the Physiotherapy Teaching Unit of the&#xD;
      University of Alcalá, and the telehealth sessions of the Therapeutic Education program of&#xD;
      both groups will be carried out by remote assistance through a digital platform. All will be&#xD;
      carried out by specialist Physiotherapists, members of the research team.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Statistical Analysis: After assessments, the data will be analyzed to verify the results. It&#xD;
      will be done: descriptive analysis of the sample (means, medians, standard deviations and&#xD;
      quartiles; normality test; frequency distributions): homogeneity check of the groups&#xD;
      (t-Student or Mann Withney's U - quantitative variables; Chi square or F of Fisher -&#xD;
      categorical variables); effectiveness analysis (parametric tests or not of paired samples;&#xD;
      multivariate models to adjust for possible confounding factors; multivariate model of&#xD;
      repeated measures to evaluate the result of the intervention. The statistical package&#xD;
      Statistical Package for the Social Sciences software (25 version , SPSS Inc, Chicago, USA) or&#xD;
      the statistical package STATA MP v14.2 (StataCo&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">September 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">December 31, 2022</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">July 31, 2022</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>Single (Outcomes Assessor)</masking>
    <masking_description>As masking techniques, the persons responsible for the assessment of the subjects and the data collection, the random assignment and the intervention in each group will be independent from each other.</masking_description>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in baseline Environmental participation at 6 weeks and 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Spanish version of Children's Assessment of Participation and Enjoyment (CAPE)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in baseline Gait speed at 6 weeks and 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>10 meter walk Test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in baseline Gait endurance at 6 weeks and 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>6 minutes walk test</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in baseline Gross Motor Function at 6 weeks and 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Spanish version of Gross Motor Function Measure (GMFM-SP)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Change in baseline Static and Dynamic Balance at 6 weeks and 3 months</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline assessment</time_frame>
    <description>Spanish version of Pediatric Balance Scale (PBS)</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">66</enrollment>
  <condition>Physical Therapy</condition>
  <condition>Cerebral Palsy</condition>
  <condition>Therapeutic Education</condition>
  <condition>Telehealth</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group A_Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>It will consist of 18 sessions, 3 times a week, for 6 consecutive weeks; on the one hand, 12 face-to-face sessions of approximately 90 minutes duration, in which the Physical Therapy treatment will be carried out based on training of specific tasks directed to objectives and training of gait with a treadmill; In addition, a therapeutic education program will be carried out, with 6 telehealth sessions lasting approximately 60 minutes, which will include action observation activities. The face-to-face sessions will be held at the Physical Therapy Teaching Unit at University of Alcalá, and the telehealth sessions of the Therapeutic Education program will be carried out by remote assistance through a digital platform. All will be carried out by specialist Physical Therapists, members of the research team.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Group B_Control Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Experimental</arm_group_type>
    <description>The subjects in this group will receive their usual Physical Therapy intervention regimen for 6 weeks at their referral center and the same telehealth Therapeutic Education program of the intervention group.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Physical Therapy</intervention_name>
    <description>FACE-TO FACE SESSIONS: approximately 90 minutes of Goal-directed training (activities for the activation of the muscles of the trunk, pelvis and lower limbs; and training of activities will be carried out in a functional and meaningful context, aimed at specific functional objectives, according to the interests of each participant and agreed with the participants and their families) and gait training on the treadmill for 20 minutes.&#xD;
TELEHEALTH THERAPEUTIC EDUCATION PROGRAM: Session 1: Concept and causes of CP, together with the general objectives and guidelines of the program. Session 2: The family-centered model; Sessions 3, 4 and 5: Actions Observation Therapy; Session 6: Program Evaluation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A_Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Therapeutic Education</other_name>
    <other_name>Family centered model</other_name>
    <other_name>Action Observation Therapy</other_name>
    <other_name>Goal-directed training</other_name>
    <other_name>Treadmill</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>THERAPEUTIC EDUCATION PROGRAM</intervention_name>
    <description>TELEHEALTH THERAPEUTIC EDUCATION PROGRAM: Session 1: Concept and causes of CP, together with the general objectives and guidelines of the program. Session 2: The family-centered model; Sessions 3, 4 and 5: Actions Observation Therapy; Session 6: Program Evaluation.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Group A_Intervention Group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_label>Group B_Control Group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  GMFCS (II-III); MACS (I-III); CFCS (I-III)&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  having undergone surgery on lower limbs in the 6 months prior to his participation in&#xD;
             the study; having surgery during the study; inability to follow the planned program&#xD;
             due to moving tu other city or other reason.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>6 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>17 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Novak I, Morgan C, Fahey M, Finch-Edmondson M, Galea C, Hines A, Langdon K, Namara MM, Paton MC, Popat H, Shore B, Khamis A, Stanton E, Finemore OP, Tricks A, Te Velde A, Dark L, Morton N, Badawi N. State of the Evidence Traffic Lights 2019: Systematic Review of Interventions for Preventing and Treating Children with Cerebral Palsy. Curr Neurol Neurosci Rep. 2020 Feb 21;20(2):3. doi: 10.1007/s11910-020-1022-z.</citation>
    <PMID>32086598</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Sellier E, McIntyre S, Smithers-Sheedy H, Platt MJ; SCPE and ACPR Groups. European and Australian Cerebral Palsy Surveillance Networks Working Together for Collaborative Research. Neuropediatrics. 2020 Apr;51(2):105-112. doi: 10.1055/s-0039-3402003. Epub 2020 Jan 7.</citation>
    <PMID>31910452</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Schiariti V, Mahdi S, Bölte S. International Classification of Functioning, Disability and Health Core Sets for cerebral palsy, autism spectrum disorder, and attention-deficit-hyperactivity disorder. Dev Med Child Neurol. 2018 Sep;60(9):933-941. doi: 10.1111/dmcn.13922. Epub 2018 May 30.</citation>
    <PMID>29845609</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Chakraborty S, Nandy A, Kesar TM. Gait deficits and dynamic stability in children and adolescents with cerebral palsy: A systematic review and meta-analysis. Clin Biomech (Bristol, Avon). 2020 Jan;71:11-23. doi: 10.1016/j.clinbiomech.2019.09.005. Epub 2019 Oct 18.</citation>
    <PMID>31677546</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Toovey R, Bernie C, Harvey AR, McGinley JL, Spittle AJ. Task-specific gross motor skills training for ambulant school-aged children with cerebral palsy: a systematic review. BMJ Paediatr Open. 2017 Aug 11;1(1):e000078. doi: 10.1136/bmjpo-2017-000078. eCollection 2017.</citation>
    <PMID>29637118</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <results_reference>
    <citation>Han YG, Yun CK. Effectiveness of treadmill training on gait function in children with cerebral palsy: meta-analysis. J Exerc Rehabil. 2020 Feb 26;16(1):10-19. doi: 10.12965/jer.1938748.374. eCollection 2020 Feb. Review.</citation>
    <PMID>32161730</PMID>
  </results_reference>
  <verification_date>February 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 24, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 28, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 28, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 28, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 3, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>University of Alcala</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Soraya Pacheco da Costa</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>University Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Physical Therapy</keyword>
  <keyword>Cerebral Palsy</keyword>
  <keyword>Telehealth</keyword>
  <keyword>Therapeutic Education</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Paralysis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Cerebral Palsy</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

