<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4852">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04836039</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>E-10840098-772.02-2682</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04836039</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Rehabilitation Experiences of Physiotherapists in Covid-19 Outbreak</brief_title>
  <official_title>Evaluation of Rehabilitation Experiences of Physiotherapists in Covid-19 Outbreak</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Medipol University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Medipol University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to evaluate the process experienced by physiotherapists while&#xD;
      providing rehabilitation services during the epidemic and to investigate the procedures&#xD;
      adopted by physiotherapists who are currently working. In addition, by analyzing the effects&#xD;
      of both the pandemic and the clinical and educational organizations in the Physiotherapy and&#xD;
      Rehabilitation Clinics where physiotherapists were working during the COVID-19 epidemic, the&#xD;
      needs arising after the pandemic can be reported. Assessments will be carried out by&#xD;
      researcher physiotherapists through a questionnaire based on research and examples in the&#xD;
      literature, and scales measuring anxiety, depression and stress levels. The measurement tool&#xD;
      will be the online survey application.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The aim of this study is to evaluate the process experienced by physiotherapists while&#xD;
      providing rehabilitation services during the epidemic and to investigate the procedures&#xD;
      adopted by physiotherapists who are currently working.&#xD;
&#xD;
      In addition, by analyzing the effects of both the pandemic and the clinical and educational&#xD;
      organizations in the Physiotherapy and Rehabilitation Clinics where physiotherapists were&#xD;
      working during the COVID-19 epidemic, the needs arising after the pandemic can be reported.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Assessments will be carried out by researcher physiotherapists through a questionnaire based&#xD;
      on research and examples in the literature, and scales measuring anxiety, depression and&#xD;
      stress levels. The measurement tool will be the online survey application.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Data collection is planned to take place in February-March 2021.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Surveys will be distributed via WhatsApp, e-mail, social media links. This questionnaire was&#xD;
      sent to 3 physiotherapists and subjected to a pre-test. This questionnaire is about the&#xD;
      following situations and contains 37 questions:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Information on employment status: In this section, physiotherapists' name-surname, gender,&#xD;
      age, professional practice experience (years), generally applied physiotherapy subgroup (more&#xD;
      than one can be selected), whether they are self-employed or employees, and the status of&#xD;
      performing face-to-face clinical practices will be questioned. If so, it will be questioned&#xD;
      which protection measures have been applied.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Information about tele-rehabilitation practices: In this section, it will be questioned&#xD;
      whether physiotherapists start to follow their patients remotely, if they are, in what way&#xD;
      they do it, whether the number of weekly sessions continues, and whether the amount collected&#xD;
      is the same as the face-to-face amount.&#xD;
&#xD;
      General information about COVID 19 rehabilitation: In this section, did the departments where&#xD;
      physiotherapists work returned to COVID 19 services, did they work in COVID 19 units,&#xD;
      rehabilitation approaches in COVID 19 patients, protocol and / or guidelines on exercises for&#xD;
      rehabilitation management and treatment of COVID 19 patients. material development /&#xD;
      implementation status will be questioned.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The impact of the pandemic on the health and teaching activities of physiotherapists and the&#xD;
      sustainability of clinical / thesis studies during this period will be questioned.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Finally, the CES Depression Scale (Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression Scale, CES-D)&#xD;
      will be used to determine depression level, the Generalized Anxiety Disorder 7 (GAD-7) Test&#xD;
      will be used to evaluate generalized anxiety level, Perceived Stress Scale (PSS) will be used&#xD;
      to determine stress level.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">January 27, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">February 27, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">February 27, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Retrospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>A questionnaire created by research physiotherapists based on researches and examples in the literature.</measure>
    <time_frame>The evaluation will take place in one interview (the interview will take 30 minutes)</time_frame>
    <description>Participants will be evaluated by applying a questionnaire and scales created by the researcher physiotherapists based on the researches and examples in the literature.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of depression level with Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>The evaluation will take place in one interview (the interview will take 30 minutes)</time_frame>
    <description>The Center for Epidemiologic Studies Depression Scale will be used to determine depression level. The scale consists of 20 questions in the form of a self-report that measure the emotional state of the person in depression, perceptions and behaviors towards depression. 4-point Likert type questionnaire with 0-60 points range is encoded in 0-3 points range.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of anxiety level with Generalized Anxiety Disorder 7 Test</measure>
    <time_frame>The evaluation will take place in one interview (the interview will take 30 minutes)</time_frame>
    <description>The Generalized Anxiety Disorder 7 test will be used to determine anxiety level. It is a 7-item four-point Likert (0 = none, 1 = many days, 2 = more than half of the days, 3 = almost every day), which evaluates the experiences asked in the scale items in the last 2 weeks. The total scores obtained from the scale are 5, 10, and 15 cut-off points for mild, moderate, and severe anxiety, respectively.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Assessment of stress level with Perceived Stress Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>The evaluation will take place in one interview (the interview will take 30 minutes)</time_frame>
    <description>Perceived Stress Scale will be used to determine stress level. Participants rate how often their lives were seen as unpredictable, uncontrollable, and overly intense during the previous month on the 5-point Likert scale (0 = Never, 4 = Very often). Total scores range from 0 to 40, with higher scores indicating a higher perceived stress level.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>1</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Actual">400</enrollment>
  <condition>Physical Therapy</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Physiotherapists</arm_group_label>
    <description>Individuals between the ages of 22-65 who continue to work as a self-employed or employee physiotherapist.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>A questionnaire and scales.</intervention_name>
    <description>Participants will be evaluated by applying a questionnaire and scales created by the researcher physiotherapists based on the researches and examples in the literature.</description>
    <arm_group_label>Physiotherapists</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Individuals between the ages of 22-65 who continue to work as a self-employed or employee&#xD;
        physiotherapist.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Individuals between the ages of 22-65 who continue to work as a self-employed or employee&#xD;
        physiotherapist.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Not meeting the inclusion criteria&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>22 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gülay Aras Bayram, asAss. Prof.</last_name>
    <role>Study Chair</role>
    <affiliation>Medipol University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Medipol University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Istanbul</city>
        <state>Beykoz</state>
        <zip>34815</zip>
        <country>Turkey</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Turkey</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 2, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 5, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 5, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 5, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 8, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Medipol University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Pınar Ciddi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Assistant Professor</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

