<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4620">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04797936</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>BERI_UA_IMU_2020_000003751</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04797936</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>BNO 1030 Extract (Imupret) in the Treatment of Mild Forms of COVID-19</brief_title>
  <official_title>A Randomized, Open-label, Multicentre, Comparative Study of Therapeutic Efficacy, Safety, and Tolerability of BNO 1030 Extract, in the Treatment of Mild Forms of COVID-19</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Ivano-Frankivsk National Medical University</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Ivano-Frankivsk National Medical University</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      According to WHO (World Health Organisation) data, about 40% of patients with COVID-19&#xD;
      (Corona Virus SARS-CoV-2) have a mild course of the disease, namely, cases of mild course are&#xD;
      of great danger from the point of view of the spread of infection, since the main source of&#xD;
      infection is a sick person. The mild course of COVID-19 is characterized by a number of&#xD;
      nonspecific symptoms: fever, cough, sore throat, nasal congestion, malaise, headache, muscle&#xD;
      pain. Evidence has emerged of loss of smell as a symptom of COVID-19 infection.&#xD;
      Anosmia/hyposmia in the absence of other respiratory diseases, such as allergic rhinitis,&#xD;
      acute rhinosinusitis, or chronic rhinosinusitis, are considered as a clinical marker of&#xD;
      COVID-19 infection in a pandemic.For people with a mild course of the disease, WHO recommends&#xD;
      providing home care, and the recommendations come down to observing a sanitary-hygienic&#xD;
      regimen and taking antipyretics if necessary. Unfortunately, the treatment of patients with a&#xD;
      mild course is still outside the interest of medical science. In its updated strategy to curb&#xD;
      the spread of COVID-19, WHO states the need for diagnosis, effective isolation, and treatment&#xD;
      of patients with mild to moderate severity of the clinical course of patients.Currently,&#xD;
      there is experience with the use of the drug Imupret for the treatment of nasopharyngitis&#xD;
      associated with other viral pathogens, in particular Epstein-Barr virus. It was shown that&#xD;
      the use of a Phyto preparation helps to accelerate the regression of symptoms characteristic&#xD;
      of nasopharyngitis, as well as accelerate the elimination of the virus from the body.&#xD;
      Obviously, the proven activity of Imupret is important in relation to the activation of&#xD;
      factors of nonspecific immunity, which is important in confronting viruses, including&#xD;
      COVID-19. Another obvious factor that is important for the treatment of viral diseases is the&#xD;
      synergism of the active substances in oak bark and walnut leaves with respect to inhibition&#xD;
      of reverse transcriptase of a wide range of respiratory viruses, as well as the&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory effect of the drug. Confirmation of the therapeutic effect of Imupret for&#xD;
      the treatment of nasopharyngitis associated with COVID-19 would allow the development of new&#xD;
      therapeutic tools to combat this infection and put into practice updated WHO emphasis on&#xD;
      national health systems: it is important to identify, treat and isolate all cases of&#xD;
      COVID-19, including cases with mild or moderate severity of the disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      The new coronavirus (2019-nCoV) from Wuhan is currently of great concern, as the virus is&#xD;
      spreading rapidly around the world and the number of cases and deaths is constantly growing.&#xD;
      The main cause of death is the severe course of COVID-19 disease, which includes pneumonia,&#xD;
      acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS), sepsis, and septic shock. As the spread of&#xD;
      COVID-19 is progressing worldwide, the focus is on the rapid identification, testing, and&#xD;
      treatment of patients with severe COVID-19 and the hospitalization of people with the highest&#xD;
      risk of fatal outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Less attention is paid to cases of mild disease. According to WHO data, about 40% of patients&#xD;
      with COVID-19 have a mild course of the disease, namely, cases of mild course are of great&#xD;
      danger from the point of view of the spread of infection, since the main source of infection&#xD;
      is a sick person. An infected person, even with minor clinical symptoms, can infect between&#xD;
      1.5 and 3.5 people and spread the virus among approximately 368 people in just five infection&#xD;
      cycles. The mild course of COVID-19 is characterized by a number of nonspecific symptoms:&#xD;
      fever, cough, sore throat, nasal congestion, malaise, headache, muscle pain. Evidence has&#xD;
      emerged of loss of smell as a symptom of COVID-19 infection. South Korea, China, and Italy&#xD;
      have already proven that a significant number of patients with proven COVID-19 infection&#xD;
      developed anosmia/hyposmia. In Germany, more than 2 out of 3 confirmed cases are reported to&#xD;
      have anosmia. Anosmia/hyposmia in the absence of other respiratory diseases, such as allergic&#xD;
      rhinitis, acute rhinosinusitis, or chronic rhinosinusitis, are considered as a clinical&#xD;
      marker of COVID-19 infection in a pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      For people with a mild course of the disease, WHO recommends providing home care, and the&#xD;
      recommendations come down to observing a sanitary-hygienic regimen and taking antipyretics if&#xD;
      necessary. Unfortunately, the treatment of patients with a mild course is still outside the&#xD;
      interest of medical science. However, in its updated strategy to curb the spread of COVID-19,&#xD;
      WHO states the need for diagnosis, effective isolation, and treatment of patients with mild&#xD;
      to moderate severity of the clinical course of patients.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Fever, cough, sore throat, nasal congestion, malaise, headache, muscle pain, and decreased&#xD;
      sense of smell are typical symptoms of acute nasopharyngitis. It is believed that the&#xD;
      previously described coronaviruses account for 10-15% of cases of nasopharyngitis, so it is&#xD;
      not surprising that the new COVID-19 virus can also cause anosmia in infected patients. These&#xD;
      patients need isolation and treatment because they are covert carriers that contribute to the&#xD;
      rapid spread of COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Currently, there is experience with the use of the drug Imupret for the treatment of&#xD;
      nasopharyngitis associated with other viral pathogens, in particular Epstein-Barr virus. It&#xD;
      was shown that the use of a Phyto preparation helps to accelerate the regression of symptoms&#xD;
      characteristic of nasopharyngitis, as well as accelerate the elimination of the virus from&#xD;
      the body. Obviously, the proven activity of Imupret is important in relation to the&#xD;
      activation of factors of nonspecific immunity, which is important in confronting viruses,&#xD;
      including COVID-19. Another obvious factor that is important for the treatment of viral&#xD;
      diseases is the synergism of the active substances in oak bark and walnut leaves with respect&#xD;
      to inhibition of reverse transcriptase of a wide range of respiratory viruses, as well as the&#xD;
      anti-inflammatory effect of the drug. Confirmation of the therapeutic effect of Imupret for&#xD;
      the treatment of nasopharyngitis associated with COVID-19 would allow the development of new&#xD;
      therapeutic tools to combat this infection and put into practice updated WHO emphasis on&#xD;
      national health systems: it is important to identify, treat and isolate all cases of&#xD;
      COVID-19, including cases with mild or moderate severity of the disease.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">May 1, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 8, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">December 19, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>Phase 4</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>Randomized</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Parallel Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Day of response to treatment from baseline to end of treatment (up to two weeks) - decrease in the average score of the symptom assessed by the patient (VAS, 0-10 points for each symptom) by 50% compared to baseline.</measure>
    <time_frame>Visit 1 (Day 1), Visit 2 (Day 4), Visit 3 (Day 14)</time_frame>
    <description>patient's assessment of the symptoms 11 Point visual analogue scale 0 - absent symptom, 10 - the maximum severity of the symptom) for rhinorrhea, nasal congestion, rhinolalia, anosmia, sore throat, general condition, fever.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom Dynamics (assessed by patients)</measure>
    <time_frame>Every day in the treatment phase up to 14 days</time_frame>
    <description>Symptom measurement by patient's self assessment (General condition, sore throat, fever, rhinorrhea, cough, nasal congestion via ten-point visual analogue scale (VAS, 0 - 10 points (0- no symptom; 10 -maximal expression of the symptom).</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <other_outcome>
    <measure>Symptom Dynamics (assessed by docktor)</measure>
    <time_frame>At Visit 1 (Day 0) and at Visit 3 (day 14)</time_frame>
    <description>Symptom measurement by doctors (General condition, sore throat, fever, rhinorrhea, cough, nasal congestion via 5-point criteria: 0-4 points/symptom. 0 - none symptom; 1- mild; 2- moderate; 3- severe; 4- very severe).</description>
  </other_outcome>
  <number_of_arms>2</number_of_arms>
  <enrollment type="Actual">133</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <condition>Nasopharyngitis</condition>
  <condition>Anosmia</condition>
  <condition>Fever</condition>
  <condition>Myalgia</condition>
  <condition>Cough</condition>
  <condition>Nasal Congestion</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment group BNO 1030</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Active Comparator</arm_group_type>
    <description>BNO 1030</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
    <arm_group_type>Other</arm_group_type>
    <description>Standard care</description>
  </arm_group>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Drug</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>BNO 1030</intervention_name>
    <description>Imupret 25 drops х 6 times per day for 14 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Treatment group BNO 1030</arm_group_label>
    <other_name>Imupret</other_name>
  </intervention>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Other</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Standard care</intervention_name>
    <description>isolation mode symptomatic therapy as needed: antipyretic (paracetamol) saline solutions in the nose x 4 times a day -14 days</description>
    <arm_group_label>Control group</arm_group_label>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Age 18-70 years old;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Clinical signs of a mild form of COVID-19 (acute nasopharyngitis associated with&#xD;
             2019-nCoV), assessed by direct contact or remotely: sudden onset, fever, cough&#xD;
&#xD;
             + at least one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  nasal congestion;&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  discharge from the nose (front and back rhinorrhea);&#xD;
&#xD;
               -  anosmia/hyposmia;&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Contact with a confirmed or suspected case of COVID-19&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The possibility of treatment on an outpatient basis subject to the self-isolation mode&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Indications for inpatient treatment&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  The presence of immunodeficiency conditions, oncological diseases, chronic diseases of&#xD;
             the cardiovascular or broncho-pulmonary system, diabetes mellitus.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Individual intolerance to the components of the drug.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>70 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Vasyl Popovych, Professor</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Ivano-Frankivsk National Medical University</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Ivano-Frankivsk National Medical University</name>
      <address>
        <city>Ivano-Frankivsk</city>
        <zip>76000</zip>
        <country>Ukraine</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Ukraine</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 8, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 12, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 15, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 12, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 12, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 15, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Ivano-Frankivsk National Medical University</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Vasyl Popovych</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Head of department &quot;Otolaringology, children otolaryngology and surdology&quot;</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Myalgia</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Nasopharyngitis</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Olfaction Disorders</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

