<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="5361">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04761510</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04761510</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Mindfulness-SOS: Stress Reduction for Refugees</brief_title>
  <official_title>Mindfulness-SOS: Stress Reduction for Refugees</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>University of Haifa</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>University of Haifa</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The COVID-19 pandemic crisis is associated with a wide range of stressors for the general&#xD;
      population. For forcibly displaced persons (FDPs), the turmoil of this crisis is magnified&#xD;
      significantly, and elevated pre-existing post-migration stressors and trauma-related mental&#xD;
      health problems are acutely amplified. In a recent randomized control trial,&#xD;
      Mindfulness-Based Trauma Recovery for Refugees (MBTR-R) led to large acute stress-buffering&#xD;
      effects among Eritrean asylum seekers in Israel. The investigators thus developed&#xD;
      Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees - a brief internet-based mobile-supported adaptation of the&#xD;
      MBTR-R mental health intervention program - specifically designed to mitigate acute stress&#xD;
      and related mental health symptoms among FDPs. The investigators will conduct a nonrandomized&#xD;
      single-group intervention trial of the efficacy, safety, utilization, and related feasibility&#xD;
      of Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees among a traumatized chronically stressed sample of East&#xD;
      African asylum seekers in an urban post-displacement setting in the Middle East (Israel). The&#xD;
      study will be carried out during an acutely stressful period of time for this population due&#xD;
      to a COVID-19 pandemic national lockdown.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      Brief Background:&#xD;
&#xD;
      The COVID-19 pandemic is associated with a range of stressors and consequent mental health&#xD;
      problems. For tens of millions of FDPs, stressors and sequelae of the pandemic are&#xD;
      particularly magnified and severe, as their preexisting stress-related mental health problems&#xD;
      are acutely exacerbated. In a recent randomized control trial prior to the COVID-19 pandemic,&#xD;
      the investigators found significant therapeutic effects of MBTR-R - a 9-week, mindfulness-&#xD;
      and compassion-based, trauma-sensitive, and socio-culturally adapted group intervention&#xD;
      program designed for FDPs - for stress- and trauma-related mental health outcomes among&#xD;
      Eritrean asylum seekers in Israel. In light of the COVID-19 pandemic, and to facilitate&#xD;
      access, reach, and flexibility of mental health care among FDPs, the investigators developed&#xD;
      Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees - a brief internet-based mobile-supported adaptation of the&#xD;
      MBTR-R mental health intervention program - specifically designed to mitigate acute stress&#xD;
      and related mental health symptoms among FDPs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Aims:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Broadly, the study aims are: I) to test the efficacy of the Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees&#xD;
      intervention program on stress- and trauma-related mental health outcomes (e.g. posttraumatic&#xD;
      stress, depression), II) to test intervention safety - including rates of clinically&#xD;
      significant deterioration in primary outcomes in response to the intervention, III) to assess&#xD;
      participant utilization of the Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees intervention program, IV) to test&#xD;
      whether Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees will lead to changes in targeted processes or mechanisms&#xD;
      of change including mindful awareness and self-compassion, and V) to test whether expected&#xD;
      pre-to-post intervention change in the targeted processes will predict expected pre-to-post&#xD;
      intervention change in stress- and trauma-related mental health outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Study Overview:&#xD;
&#xD;
      Accordingly, the investigators will conduct a nonrandomized single-group intervention trial&#xD;
      among a community sample of traumatized and chronically stressed East African asylum seekers&#xD;
      (N=60, 50% female), residing in Israel in an urban post-displacement setting, during the&#xD;
      COVID-19 pandemic. Over the course of three successive months, participants will be recruited&#xD;
      from the community via public flyers, social networks, local non-governmental- (NGOs), and&#xD;
      municipal- organizations working with FDPs. Participants will be assigned to Mindfulness-SOS&#xD;
      for Refugees - a brief internet-based mobile-supported intervention program, entailing 8&#xD;
      brief sessions as well as 9 mindfulness meditation practice exercises - delivered via audio&#xD;
      recordings using participants' personal smartphones. Over the course of the Mindfulness-SOS&#xD;
      for Refugees intervention program, participants will receive administrative guidance (e.g.&#xD;
      technical support in case of mobile phone and internet platform-related difficulties and&#xD;
      relevant information of the internet-based mobile-supported intervention program and&#xD;
      assessment); as well as adherence-focused guidance (e.g. adherence monitoring including&#xD;
      weekly brief check-in telephone calls and smartphone text-based nudges to remind and prompt&#xD;
      weekly adherence and assessment), in the participants' mother tongue, Tigrinya. Stress- and&#xD;
      trauma-related mental health outcomes and targeted change processes will be assessed via&#xD;
      self-report questionnaires pre-intervention, brief weekly assessments, and post-intervention.&#xD;
      In addition to participants' self-report, participant-level utilization of the&#xD;
      Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees intervention program will be digitally monitored. Participants&#xD;
      will be encouraged to complete 2 sessions per week and practice each day for 4 weeks but can&#xD;
      choose to extend this up to 8 weeks. Post-intervention assessments will be carried out when&#xD;
      participants will complete the 8 sessions of the internet-based mobile-supported intervention&#xD;
      program (recommended 4 weeks, a maximum of 8 weeks post-baseline, or when participants will&#xD;
      indicate that they are no longer interested in participating in the intervention program).&#xD;
      The intervention program and assessments will be completed on participants' smartphones.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Completed</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">September 14, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Actual">January 14, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">January 14, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <phase>N/A</phase>
  <study_type>Interventional</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <allocation>N/A</allocation>
    <intervention_model>Single Group Assignment</intervention_model>
    <primary_purpose>Treatment</primary_purpose>
    <masking>None (Open Label)</masking>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Harvard Trauma Questionnaire according to DSM-5 (HTQ-5)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from immediately pre-intervention to 1-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The Harvard Trauma Questionnaire according to DSM-5 (HTQ-5) is a 25-item self-report questionnaire to assess post-traumatic stress symptom severity (4-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of post-traumatic stress severity (minimum scale score 1 and maximum scale score 4), HTQ-5 mean cut-off score ≥ 2 is commonly used to identify categorical (diagnostic) symptom status of post-traumatic stress disorder</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ-9)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from immediately pre-intervention to 1-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The brief Patient Health Questionnaire (PHQ-9) is a 9-item self-report questionnaire to assess depression symptom severity (4-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of depression symptom severity (minimum scale score 0 and maximum scale score 27), PHQ-9 mean cut-off score ≥10 is commonly used to identify categorical (diagnostic) symptom status of depression</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Beck's Anxiety Inventory (BAI)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from immediately pre-intervention to 1-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>6 Items of the Beck's Anxiety Inventory (BAI) self-report questionnaire will be used to assess anxiety symptom severity (4-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of anxiety symptom severity</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Post-Migration Living Difficulties Checklist (PMLD)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from immediately pre-intervention to 1-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>The Post-Migration-Living-Difficulties Checklist (PMLD) is a 9-item self-report questionnaire to assess post-migration stress (5-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of post-migration stress (minimum scale score 1 and maximum scale score 5)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief Inventory of Thriving (BIT)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from immediately pre-intervention to 1-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>One item of the Brief Inventory of Thriving (BIT) self-report questionnaire will be used to assess subjective well-being (5-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of subjective well-being</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Dimensions of Anger Reactions-5 (DAR-5)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from immediately pre-intervention to 1-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>One item of the Dimensions of Anger Reactions-5 (DAR-5) self-report questionnaire will be used to assess anger duration (5-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of anger duration</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Parenting Scale (PS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from immediately pre-intervention to 1-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>One item of the Parenting Scale (PS) self-report questionnaire will be used to assess parental discipline strategies (5-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating less effective discipline strategies</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Modified 5-item Extended-Hurt/Insult/Threaten/Scream (Modified E-HITS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from immediately pre-intervention to 1-week post-intervention</time_frame>
    <description>One adapted item of the Modified 5-item Extended-Hurt/Insult/Threaten/Scream (Modified E-HITS) self-report questionnaire will be used to assess intimate partner violence (IPV) perpetration (5-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of perpetration of IPV</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Positive and Negative Affect Schedule (PANAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from immediately pre-intervention to 1-week post-intervention, measured weekly up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>The Positive and Negative Affect Schedule (PANAS) is a 20-item self-report questionnaire to assess positive and negative affect (5-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of activation of positively and negatively valanced affects</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief assessment of mindful awareness</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from immediately pre-intervention to 1-week post-intervention, measured weekly up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>4 self-report Items will be used to assess mindful awareness (5-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of mindful awareness</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief assessment of self-compassion</measure>
    <time_frame>Change from immediately pre-intervention to 1-week post-intervention, measured weekly up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>3 self-report Items will be used to assess self-compassion (5-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of self-compassion</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief weekly assessment of formal and informal mindfulness practice</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly change from week 1 of intervention to 1-week post-intervention, up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>2 self-report Items will be used to assess number of formal and informal mindfulness practice during the past week, with higher scores indicating greater number of mindfulness practices during the past week</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief weekly assessment of post-traumatic stress</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly change from week 1 of intervention to 1-week post-intervention, up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>4 self-report Items will be used to assess post-traumatic stress (5-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of post-traumatic stress</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief weekly assessment of depression</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly change from week 1 of intervention to 1-week post-intervention, up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>One self-report item will be used to assess depression (5-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of depression</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Brief weekly assessment of anxiety</measure>
    <time_frame>Weekly change from week 1 of intervention to 1-week post-intervention, up to 8 weeks</time_frame>
    <description>One self-report item will be used to assess anxiety (5-point Likert scale), with higher scores indicating greater levels of anxiety</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">60</enrollment>
  <condition>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</condition>
  <condition>Stress Related Disorder</condition>
  <intervention>
    <intervention_type>Behavioral</intervention_type>
    <intervention_name>Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees</intervention_name>
    <description>Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees is a brief internet-based mobile-supported intervention program which is a mobile-health adaptation of MBTR-R - a mindfulness- and compassion-based, trauma-sensitive, and socio-culturally adapted group intervention program designed for FDPs. Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees entails 8 brief sessions and 9 mindfulness meditation practice exercises - delivered via audio recordings using participants' smartphones. The intervention program is specifically designed to mitigate acute stress and related mental health symptoms among FDPs. During participation in the Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees intervention program, participants will be encouraged to complete 2 sessions per week and practice each day for 4 weeks but can choose to extend this up to 8 weeks. Delivery of Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees entails administrative guidance as well as adherence-focused guidance.</description>
  </intervention>
  <eligibility>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  East African refugee or asylum seeker living in Israel&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Tigrinya fluency and literacy&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Owns a personal smartphone&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Active suicidal ideation or/and past suicide attempt in the last year or/and passive&#xD;
             suicidal ideation with clinical indicators of imminent suicide risk (e.g. severe&#xD;
             paranoia)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Current mental health treatment (i.e. psychotherapy or/and group therapy at least&#xD;
             twice a month)&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Participation in the MBTR-R group in a previous study&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>65 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Assaf</name>
      <address>
        <city>Tel Aviv</city>
        <state>Merkaz</state>
        <zip>6617141</zip>
        <country>Israel</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Israel</country>
  </location_countries>
  <link>
    <url>https://www.mindfulness-sos-study.com/</url>
    <description>Mindfulness-SOS for Refugees intervention program study website</description>
  </link>
  <verification_date>February 2020</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>January 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 17, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 21, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>February 17, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>February 17, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">February 21, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Forcibly Displaced Persons</keyword>
  <keyword>Post-migration Stress</keyword>
  <keyword>Trauma</keyword>
  <keyword>Post-traumatic Stress Disorder</keyword>
  <keyword>Depression</keyword>
  <keyword>Anxiety</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19 Pandemic</keyword>
  <keyword>Stress</keyword>
  <keyword>Online Mental Health Intervention Program</keyword>
  <keyword>Treatment Adherence</keyword>
  <keyword>Mindfulness</keyword>
  <keyword>Compassion</keyword>
  <condition_browse>
    <!-- CAUTION:  The following MeSH terms are assigned with an imperfect algorithm            -->
    <mesh_term>Disease</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Traumatic</mesh_term>
    <mesh_term>Stress Disorders, Post-Traumatic</mesh_term>
  </condition_browse>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

