<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="4397">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04772404</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>DF0094UG</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04772404</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Repercussion of the COVID-19 Pandemic on Physical Activity, Psychological State and Sleep</brief_title>
  <official_title>Repercussion of the COVID-19 Pandemic on Physical Activity, Psychological State and Sleep</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Universidad de Granada</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Universidad de Granada</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The COVID-19 outbreak in our environment has caused significant changes in the population.&#xD;
      The main objective of this research project is to evaluate the level of physical activity,&#xD;
      psychological state and sleep during the COVID-19 pandemic in different populations.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <overall_status>Recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">March 7, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">June 15, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 15, 2021</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Knowledge of COVID</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Questionnaire to evaluate the knowledge about COVID-19. It includes 12 items. Patients have to answer true/false. Higher puntuation indicates better knowledge results.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Fear of COVID-19 Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Bangla fear of COVID (FCV19-S): It is a questionnaire that assesses the fear of COVID-19. It consists of 7 items scored on a 5-item Likert scale. The higher the score, the more fear.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID-19 Anxiety Scale (CAS)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Coronavirus anxiety scale (CAS): It is a scale that measures the anxiety generated by COVID-19 in the last two weeks. It presents 5 items and a score&gt; 9 indicates dysfunctional anxiety associated with the pandemic.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COVID Stress Scales</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>COVID stress scale (CSS): is a 36-item COVID Stress Scale (CSS) to measure these features, as they pertain to COVID-19. The CSS were developed to better understand and assess COVID-19-related distress. The scales were intentionally designed so they could be readily adapted for future pandemics.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Burn-Out de Maslach Inventory</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The Maslach Burnout Inventory (MBI) is a psychological assessment instrument comprising 22 symptom items pertaining to occupational burnout</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Steps per day</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Accelerometer</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>International physical activity questionnaire</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The International Physical Activity Questionnaire (IPAQ) was developed to measure health-related physical activity (PA) in populations. Higher scores indicates higher physical activity levels.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Barriers to being active quiz</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Barriers to being active quiz (BBAQ-21): It is a questionnaire that consists of 21 items. This questionnaire was aimed at ascertaining perception of barriers against engaging in PA.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Questionnaire of the transtheoretical model of change of physical exercise</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Questionnaire of the transtheoretical model of change of physical exercise (QTMCPE): It is made up of 22 items for people who are not physically active and 9 items for physically active people. It is a Likert-type scale that measures from 1 to 5.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Anxiety and depression will be assessed with the Hospital Anxiety and Depression Scale (HADS) . This scale is composed of 14 items divided into two subscales, 7 items of anxiety and 7 items of depression, involving higher values worse psycho-emotional state.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Connor-Davidson Resilience Scale (CD-RISC) was used to measure resilience. It consists of 10 items which form five factors. Respondents are asked to answer on a five-point Likert scale (0 = totally disagree to 4 = totally agree).</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>COPE-28</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The Brief-COPE is a 28 item self-report questionnaire designed to measure effective and ineffective ways to cope with a stressful life event. &quot;Coping&quot; is defined broadly as an effort used to minimize distress associated with negative life experiences.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The Pittsburgh Sleep Quality Index (PSQI) is a self-rated questionnaire which assesses sleep quality and disturbances in the previous month.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Morningness-eveningness questionnaire (MEQ)</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Morningness-Eveningness Questionnaire: Consisting of 19 items, the scale was developed to assess individual differences in morningness and eveningness - the degree to which respondents are active and alert at certain times of day. Scale items query preferences in sleep and waking times, and subjective &quot;peak&quot; times at which respondents feel their best.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Epworth sleepiness Scale</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The ESS asks the respondent to rate on a 4-point scale (0-3) their usual chances of having dozed off or fallen asleep while engaged in eight different activities that differ widely in their somnificity.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Insomnia severity index</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Insomnia severity index: It consists of 24 questions that measure sleep disturbances along dimensions: subjective sleep quality, sleep latency (LS), duration, efficiency, sleep disorders, use of sleep medication, and daytime dysfunction. The evaluation is based on the answers obtained from the previous month.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>EuroQoL-5D</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>The perception of the level of health and the quality of life were evaluated with the questionnaire European Quality of&#xD;
Life-5 Dimensions (EQ-5D). It is composed of 2 parts in which health status is assessed:&#xD;
Descriptive system: It consists on 5 dimensions that include mobility, self-care, usual activities, pain/discomfort, and anxiety/depression. Patients classify their health status in 3 severity levels: having no problems, having some or moderate problems, being unable to do/having extreme problems.&#xD;
Visual Analog Scale, by which respondents can report their perceived health status with a grade ranging from 0 (the worst possible health status) to 100 (the best possible health status)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Charlson Comorbidity Index</measure>
    <time_frame>Baseline</time_frame>
    <description>Charlson Comorbidity Index predicts the ten-year mortality for a patient who may have a range of comorbid conditions</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">100</enrollment>
  <condition>Healthy</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Healthy people&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        • Healthy people&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Cognitive impairment.&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Diagnose of autism spectrum disorder or severe intellectual disability&#xD;
&#xD;
          -  Physical or functional impairment that limits the performance of evaluation&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Department of Physical Therapy</name>
      <address>
        <city>Granada</city>
        <zip>18016</zip>
        <country>Spain</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
    <status>Recruiting</status>
    <contact>
      <last_name>Marie Carmen Valenza, PhD</last_name>
      <email>cvalenza@ugr.es</email>
    </contact>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>Spain</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>February 12, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>February 25, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">February 26, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 25, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 25, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 30, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Universidad de Granada</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Marie Carmen Valenza</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>Principal Investigator; PT; PhD</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <patient_data>
    <sharing_ipd>No</sharing_ipd>
  </patient_data>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

