<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="2593">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04830852</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>Pro00015510</org_study_id>
    <secondary_id>21X125F1</secondary_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04830852</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Pediatric SARS-CoV-2 and MIS-C Long-term Follow-up</brief_title>
  <official_title>Pediatric SARS-CoV-2 and MIS-C Long-term Follow-up</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Children's National Research Institute</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
    <collaborator>
      <agency>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</agency>
      <agency_class>NIH</agency_class>
    </collaborator>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Children's National Research Institute</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      This is a multisite prospective observational study to evaluate the clinical sequelae of&#xD;
      symptomatic and asymptomatic severe acute respiratory syndrome coronavirus 2 (SARS-CoV-2)&#xD;
      infection in the pediatric population, including coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) and&#xD;
      multisystem inflammatory syndrome in children (MIS-C), and characterize the immune response&#xD;
      associated with these clinical presentations. Patients aged 21 years and younger with&#xD;
      laboratory confirmed history of symptomatic or asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection will visit&#xD;
      the study sites for clinical and research evaluations and sample collection at schedules&#xD;
      dependent on time since infection. Patients enrolled within 12 weeks after acute infection or&#xD;
      positive test will be part of the &quot;recovery group&quot; and will attend study visits at baseline,&#xD;
      every 3 months for the first 6 months, and subsequently every 6 months for a total of 3&#xD;
      years. Patients enrolled more than 12 weeks after acute infection or positive test will be in&#xD;
      the &quot;convalescent group&quot; and will attend study visits at baseline and subsequently every 6&#xD;
      months for a total of 3 years.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Household contacts of the infected patients will serve as a control group and will attend&#xD;
      visits for evaluations and sample collection at baseline and every 12 months for a total of 3&#xD;
      years. This protocol will establish a cohort of pediatric patients recovered from SARS CoV-2&#xD;
      infection and a biorepository for evaluation of the potential roles of host genetics, immune&#xD;
      response, and other possible factors influencing long-term outcomes.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Parents or guardians of participants in all cohorts will also be enrolled for limited&#xD;
      participation to complete questionnaires about how the family is impacted by the&#xD;
      participant's health and SARS-CoV-2&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      This study will establish a cohort of surviving pediatric patients with symptomatic&#xD;
      (including COVID-19 and MIS-C) and asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection to study the long-term&#xD;
      sequelae of acute infection and the evolution of the immune response over time. Longitudinal&#xD;
      follow-up of this cohort will provide important information about clinical sequelae of acute&#xD;
      COVID-19 and MIS-C, characteristics of the immune response to SARS-CoV-2, and the extent and&#xD;
      duration of protective immunity.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Non-contrast low-radiation chest CT or AP chest radiograph: All participants will undergo 2&#xD;
      chest imaging procedures, one at baseline and one at the final study visit (year 3). Thus,&#xD;
      each chest CT would involve an effective dose of 1 mSv to 2 mSv for all age groups, while&#xD;
      each chest X-ray would involve approximately 0.01 mSv to 0.06 mSv for all age groups. An&#xD;
      average person's annual natural background radiation effective dose is 3 mSv.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants of childbearing potential will have a pregnancy test prior to this procedure,&#xD;
      and participants who are pregnant will be excluded from this procedure and will be withdrawn.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Non-contrast cardiac MRI: All participants will undergo 4 non-contrast cardiac MRI procedures&#xD;
      during this study. The first cardiac MRI will be performed at baseline (for survivor&#xD;
      participants, at least 6 weeks post onset of symptoms), and then cardiac MRI will be&#xD;
      performed annually. No cardiac MRI will be performed in any participant requiring conscious&#xD;
      sedation. For most participants, the primary risk associated with cardiac MRI is discomfort&#xD;
      as participants will be asked to lie still for a long period of time. Additionally,&#xD;
      participants may feel claustrophobic during the scan or find the sound of the MRI disturbing.&#xD;
      Participants with pacemakers, aneurysm clips, metallic prostheses, shrapnel fragments,&#xD;
      welders and metal workers are at risk for injury and will be excluded from having an MRI&#xD;
      performed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants of childbearing potential will have a pregnancy test prior to this procedure,&#xD;
      and participants who are pregnant will be excluded from this procedure and will be withdrawn.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Blood draw: The two hazards associated with blood drawing are those of the needle stick and&#xD;
      those associated with blood loss. Risks of blood draw are pain at the site of the needle&#xD;
      stick, the potential formation of hematoma at the site of the needle stick, and a small&#xD;
      potential for infection and/or inflammation at the site of the needle stick. Occasionally,&#xD;
      individuals may faint as a result of vasovagal reactions to the procedure. These risks will&#xD;
      be minimized by maintaining sterile technique, carefully preparing the site of needle&#xD;
      puncture with an alcohol swab, using the smallest size needle or cannula required for the&#xD;
      procedure, applying local pressure after removal of the needle or cannula, and having the&#xD;
      individual lie down or sit for 5 to 10 minutes after the procedure, if needed. The major risk&#xD;
      of repeated blood drawing is anemia. To minimize this risk, the amount of blood drawn for all&#xD;
      purposes will be adjusted so as not to exceed the guidelines: for pediatric patients, no more&#xD;
      than 5 mL/kg drawn for research purposes in a single day, and no more than 9.5 mL/kg drawn&#xD;
      over any 8 week period; for participants 18 years of age or older, no more than 10.5 mL/kg or&#xD;
      550 mL drawn for research purposes over any 8 week period.&#xD;
&#xD;
      A total of 26.5 to 30 mL of blood will be drawn at each visit for profile analysis as&#xD;
      outlined.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Echocardiogram: Echocardiogram is not an invasive procedure. Some patients report mild&#xD;
      discomfort during the test.&#xD;
&#xD;
      EKG: EKG is not an invasive procedure. Some patients experience minor irritation from the&#xD;
      electrodes. There are no other anticipated risks related to completing an EKG.&#xD;
&#xD;
      PFT: PFT is not an invasive procedure. Some patients with underlying lung disease may&#xD;
      experience wheezing, coughing, shortness of breath, chest tightness, dizziness, headache, and&#xD;
      rarely fainting or asthma attack during the testing. If this happens, we will stop the test&#xD;
      until symptoms resolve.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Completing questionnaires: Participants and/or legal guardians will be asked to complete&#xD;
      multiple questionnaires at every visit. To complete the questionnaires will take&#xD;
      approximately 25 to 64 minutes. Some of the questions in the questionnaire may be upsetting&#xD;
      or uncomfortable.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Participants will be informed that they may skip or decline to answer questions that make&#xD;
      them feel uncomfortable. If responses on self- or parent-proxy measures indicate significant&#xD;
      distress or a clinical elevation (&gt; 2 standard deviations) for depressive symptoms, a study&#xD;
      team member will follow up with the participant and a list of resources will be provided.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Collection of saliva, NP swab, urine, and stool: There are no risks associated with these&#xD;
      procedures. Collection of NP swabs may cause discomfort, gagging, and rarely nosebleed.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Genetic testing (optional): This protocol involves genetic testing using whole genome&#xD;
      sequencing (WGS) approaches for all participants. Genetic findings may cause emotional stress&#xD;
      and may require further medical testing or treatment that is not covered by this study. There&#xD;
      may also be medical and psychosocial implications for participants and their families.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Following genetic testing, data will be shared in controlled-access public databases for&#xD;
      other qualified biomedical investigators to study. However, no personal, identifiable&#xD;
      information will be shared in this process, since the results will be identified only by a&#xD;
      code.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Clinical photography (optional): Taking pictures of the face and body may be embarrassing to&#xD;
      some people. These photographs may be published in medical journals, without identifying the&#xD;
      participant. We will attempt to preserve the anonymity of the participant as much as&#xD;
      possible, while providing the information needed to support the research being published.&#xD;
      Participants may decline photographs or place any restrictions on their use. Participants&#xD;
      will be given the opportunity to discuss this with the PI or AIs.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Storage of samples and data: The primary risk of storing and sharing samples and data is&#xD;
      breach of confidentiality. Study samples and data will be kept confidential. Following&#xD;
      research testing and publication of the study results, study data will be shared in&#xD;
      accordance with NIH policy in a controlled-access public database, but no personal,&#xD;
      identifiable information will be shared.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Incidental findings of standard procedures: Some standard clinical procedures and evaluations&#xD;
      performed as part of this protocol (e.g., echocardiogram, EKG) may result in the discovery of&#xD;
      a previously unknown medical condition. If this occurs, the study team will discuss the&#xD;
      findings with the participant.&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Not yet recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2021</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2027</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Anticipated">May 1, 2024</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence and prevalence of medical sequelae</measure>
    <time_frame>6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence and prevalence of medical sequelae among symptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection survivors, asymptomatic SARS CoV 2 infection survivors, and MIS-C survivors.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Risk factors for medical sequelae</measure>
    <time_frame>6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Risk factors for medical sequelae among symptomatic SARS CoV 2 infection survivors, asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection survivors, and MIS-C survivors.</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Quality of life and social impact</measure>
    <time_frame>6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Health-related quality of life and social impact in children and adolescents recovered from SARS-CoV-2 infection including parent/guardian and child assessments.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Incidence and prevalence of reinfection</measure>
    <time_frame>6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Incidence and prevalence of reinfection in previously infected and recovered SARS-CoV-2 and MIS-C survivors with and without vaccination.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Biorepository</measure>
    <time_frame>6 years</time_frame>
    <description>Establishment of a biorepository for additional biomarker analysis.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <number_of_groups>4</number_of_groups>
  <enrollment type="Anticipated">5000</enrollment>
  <condition>SARS-CoV-2</condition>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Recovery Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients aged 21 years and younger with laboratory confirmed history of symptomatic or asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection will visit the study sites for clinical and research evaluations and sample collection at schedules dependent on time since infection. Patients enrolled within 12 weeks after acute infection or positive test will be part of the &quot;recovery group&quot; and will attend study visits at baseline, every 3 months for the first 6 months, and subsequently every 6 months for a total of 3 years.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Convalescent Group</arm_group_label>
    <description>Patients aged 21 years and younger with laboratory confirmed history of symptomatic or asymptomatic SARS-CoV-2 infection will visit the study sites for clinical and research evaluations and sample collection at schedules dependent on time since infection. Patients enrolled more than 12 weeks after acute infection or positive test will be in the &quot;convalescent group&quot; and will attend study visits at baseline and subsequently every 6 months for a total of 3 years.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Household contacts of infected patients</arm_group_label>
    <description>Household contacts of the infected patients will serve as a control group and will attend visits for evaluations and sample collection at baseline and every 12 months for a total of 3 years. This protocol will establish a cohort of pediatric patients recovered from SARS CoV-2 infection and a biorepository for evaluation of the potential roles of host genetics, immune response, and other possible factors influencing long-term outcomes.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <arm_group>
    <arm_group_label>Parents/guardians of participants</arm_group_label>
    <description>Parents or guardians of participants in all cohorts will also be enrolled for limited participation to complete questionnaires about how the family is impacted by the participant's health and SARS-CoV-2.</description>
  </arm_group>
  <biospec_retention>Samples With DNA</biospec_retention>
  <biospec_descr>
    <textblock>
      Blood draw, collection of saliva, NP swab, urine, and stool as well as genetic testing&#xD;
      (optional).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </biospec_descr>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Patients aged 0 to 21 years with confirmed history of symptomatic SARS CoV-2 infection&#xD;
        (including COVID-19), MIS C, or asymptomatic SARS CoV-2 infection (n = up to 1000), as well&#xD;
        as their household contacts (aged ≤21 years; n = up to 1000). Additionally, a parent or&#xD;
        guardian of each participant will be enrolled to complete targeted questionnaires (n = up&#xD;
        to 2000).&#xD;
&#xD;
        Accrual ceiling is 5000 patients.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Survivors and household contacts:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In order to be eligible to participate in this study as a survivor or household contact, an&#xD;
        individual must meet all of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Stated willingness to comply with all study procedures and availability for the&#xD;
             duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Male or female aged 0 to 21 years (at the NIH CC, minimum age is 3 years).&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Willing to allow storage of samples and data for future research.&#xD;
&#xD;
          4. At the NIH CC: Has a physician or clinic outside NIH to manage underlying medical&#xD;
             conditions, or agrees to establish care with an outside physician or clinic for any&#xD;
             medical conditions requiring treatment that may be diagnosed as a result of protocol&#xD;
             participation.&#xD;
&#xD;
        In addition, an individual must meet all criteria for one of the following cohorts.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Symptomatic survivor cohort (including MIS-C):&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Documented prior COVID-19 or MIS-C as evidenced by one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. detection of SARS-CoV-2 RNA or antigen in NP swab, saliva, sputum, or other&#xD;
                  sample source with Emergency Use Authorization (EUA)/approval from the US Food&#xD;
                  and Drug Administration (FDA) and a history of clinical manifestation compatible&#xD;
                  with COVID-19*; or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. positive SARS-CoV-2 antibody test using an assay that has received EUA from the&#xD;
                  FDA (negative SARS-CoV-2 RNA or antigen or never tested), and a history of&#xD;
                  clinical manifestation compatible with COVID-19*; or&#xD;
&#xD;
               3. meeting CDC case definition for MIS-C (see Appendix 1).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Onset of COVID-19/MIS-C symptoms is at least 4 weeks before screening. *one or more of&#xD;
             the following: ageusia, anosmia, chills, confusion, cough, rash, &quot;COVID toes&quot;,&#xD;
             diarrhea, dyspnea, fatigue, fever, headache, myalgia, nausea/vomiting, pneumonia,&#xD;
             rhinorrhea.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Asymptomatic survivor cohort:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Documented prior SARS-CoV-2 infection as evidenced by one of the following:&#xD;
&#xD;
               1. detection of SARS-CoV-2 RNA or antigen in NP swab, saliva, sputum, or other&#xD;
                  sample source with EUA/approval from the FDA without history of clinical&#xD;
                  manifestation compatible with COVID-19; or&#xD;
&#xD;
               2. positive SARS-CoV-2 antibody test using an assay that has received EUA from the&#xD;
                  FDA without history of clinical manifestation compatible with COVID-19*.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Positive SARS-CoV-2 RNA or antigen test is at least 4 weeks before screening. *one or&#xD;
             more of the following: ageusia, anosmia, chills, confusion, cough, rash, &quot;COVID toes&quot;,&#xD;
             diarrhea, dyspnea, fatigue, fever, headache, myalgia, nausea/vomiting, pneumonia,&#xD;
             rhinorrhea.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Household contact (control) cohort:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Lived in the same household as a participant with SARS-CoV-2 infection during the time&#xD;
             of illness, or was within approximately 6 feet (2 meters) of the participant for a&#xD;
             prolonged period of time, or having direct contact with infectious secretions of a&#xD;
             COVID-19 case (e.g., being coughed on).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. No diagnosis of SARS-CoV-2 infection or current symptoms suggestive of COVID-19.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Parents and guardians:&#xD;
&#xD;
        In order to participate in this study as a parent or guardian, an individual must meet all&#xD;
        of the following criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Is a parent or guardian of a participant enrolled as a survivor or household contact.&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Stated willingness to comply with all study procedures and availability for the&#xD;
             duration of the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Willing to allow storage of data for future research.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        Survivors and household contacts:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from participation&#xD;
        in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
          1. Any symptoms suggestive of an ongoing infection within 15 days of screening, including&#xD;
             but not limited to fever &gt; 38.2 °C, new or worsening respiratory symptoms (e.g.,&#xD;
             cough, dyspnea), or new or worsening gastrointestinal symptoms (e.g., nausea,&#xD;
             vomiting, diarrhea or abdominal pain).&#xD;
&#xD;
          2. Any medical or mental health condition that, in the judgement of the principal&#xD;
             investigator, would make the volunteer unable to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
          3. Pregnancy.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Parents and guardians:&#xD;
&#xD;
        An individual who meets any of the following criteria will be excluded from participation&#xD;
        in this study:&#xD;
&#xD;
        1. Any medical or mental health condition that, in the judgement of the principal&#xD;
        investigator, would make the volunteer unable to participate in the study.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Co-enrollment: Participants may be co-enrolled in other clinical studies, including&#xD;
        observational studies and therapeutic trials. However, the study staff should be informed&#xD;
        of co-enrollment.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>N/A</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>21 Years</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>Accepts Healthy Volunteers</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Roberta DeBiasi, MD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Children's National Research Institute</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Gina Montealegre, MD, MS</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases (NIAID)</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <overall_contact>
    <last_name>Roberta DeBiasi, MD, MS</last_name>
    <phone>2024765052</phone>
    <email>RDebiasi@childrensnational.org</email>
  </overall_contact>
  <overall_contact_backup>
    <last_name>Gina Montealegre, MD, MS</last_name>
    <phone>3017617747</phone>
    <email>gina.montealegre@nih.gov</email>
  </overall_contact_backup>
  <verification_date>April 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>April 1, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>April 1, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>April 1, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>April 1, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">April 5, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Principal Investigator</responsible_party_type>
    <investigator_affiliation>Children's National Research Institute</investigator_affiliation>
    <investigator_full_name>Roberta DeBiasi</investigator_full_name>
    <investigator_title>MD, MS, Division Chief, Infectious Diseases, Co-Director of the Congenital Zika Program</investigator_title>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>SARS-CoV-2</keyword>
  <keyword>COVID-19</keyword>
  <keyword>MIS-C</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

