<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<clinical_study rank="3109">
  <!-- This xml conforms to an XML Schema at:
    https://clinicaltrials.gov/ct2/html/images/info/public.xsd -->
  <required_header>
    <download_date>ClinicalTrials.gov processed this data on April 14, 2021</download_date>
    <link_text>Link to the current ClinicalTrials.gov record.</link_text>
    <url>https://clinicaltrials.gov/show/NCT04794920</url>
  </required_header>
  <id_info>
    <org_study_id>EMOCOV</org_study_id>
    <nct_id>NCT04794920</nct_id>
  </id_info>
  <brief_title>Post-Covid-19 Emotional Aspects of Hospital Staff</brief_title>
  <acronym>EMOCOV</acronym>
  <official_title>Post-Covid-19 Emotional Aspects of Hospital Staff</official_title>
  <sponsors>
    <lead_sponsor>
      <agency>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</agency>
      <agency_class>Other</agency_class>
    </lead_sponsor>
  </sponsors>
  <source>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</source>
  <oversight_info>
    <has_dmc>No</has_dmc>
    <is_fda_regulated_drug>No</is_fda_regulated_drug>
    <is_fda_regulated_device>No</is_fda_regulated_device>
  </oversight_info>
  <brief_summary>
    <textblock>
      The ongoing SARS-CoV2 or Covid-19 pandemic is causing a major global health crisis. In&#xD;
      France, it prompted an urgent reorganization of the healthcare supply, mobilizing caregivers&#xD;
      and hospital staff in a climate of uncertainty. Health services have been put to the test,&#xD;
      some staff being on the front line, others having faced the reorganization of the health&#xD;
      system necessitated by such a pandemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Frontline caregivers have been compared to &quot;fighters on the front lines.&quot; They encountered&#xD;
      many difficulties, such as direct exposure to patients with a high viral load, exposure to&#xD;
      the risk of contamination, physical exhaustion, reorganization of workspaces, adaptation to&#xD;
      rigid work organizations, the management of the shortage of materials, the unusually high&#xD;
      number of deaths among patients, colleagues or relatives, ethical questions relating to&#xD;
      decision-making in a strained healthcare system.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The psychological impact on these hospital staff is an indirect issue of such a pandemic in&#xD;
      terms of mental health.&#xD;
&#xD;
      The investigators have little data in the literature on the incidence of psychiatric episodes&#xD;
      in the post-epidemic period. Work on the impact of two major pandemics of influenza A H1N1&#xD;
      (2009) and SARS-CoV-1 (2003) on the mental health of caregivers and other staff working in&#xD;
      hospitals reports increased rates of mental disorders after discharge from anxiety-type&#xD;
      crisis, depression and post-traumatic stress. This over-representation of mental disorders&#xD;
      was still found several years after the epidemic.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Similar results are emerging in recent studies involving hospital staff who were used in the&#xD;
      Covid-19 crisis. These highlight a certain number of risk factors for the occurrence of these&#xD;
      disorders (young age, nursing profession, underlying psychiatric pathology, exercise carried&#xD;
      out in the first line of Covid).&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </brief_summary>
  <detailed_description>
    <textblock>
      At the Paris Saint-Joseph Hospital Group (GHPSJ), a multidisciplinary working group was early&#xD;
      involved in psychological support for staff.&#xD;
&#xD;
      This group proposed the establishment of on-call duty entrusted to a psychological support&#xD;
      unit, made up of a doctor, a nurse and a psychologist who volunteered to carry out patrols in&#xD;
      the various departments of the hospital. These visits, sometimes organized at the request of&#xD;
      the management of the services and sometimes improvised, aimed to identify the difficulties&#xD;
      encountered in the field, and to discuss with the teams.&#xD;
&#xD;
      Concomitantly and complementary, the staff bubble opened at the Paris Saint-Joseph Hospital&#xD;
      on March 27, to offer a decompression space to all staff (caregivers or not) with proposals&#xD;
      for hypnosis, physiotherapy, sophrology sessions. , psychotherapy, but also informal&#xD;
      discussions or a break in a relaxing armchair.&#xD;
&#xD;
      As a continuation of this approach, the multidisciplinary working group plans to search in&#xD;
      July 2020 for symptoms present in certain mental illnesses (anxiety, depression,&#xD;
      post-traumatic stress syndrome) in all the staff of the Paris Saint-Joseph Hospital Group. ,&#xD;
      now that the crisis seems to be receding. This will make it possible to adapt the support&#xD;
      offer for staff in the coming months. This inventory will be made on the basis of validated&#xD;
      questionnaires: the Posttraumatic stress disorder CheckList-5 (PCL) questionnaire for&#xD;
      post-traumatic stress and the Hospital Anxiety and Depression scale (HAD) score for mental&#xD;
      disorders (anxiety, depression) . A 3rd questionnaire will collect additional data and&#xD;
      provide feedback on the frequentation of the bubble&#xD;
    </textblock>
  </detailed_description>
  <overall_status>Active, not recruiting</overall_status>
  <start_date type="Actual">July 10, 2020</start_date>
  <completion_date type="Anticipated">May 31, 2021</completion_date>
  <primary_completion_date type="Actual">October 3, 2020</primary_completion_date>
  <study_type>Observational</study_type>
  <has_expanded_access>No</has_expanded_access>
  <study_design_info>
    <observational_model>Cohort</observational_model>
    <time_perspective>Prospective</time_perspective>
  </study_design_info>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of symptoms related to post-traumatic stress in all staff who worked at the GHPSJ during the crisis (from March 15 to May 15, 2020).</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of staff with a score&gt; 44 on the PCL questionnaire</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <primary_outcome>
    <measure>Frequency of symptoms related to post-traumatic stress in all staff who worked at the GHPSJ during the crisis (from March 15 to May 15, 2020).</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Rate of staff with a score ≥11 on items A and D for the HAD score</description>
  </primary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Look for demographic and professional characteristics that may favor the onset of these symptoms</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Univariate and multivariate analyzes to identify the risk factors for the occurrence of these symptoms (anxiety, depression and post-traumatic stress)</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the impact of frequentation of the staff bubble on the occurrence of anxiety / depressive disorders</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Difference between the average HAD scores between the group &quot;frequentation of the staff bubble&quot; and the group &quot;non-attendance of the staff bubble&quot;. The distinction between the 2 groups is made on the basis of their answer to the dedicated question asked in the questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the impact of frequentation of the staff bubble on the occurrence of post-traumatic stress</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Difference between the mean PCL scores between the 2 above-mentioned groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the impact of the psychological support unit on the occurrence of anxiety / depressive disorders</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Difference between the average HAD scores between the &quot;contact with the psychological support unit&quot; group and the &quot;no contact with the psychological support unit&quot; group. The distinction between the 2 groups is made on the basis of their response to the question asked in the questionnaire.</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the impact of the psychological support unit on the occurrence of post traumatic stress</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>Difference between the mean PCL scores between the 2 above-mentioned groups</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the benefit felt by staff from frequenting the staff bubble</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>In the group &quot;frequentation of the staff bubble&quot;: percentage of response &quot;Very beneficial&quot; or &quot;Quite beneficial&quot;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <secondary_outcome>
    <measure>Evaluate the benefit felt by the staff of the meeting with the psychological support unit</measure>
    <time_frame>Day 1</time_frame>
    <description>In the group &quot;meeting with the psychological support unit&quot;: percentage of response &quot;Very beneficial&quot; or &quot;Quite beneficial&quot;</description>
  </secondary_outcome>
  <enrollment type="Actual">780</enrollment>
  <condition>Covid19</condition>
  <eligibility>
    <study_pop>
      <textblock>
        Any staff (caregivers and non-carers) who worked during the Covid 19 crisis (from March 15&#xD;
        to May 15) at the GHPSJ, on site or by teleworking, all or part of the period&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </study_pop>
    <sampling_method>Non-Probability Sample</sampling_method>
    <criteria>
      <textblock>
        Inclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Any staff (caregivers and non-carers) who worked during the Covid 19 crisis (from March&#xD;
        15 to May 15) at the GHPSJ, on site or by teleworking, all or part of the period.&#xD;
&#xD;
        Exclusion Criteria:&#xD;
&#xD;
        - Opposition to participate in research.&#xD;
      </textblock>
    </criteria>
    <gender>All</gender>
    <minimum_age>18 Years</minimum_age>
    <maximum_age>N/A</maximum_age>
    <healthy_volunteers>No</healthy_volunteers>
  </eligibility>
  <overall_official>
    <last_name>Marguerite D'USSEL</last_name>
    <role>Principal Investigator</role>
    <affiliation>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint Joseph</affiliation>
  </overall_official>
  <location>
    <facility>
      <name>Groupe Hospitalier Paris Saint-Joseph</name>
      <address>
        <city>Paris</city>
        <state>Ile De France</state>
        <zip>75014</zip>
        <country>France</country>
      </address>
    </facility>
  </location>
  <location_countries>
    <country>France</country>
  </location_countries>
  <verification_date>March 2021</verification_date>
  <study_first_submitted>March 9, 2021</study_first_submitted>
  <study_first_submitted_qc>March 11, 2021</study_first_submitted_qc>
  <study_first_posted type="Actual">March 12, 2021</study_first_posted>
  <last_update_submitted>March 11, 2021</last_update_submitted>
  <last_update_submitted_qc>March 11, 2021</last_update_submitted_qc>
  <last_update_posted type="Actual">March 12, 2021</last_update_posted>
  <responsible_party>
    <responsible_party_type>Sponsor</responsible_party_type>
  </responsible_party>
  <keyword>Emotional aspects</keyword>
  <keyword>caregivers</keyword>
  <!-- Results have not yet been posted for this study                                          -->
</clinical_study>

